<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Custom Feed</title><link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/reur/</link><description>Custom scraped articles</description><item><title>Trump orders 'blockade' of sanctioned oil tankers leaving, entering Venezuela</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/trump-orders-blockade-sanctioned-oil-tankers-leaving-entering-venezuela-2025-12-16/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Dec 16 (Reuters) - U.S. President Donald Trump ordered on Tuesday a "blockade" of all sanctioned oil tankers entering and leaving Venezuela, in Washington's latest move to increase pressure on Nicolas Maduro's government, targeting its main source of income.

It is unclear how Trump will impose the move against the sanctioned vessels, and whether he will turn to the Coast Guard to interdict vessels like he did last week. The administration has moved thousands of troops and nearly a dozen warships - including an aircraft carrier - to the region.

"For the theft of our Assets, and many other reasons, including Terrorism, Drug Smuggling, and Human Trafficking, the Venezuelan Regime has been designated a FOREIGN TERRORIST ORGANIZATION," Trump wrote on Truth Social. "Therefore, today, I am ordering A TOTAL AND COMPLETE BLOCKADE OF ALL SANCTIONED OIL TANKERS going into, and out of, Venezuela."

In a statement, Venezuela's government said it rejected Trump's "grotesque threat."

Oil prices rose more than 1% in Asian trade on Wednesday. Brent crude futures LCOc1 were up 70 cents, or 1.2%, at $59.62 a barrel at 0245 GMT, while U.S. West Texas Intermediate crude CLc1 rose 73 cents, or 1.3%, to $56.00 a barrel.

U.S. crude futures climbed over 1% to $55.96 a barrel in Asian trading after Trump's announcement. Oil prices settled at $55.27 a barrel on Tuesday, the lowest close since February 2021.

Oil market participants said prices were rising in anticipation of a potential reduction in Venezuelan exports, although they were still waiting to see how Trump’s blockade would be enforced and whether it would extend to include non-sanctioned vessels.

LEGAL QUESTIONS.

American presidents have broad discretion to deploy U.S. forces abroad, but Trump’s asserted blockade marks a new test of presidential authority, said international law scholar Elena Chachko of UC Berkeley Law School.

Blockades have traditionally been treated as permissible “instruments of war,” but only under strict conditions, Chachko said. “There are serious questions on both the domestic law front and international law front,” she added.

U.S. Representative Joaquin Castro, a Texas Democrat, called the blockade "unquestionably an act of war."

"A war that the Congress never authorized and the American people do not want," Castro added on X.

There has been an effective embargo in place after the U.S. seized a sanctioned oil tanker off the coast of Venezuela last week, with loaded vessels carrying millions of barrels of oil staying in Venezuelan waters rather than risk seizure.

Since the seizure, Venezuelan crude exports have fallen sharply, a situation worsened by a cyberattack that knocked down state-run PDVSA's administrative systems this week.

While many vessels picking up oil in Venezuela are under sanctions, others transporting the country's oil and crude from Iran and Russia have not been sanctioned, and some companies, particularly the U.S.' Chevron (CVX.N) , opens new tab , transport Venezuelan oil in their own authorized ships.

China is the biggest buyer of Venezuelan crude, which accounts for roughly 4% of its imports, with shipments in December on track to average more than 600,000 barrels per day, analysts have said.

For now, the oil market is well supplied and there are millions of barrels of oil on tankers off the coast of China waiting to offload. If the embargo stays in place for some time, then the loss of nearly a million barrels a day of crude supply is likely to push oil prices higher.

Two U.S. officials said the new policy, if implemented fully, could have a major impact on Maduro.

David Goldwyn, a former State Department energy diplomat, said if Venezuela's affected exports are not replaced by increased OPEC spare capacity, the impact on oil prices could be in the range of five to eight dollars a barrel.

"I would expect inflation to skyrocket, and massive and immediate migration from Venezuela to neighboring countries," Goldwyn said.

Since the U.S. imposed energy sanctions on Venezuela in 2019, traders and refiners buying Venezuelan oil have resorted to a "shadow fleet" of tankers that disguise their location and to vessels sanctioned for transporting Iranian or Russian oil.

As of last week, more than 30 of the 80 ships in Venezuelan waters or approaching the country were under U.S. sanctions, according to data compiled by TankerTrackers.com.

Trump's pressure campaign on Maduro has included a ramped-up military presence in the region and more than two dozen military strikes on vessels in the Pacific Ocean and Caribbean Sea near Venezuela, which have killed at least 90 people.

Trump has also said that U.S. land strikes on the South American country will soon start .

Maduro has alleged that the U.S. military build-up is aimed at overthrowing him and gaining control of the OPEC nation's oil resources, which are the world's largest crude reserves.

In wide-ranging interviews with Vanity Fair , Susie Wiles, Trump's chief of staff, said Trump "wants to keep on blowing boats up until Maduro cries uncle."

The Pentagon and Coast Guard referred questions to the White House.

The Trump administration has formally designated Venezuela's Cartel de los Soles as a foreign terrorist organization, saying the group includes Maduro and other high-ranking officials.

Maduro, speaking Tuesday before Trump's post, said, "Imperialism and the fascist right want to colonize Venezuela to take over its wealth of oil, gas, gold, among other minerals. We have sworn absolutely to defend our homeland and in Venezuela peace will triumph."</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:02 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/FV3SPPJRPRKW7GUKSBMEA5BOBA.jpg?auth=80e6d03ead020f29db9dda743788a81104d9c9339f6079b0d1fafa25d1a44f0f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Australia promises crackdown on hate as Bondi Beach shooting victim Matilda is farewelled</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/funeral-youngest-bondi-beach-shooting-victim-matilda-be-held-thursday-2025-12-17/</link><description>SYDNEY, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese on Thursday promised a crackdown on hate speech in the wake of an attack on a Jewish holiday event at Sydney's Bondi Beach, as the youngest of 15 victims was laid to rest.

Yellow toy bees topped the coffin of 10-year-old Matilda, who was remembered as a 'ray of sunshine' who loved animals and dancing.

Matilda's middle name was Bee, which inspired attendees to wear bee stickers, and bring bee-themed toys and balloons, while some mourners wore yellow. Matilda's family has asked the media not to use their surname.

"The tragic, so totally cruel, unfathomable murder of young Matilda is something to all of us as if our own daughter was taken from us," said Rabbi Yehoram Ulman.

"Matilda grew up like a child would, loving what children love. She loved the outdoors, animals. She went to school, she had friends, everybody loved her."

The alleged father-and-son gunmen opened fire as hundreds of people celebrated Hanukkah on Sydney's famous Bondi Beach on Sunday. The attack, which shocked the nation and led to fears over rising antisemitism, appears to have been inspired by the Islamic State, authorities say.

The line outside the hall where Matilda's funeral was held in Sydney's eastern suburbs snaked down the street. Many mourners who could not get in watched the service on a screen outside the building.

Some were angry at the government, saying it had not done enough to combat a rise in antisemitism since the start of the war in Gaza.

"It’s like your heart's been ripped out. It's terrible … no one wants this," said Jae Glover, 25, as he handed out bee stickers.

"It's a feeling, it could have been avoided. Antisemitism has now been brewing in Australia for over two years."

As Matilda's small white coffin was carried to a hearse at the end of the funeral, people crowded around to say their final goodbyes.

"As the coffin was driving away, I was just whispering, 'I'm so sorry, my baby. I'm so sorry, my baby', because I have five babies. We failed this baby," said Chana Friedman, 37.

Elena Marguleva said the service was "heartbreaking and devastating", and that she had not been eating or sleeping since the attack. "I can't come to terms with how this could possibly happen."

Albanese said the government will seek to introduce legislation that makes it easier to charge people promoting hate speech and violence. Penalties would be increased, cancelling or refusing visas would be made easier and a regime for targeting organisations whose leaders engage in hate speech would be developed, he said.

"Australians are shocked and angry. I am angry. It is clear we need to do more to combat this evil scourge much more," Albanese told a news conference announcing the reforms.

Albanese's government has said it has consistently denounced antisemitism over the last two years. It passed legislation to criminalise hate speech and in August it expelled the Iranian ambassador after accusing Tehran of directing two antisemitic arson attacks in the cities of Sydney and Melbourne.

Still, antisemitic incidents are mounting. A 19-year-old Sydney man was charged and will face court on Thursday after allegedly threatening violence towards a Jewish person on a flight from Bali to Sydney on Wednesday.

"Police will allege the man made antisemitic threats and hand gestures indicating violence towards the alleged victim, who the man knew to be affiliated with the Jewish community," Australian Federal Police said on Thursday.

Police allege the attack was carried out by Sajid Akram, 50, and his 24-year-old son Naveed. Sajid was shot dead by police at the scene, while Naveed Akram was charged with 59 offences including murder and terror charges on Wednesday after waking from a coma. His case has been adjourned until April 2026, the court confirmed on Thursday.

The centre-left Labor government has ruled out holding a Royal Commission, a high-level inquiry with judicial powers, into the shootings for now.

On Wednesday, the leader of New South Wales where the attack took place said he would next week recall the state parliament to pass urgent reforms on gun laws.

Police are looking into Australia-based Islamic State networks as well as the gunmen's alleged links to militants in the Philippines.

The Philippines' National Security Council on Wednesday said that while Sajid Akram and his son had been in the country for a month in November the pair had not engaged in any military training.

Islamic State-linked networks are known to operate in the Philippines and have wielded some influence in the south of the country.

"There is no valid report or confirmation that the two received any form of military training while in the country and no evidence supports such a claim at present," Philippine national security adviser Eduardo Ano said in a statement.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:05 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/JS4HXQZSYNITDMTY5MB7BF2UMM.jpg?auth=efb896e10465ee2f2b6069b47a8b34a0e1ef2aa9db35ba65936f57f448940efc&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>UN, aid groups warn Gaza operations at risk from Israel impediments</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/un-aid-groups-warn-gaza-operations-risk-israel-impediments-2025-12-17/</link><description>UNITED NATIONS, Dec 17 (Reuters) - The United Nations and aid groups warned on Wednesday that humanitarian operations in the Palestinian territories, particularly Gaza, were at risk of collapse if Israel does not lift impediments that include a "vague, arbitrary, and highly politicized" registration process.

Dozens of international aid groups face de-registration by December 31, which then means they have to close operations within 60 days, said the U.N. and more than 200 local and international aid groups in a joint statement.

"The deregistration of INGOs (international aid groups) in Gaza will have a catastrophic impact on access to essential and basic services," the statement read.

"INGOs run or support the majority of field hospitals, primary healthcare centers, emergency shelter responses, water and sanitation services, nutrition stabilization centers for children with acute malnutrition, and critical mine action activities," it said.

SUPPLIES LEFT OUT OF REACH: GROUPS

While some international aid groups have been registered under the system that was introduced in March, "the ongoing re-registration process and other arbitrary hindrances to humanitarian operations have left millions of dollars’ worth of essential supplies - including food, medical items, hygiene materials, and shelter assistance - stuck outside of Gaza and unable to reach people in need," the statement read.

Israel's mission to the United Nations in New York did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the statement.

Under the first phase of U.S. President Donald Trump's Gaza plan, a fragile ceasefire in the two-year-old war between Israel and Palestinian militants Hamas began on October 10. Hamas released hostages, Israel freed detained Palestinians and more aid began flowing into the enclave where a global hunger monitor said in August famine had taken hold.

However, Hamas says fewer aid trucks are entering Gaza than was agreed. Aid agencies say there is far less aid than required, and that Israel is blocking many necessary items from coming in. Israel denies that and says it is abiding by its obligations under the truce.

"The U.N. will not be able to compensate for the collapse of INGOs’ operations if they are de-registered, and the humanitarian response cannot be replaced by alternative actors operating outside established humanitarian principles," the statement by the U.N. and aid groups said.

The statement stressed "humanitarian access is not optional, conditional or political," adding: "Lifesaving assistance must be allowed to reach Palestinians without further delay."</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:12 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RIQAEU7Z5VOIBPALCGILLKWTMA.jpg?auth=5e082646c161630826fc62d2f81384d1425a14f51bee12643841ca750b1a159d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Son of filmmaker Rob Reiner appears in court on charges he murdered parents</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/son-filmmaker-rob-reiner-makes-court-appearance-charges-he-murdered-parents-2025-12-17/</link><description>LOS ANGELES, Dec 17 (Reuters) - The younger son of Hollywood filmmaker and political luminary Rob Reiner made his first court appearance on Wednesday, charged with double murder in the stabbing deaths of his parents, but the arraignment was postponed for three weeks, and he did not enter a plea.

Nick Reiner , 32, was ordered to return to Los Angeles County Superior Court for a continuation of his arraignment on January 7. No explanation was given in court for the delay in the hearing, which was requested by the defense.

Bearded, wearing eyeglasses and garbed in a blue protective vest, he appeared in court three days after his arrest and a day after he was charged with one of the most shocking celebrity homicide cases in the city's history.

He is accused of fatally stabbing his parents, actor-director Rob Reiner, 78, and photographer-producer Michele Reiner, 70, in the early morning hours of Sunday in the couple's mansion in the affluent west LA neighborhood of Brentwood, then fleeing the scene.

The couple's bodies were discovered Sunday afternoon, hours before a planned evening gathering with former President Barack Obama and Michelle Obama, according to the former first lady.

Nick Reiner, who has publicly acknowledged a years-long struggle with drug addiction, was arrested that night near a downtown Los Angeles park close to the University of Southern California campus.

Seated slightly slouched behind a glass partition in the courtroom, the defendant spoke little during his few minutes in court, saying only, "Yes, your honor," in a calm, clear voice when asked by Judge Theresa McGonigle if he agreed to waive his right to a speedy arraignment.

Speaking briefly to reporters outside the courthouse afterward, defense attorney Alan Jackson offered no additional insight, saying the proceedings were merely being paused.

"Today we're going to rest on where we stand procedurally, which is, this was a continuance of arraignment. Nothing happened today, substantively," he said.

"This is a devastating tragedy that has befallen the Reiner family," Jackson added. "There are very, very complex and serious issues that are associated with this case. Those need to be thoroughly, but very carefully dealt with and examined."

Family members were not present for the hearing. But Nick Reiner's two siblings, brother Jake Reiner, 34, and sister Romy Reiner, 27, issued a joint statement afterward, their first public comment since the killings.

"Words cannot even begin to describe the unimaginable pain we are experiencing every moment of the day," the two wrote. "The horrific and devastating loss of our parents, Rob and Michele Reiner, is something that no one should ever experience. They weren't just our parents; they were our best friends."

According to a New York Times account, it was Romy Reiner who found her father's body, after a massage therapist arriving at the house for an appointment failed to get an answer at the front gate and called the daughter for assistance. The daughter was unaware that her mother was also dead until after paramedics arrived, the Times reported, citing someone close to the family.

Authorities said Nick Reiner was taken into custody without incident on Sunday night, and was booked on suspicion of murder into a downtown jail, where he remains held with bond. According to various news media reports, he had lived in a guest house on his parents' property.

If convicted as charged on two counts of first-degree murder, he would face life in prison without the possibility of parole, or the death penalty.

District Attorney Nathan Hochman has said prosecutors have yet to decide whether to seek the death sentence.

Capital punishment remains on the books in California, but nobody has been put to death in the state since 2006, and Governor Gavin Newsom imposed an indefinite moratorium on executions in 2019.

According to prosecutors, a knife was used in the Reiner killings, but few other details were given about the circumstances of the slayings. Authorities have made no mention of a possible motive or whether drug use was a factor.

Various news media outlets have reported that Nick Reiner quarreled with his parents on Saturday night at a holiday party hosted by comedian Conan O'Brien.

Asked whether investigators had recovered the murder weapon, Hochman said on Tuesday that would be revealed in court. Autopsies, once completed, will determine the precise cause, manner and times of death, officials said.

Nick Reiner has spoken of being in and out of drug rehab facilities since he was 15 and periods of homelessness that occurred when he refused to seek treatment for his addictions. Those experiences inspired the movie "Being Charlie," co-written by Reiner and his father.

As an actor, Rob Reiner was best remembered for his role on the TV comedy "All in the Family" as Mike "Meathead" Stivic, the son-in-law and liberal foil of the lead character, working-class bigot Archie Bunker, played by Carroll O'Connor.

Reiner went on to a prolific Hollywood career as a filmmaker, directing such popular movies as "This Is Spinal Tap," "The Princess Bride," "When Harry Met Sally...," "Stand by Me," "A Few Good Men," "Misery" and "The American President."

His final film, a sequel to the mockumentary "This Is Spinal Tap" was released this year, 41 years after the original.

His wife, Michele, was at one time a photographer who captured the image of Donald Trump that appears on the cover of his book "Trump: The Art of the Deal." She and Rob Reiner met while he was directing "When Harry Met Sally" and wed in 1989.

Rob Reiner, a native of New York City and son of the late comedy writer and actor Carl Reiner, also was well known for his political activism and as a supporter of the Democratic Party.

He was first married to Penny Marshall, who starred in the TV sitcom "Laverne &amp; Shirley," and was also a producer and director. He was the adoptive father to Marshall's daughter.

(This story has been refiled to correct the caption in the images)</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:19 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RHPRCITX65NN3KE672Y5GQLAWI.jpg?auth=de08bd10a9452ed9c950ed2f67325d6148c642f7c7249605b5657bcd462b64e3&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>In holiday speech, Trump highlights victories amid sinking approval ratings</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/prime-time-speech-trump-highlight-victories-amid-low-economic-approval-2025-12-17/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Dec 17 (Reuters) - In a rare evening address from the White House, U.S. President Donald Trump boasted on Wednesday of his accomplishments and blamed his Democratic predecessor for soaring consumer prices as his party braces for a tough midterm election next year.

"Eleven months ago, I inherited a mess, and I'm fixing it," Trump said in a speech that lasted less than 20 minutes and was delivered at a jarringly rapid-fire pace .

The Republican president, who regularly protests that he does not get credit for his accomplishments, offered few new policy initiatives to address high costs. The speech instead was delivered with a pronounced sense of grievance, with Trump complaining about migrant invasions, violent crime and transgender rights in the White House's Diplomatic Reception Room festooned with holiday decor.

He placed blame at the feet of former President Joe Biden, previous trade deals, immigrants and what he described as a corrupt system.

At the same time, Trump touted his administration's work this year on a range of issues from reducing border crossings to bringing down prices of some goods. And he promised the nation would be stronger next year.

Among the few policy initiatives, Trump announced his administration would send a "warrior dividend" of $1,776 to 1.45 million U.S. service members in the coming week. He also backed a Republican proposal to send cash directly to the public to offset the cost of health insurance rather than provide subsidies through the Affordable Care Act. That proposal has yet to receive enough support in Congress.

"I want the money to go directly to the people so you can buy your own healthcare," Trump said. "The only losers will be the insurance companies."

Suprisingly, he spent little time addressing foreign affairs, a subject that occupied much of his first year back in office. He made a passing reference to the war in Gaza but made no mention of the war in Ukraine or the brewing conflict with Venezuela.

The address offered an opportunity for the president to address people's concerns about affordability, an issue that Trump has repeatedly referred to as a Democratic hoax .

While casting blame on Biden's presidency, Trump conceded that prices remain high, but argued the nation was "poised" for an economic boom.

"I am bringing those high prices down and bringing them down very fast," he said.

He pledged conditions would improve in the coming year, citing his tax policies, tariffs and plans to replace the chairman of the Federal Reserve, Jerome Powell.

That timetable would come as welcome news to Trump's fellow Republicans, who are seeking to maintain control of the House of Representatives and Senate in November elections next year. Nearly a year before elections, Democrats are already highlighting affordability concerns and differences over healthcare policy.

Trump campaigned on the economy, effectively leveraging the high inflation of Biden's presidency to beat former Vice President Kamala Harris in last year's election.

As president, Trump's tariff policies this year have created uncertainty and lifted prices in an economy that has now been overseen by his administration for nearly a year - and Trump, like Biden before him, has been struggling to persuade Americans that the economy is healthy.

A new Reuters/Ipsos poll on Tuesday showed just 33% of U.S. adults approve of how Trump has handled the economy.

After the speech, Democrats contended Trump had offered Americans few solutions to their concerns.

Senator Mark Warner of Virginia called the address "a sad attempt at distraction," while California Governor Gavin Newsom, a potential 2028 presidential contender, simply posted the word "Me" - referring to Trump - more than 700 times.

In his remarks, Trump said he had attracted $18 trillion in investments that will create jobs and open factories. He credited his tariff policy as a leading factor: "One year ago our country was dead... Now we're the hottest country anywhere in the world."

The speech came just a day before a closely-watched update on inflation from the Bureau of Labor Statistics. After touching a four-year low of 2.3% in April just three months into Trump's second term, annual inflation since then has been grinding higher.

Broadly, recent government data has shown that the economy’s growth has rebounded somewhat after it contracted during the first few months of the year. Yet it also shows that job growth has slowed during Trump’s second term, unemployment has risen to its highest level in four years and consumer prices remain high.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:26 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4NCV74S6PRMIRL7P2GULKCOFU4.jpg?auth=fd1378af47a2ddfaa90e95354a48a608a137896539454e624d93a5cd12ca4925&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Brown University gunman 'could be anywhere' on fifth day of manhunt</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/brown-university-gunman-still-large-manhunt-enters-fifth-day-2025-12-17/</link><description>Dec 17 (Reuters) - The gunman who killed two Brown University students remained at large on Wednesday, and there was no indication that authorities have grown closer to identifying the suspect four days after he opened fire inside a classroom and escaped into the surrounding streets in Providence, Rhode Island.

It is rare but not unprecedented for the perpetrator of a high-profile attack to evade capture for multiple days. But the lack of any identification has left people in the area on edge, with some staying behind locked doors and keeping their kids home from school.

"This is outside of the norm," said Felipe Rodriguez, a former New York Police detective who now teaches at the City University of New York's John Jay College of Criminal Justice. "Mass shooters, by large, are usually killed at the scene or quickly captured."

Investigators have released security camera images of a masked man they believe to be the suspect, based on witness accounts from survivors, but admit they still do not know who he is or what his motive may have been.

"He could be anywhere," Providence Police Chief Oscar Perez said of the killer at a press conference on Wednesday. "We still don't know who the person is or where he is."

Perez called the manhunt "probably the most intense investigation that we have in this nation."

Providence Mayor Brett Smiley told the same press conference he shared the feelings of the city's residents and Brown students who were "restless and eager" for an arrest.

At least eight other people were wounded in the attack. Six of them remained hospitalized.

On Wednesday, police published grainy photos of another unidentified man who they said was in the vicinity of the suspected shooter and have asked the public to help identify him. The images showed a man wearing a jacket over a hooded sweatshirt, his face visible, walking along a street.

"This is a person we would like to speak with," Perez said, describing him as someone "who may have information relevant to the investigation."

Early on Sunday, a day after the shooting, investigators appeared to have broken the case open when they announced a person was in custody. But authorities released the unnamed man in his 20s that evening after evidence showed he was not involved.

Officials said on Tuesday the investigation has been hampered by a lack of security cameras in the building and in the nearby area.

Investigators have released video clips, mostly taken from residential doorbell cameras, showing the possible shooter walking in a neighborhood near campus both before and immediately after the attack. In one video, the person can be seen walking away from the building right after the shooting as police cars with flashing lights arrive on the scene.

While the man in the video is masked, officials hope someone might recognize his body, gait, movements or posture.

Perez again called on people who live nearby to check their security cameras for any possible sightings of the suspect.

There are some other cases in which attackers have escaped, at least temporarily. The brothers who bombed the Boston Marathon in 2013 hid for four days in the Boston area and then killed a police officer when trying to flee. The older brother died after a gunfight with police that ended when his younger brother ran him over with a stolen car.

Luigi Mangione, the man accused of assassinating a healthcare executive last year in Manhattan, eluded authorities for five days. Mangione was captured in Altoona, Pennsylvania, after he was spotted eating at a McDonald's by a customer and an employee who believed he resembled the gunman.

More recently in September, conservative activist Charlie Kirk’s suspected shooter was taken into custody after a 33-hour manhunt . Suspect Tyler Robinson was captured after a relative and a family friend alerted the local sheriff's office that he had made comments suggesting he had committed the murder, the Utah governor said at the time.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:32 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/ECNXYIW3PJPSVFQFX2B7HZLT7I.jpg?auth=014224fd99c159d71e69adda49a465b4cd9a951b67729398adfa99dfdbbf99b3&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US approves $11.1 billion arms package for Taiwan, largest ever</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/taiwan-says-us-has-initiated-111-billion-arms-sale-procedure-2025-12-18/</link><description>TAIPEI/WASHINGTON, Dec 18 (Reuters) - The United States on Wednesday approved $11.1 billion in arms sales to Taiwan, the largest ever U.S. weapons package for the island which is under increasing military pressure from China.

The Taiwan arms sale announcement is the second under U.S. President Donald Trump's current administration, and comes as Beijing ramps up its military and diplomatic pressure against Taiwan, whose government rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims.

The proposed arms sale covers eight items, including HIMARS rocket systems, howitzers, Javelin anti-tank missiles, Altius loitering munition drones and parts for other equipment, Taiwan's defence ministry said in a statement.

"The United States continues to assist Taiwan in maintaining sufficient self‑defence capabilities and in rapidly building strong deterrent power and leveraging asymmetric warfare advantages, which form the foundation for maintaining regional peace and stability," it added.

The ministry said the package is at the Congressional notification stage, which is where Congress has a chance to block or alter the sale should it wish, though Taiwan has widespread cross-party support.

In a series of separate statements announcing details of the weapons deal, the Pentagon said the arms sales serve U.S. national, economic and security interests by supporting Taiwan's continuing efforts to modernise its armed forces and to maintain a "credible defensive capability".

Pushed by the United States, Taiwan has been working to transform its armed forces to be able to wage "asymmetric warfare", using mobile, smaller and often cheaper weapons which still pack a targeted punch, like drones.

"Our country will continue to promote defence reforms, strengthen whole‑of‑society defence resilience, demonstrate our determination to defend ourselves, and safeguard peace through strength," Taiwan presidential office spokesperson Karen Kuo said in a statement, thanking the United States for the sales.

Taiwan President Lai Ching-te last month announced a $40 billion supplementary defence budget , to run from 2026 to 2033, saying there was "no room for compromise on national security".

China's foreign ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.

Rupert Hammond-Chambers, president of the U.S.-Taiwan Business Council, said weapons like the HIMARS, which have been used extensively by Ukraine against Russian forces, could play an essential role in destroying an invading Chinese force.

"This bundle of congressional notifications, a record in U.S. security assistance for Taiwan, is a response to the threat from China and the demand from Mr. Trump that partners and allies do more to secure their own defence," he added.

The announcement followed an unannounced trip by Taiwan's Foreign Minister Lin Chia-lung to the Washington-area last week to meet U.S. officials, according to two sources who spoke to Reuters on condition of anonymity.

Reuters was unable to determine the agenda of the meetings and Taiwan's foreign ministry declined to comment.

Washington has formal diplomatic ties with Beijing, but maintains unofficial ties with Taiwan and is the island's most important arms supplier. The U.S. is bound by law to provide Taiwan with the means to defend itself, though such arms sales are a persistent source of friction with China.

Trump's penchant for dealmaking and his planned visit to Chinese President Xi Jinping next year, have kindled fears in the region of weakening U.S. support for Taiwan.

But U.S. officials told Reuters at the outset of Trump's second term this year that they had plans to ramp up weapons sales to Taipei to a level exceeding Trump's first term as part of an effort to deter China.

The Trump administration's national security strategy unveiled earlier this month said the U.S. aimed to deter conflict over Taiwan by "preserving military overmatch" against China in the region, language welcomed in Taipei.

The strategy also highlighted Taiwan's strategic importance due to its location dividing "Northeast and Southeast Asia into two distinct theatres".

China views Taiwan as its own territory, a position Taipei rejects.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:39 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/COHVOCUUNJJ5XPJJHL7NUTPJCE.jpg?auth=6d35436c20c7e830072a6456de87027a88038deeb664b605c18ba80f68c68495&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Three dead, cargo ship catches fire in drone attacks on Russia's Rostov region</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/three-dead-cargo-ship-catches-fire-drone-attacks-russias-rostov-region-2025-12-18/</link><description>MOSCOW, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Three people, including two crew members of a cargo vessel, were killed in overnight Ukrainian drone attacks on the Russian port of Rostov-on-Don and the town of Bataysk in the southern Rostov region, the local governor said on Thursday.

Yuri Slyusar, writing on Telegram, said the fire at the vessel was put out, while three more crew members were injured. The governor also said that seven people were injured in an attack on Bataysk.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Brazil Senate approves bill to cut Bolsonaro's 27-year sentence for coup plot</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazil-senate-approves-bill-cut-bolsonaros-27-year-sentence-coup-plot-2025-12-17/</link><description>BRASILIA, Dec 17 (Reuters) - Brazil's Senate approved on Wednesday a bill to shorten the 27-year prison sentence of former President Jair Bolsonaro, although it is likely to face resistance from the Supreme Court and President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.

The bill was approved by the lower house last week and now goes to Lula, who has not said whether he will sign it into law or veto it. It could cut the former president's prison term to just over two years.

The text also establishes sentence reductions for those convicted for their roles in a January 2023 riot , opens new tab , when Bolsonaro supporters invaded and ransacked the presidential palace, Supreme Court and Congress.

"This is part of our path to peace, and we must all celebrate it," said Senator Esperidiao Amin, the bill's sponsor in the Senate, following its approval in a 48-25 vote.

Last month, Bolsonaro began serving his sentence for plotting a coup against Lula after losing the 2022 election.

A preliminary version of the bill put forward by opposition right-wing lawmakers would have pardoned those involved in "political demonstrations" after Lula's election, but the bill's sponsor in the lower house ruled out granting them full amnesty.

About 2,000 people were arrested over the Brasilia attack, which drew comparisons to the January 2021 attack on the U.S. Capitol in Washington. Many of those in Brazil have been convicted by the Supreme Court of attempting a coup, among other crimes.

The bill changes the calculation of sentences to avoid cumulative punishments for multiple crimes. It also provides reduced sentences for defendants who took part in acts in a crowd context, but not as leaders or in financing positions.

Senator Flavio Bolsonaro, the former president's eldest son who got his father's support this month to run for president next year, welcomed the bill's approval in a short video posted on social media.

"It wasn't exactly what we wanted, but it was what was possible within the current situation in Congress," he said.

Despite Lula's relative silence about the bill, government ministers and lawmakers aligned with the administration have shown strong opposition to the move, signaling the president will certainly veto it.

"The government is against this proposal... for reasons that are already known: those who have attacked democracy must pay for their crimes," Institutional Relations Minister Gleisi Hoffmann said in a post on X ahead of the vote.

Lula previously said that he would wait for the bill to "get to his desk" before a decision on whether to sign it into law, adding he would take "the best decision for Brazil."

The bill was amended during an earlier vote on Wednesday in a Senate committee to make it clear that sentence reductions will only apply to those involved in acts related to the attempted coup, and not to other crimes.

Amin argued that the change did not force the bill to return to the lower house, as it was a simple adjustment to the wording.

The change in the text has raised the prospect of the bill being taken to court. The leader of Lula's Workers' Party in the lower house, lawmaker Lindbergh Farias, said he was ready to take legal action.

"What is happening in the Senate is a shame," Farias said in a post on X shortly before the conclusion of the vote in the Senate, adding he already had a request to appeal the bill in the Supreme Court.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:53 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/ZRFEEA4I6JM2RPLKQDTBK2ZU4I.jpg?auth=af4d60260fac504acc290705e3bd8cb45fec2d9fca29f47ce38b154a83809281&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Ukrainian drones kill three people in Russia's Rostov region, authorities say</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/ukrainian-drones-hit-tanker-russias-rostov-port-causing-deaths-mayor-says-2025-12-18/</link><description>Dec 18 (Reuters) - Three people, including two crew members of a cargo vessel, were killed in overnight Ukrainian drone attacks on the Russian port of Rostov-on-Don and the town of Bataysk in the southern Rostov region, the local governor said on Thursday.

The fire was extinguished, Yuri Slyusar wrote on his Telegram messaging app channel.

Rostov-on-Don head Alexander Skryabin said earlier that a leak of oil products had been avoided.

Ukraine and Russia have accused each other of deliberately attacking civilian vessels. Russian President Vladimir Putin has threatened to " cut Ukraine off from the sea" after Kyiv's attacks damaged three 'shadow fleet' tankers heading to Russia to export its oil earlier this month.

One person was killed and seven people were injured in the town of Bataysk where two private homes caught fire as result of a drone attack, Slyusar also said.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:02 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Mass layoffs overshadow Guinea's Simandou mega mine as output accelerates</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/mass-layoffs-overshadow-guineas-simandou-mega-mine-output-accelerates-2025-12-18/</link><description>SIMANDOU, Guinea, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Guinea's Simandou mega mining project, promoted by the military government as a symbol of the country's economic transformation, is laying off thousands of workers just as it begins exporting iron ore after decades of delays and corruption scandals.

Simandou was officially launched with pomp and a public holiday in November, ahead of elections on December 28, the first since the military coup in 2021 that brought Mamady Doumbouya to power.

The junta leader is standing for president and political analysts say he is the favourite to win, meaning he could be in power for another seven years.

Even without Simandou, the world's largest untapped reserve of iron ore, Guinea is the world's biggest exporter of bauxite , used to make aluminium. Its mining wealth, however, has failed to transform for the better the lives of many of its people.

World Bank data published in 2025 showed more than half the population lived in poverty.

Reuters interviewed a dozen workers and former employees, as well as some senior company sources. Asking not to be named because of the sensitivity of the issue, they said the process of sacking thousands of workers had begun and that the impact was likely to be more severe than in the case of comparable mining projects.

It is a bitter disappointment for those who hoped their lives would be improved for the long term by Simandou's ambitions to produce around 120 million metric tons of iron ore annually, or around 7% of global demand.

Employment from Simandou peaked at over 60,000 jobs in 2024 and 2025, companies and government sources told Reuters, as contractors raced to meet deadlines set by Guinea's military rulers to try to fast-track iron ore exports after nearly three decades of delay.

Fewer than 15,000 people will be needed to run the mines, the ports, and the 670 kilometre (416-mile) railway specially built to allow export from the landlocked project.

The project is run by two consortia – one led by Rio Tinto (RIO.L) , opens new tab , (RIO.AX) , opens new tab and the other by the Winning Consortium Simandou, or WCS, comprising mostly Chinese companies.

The way the work has been organised means the workforce reduction is extreme.

One executive involved said the railway was "a simultaneous spread project," meaning every section was built at the same time, the labour force was ramped up to peak construction, "then falls off a cliff because everything finishes".

WCS, which manages almost all of the railway via more than a dozen subcontractors, did not respond to requests for comment on its workforce.

Rio Tinto, through a joint venture Rio Tinto-Simfer, is in charge of two mine blocks, 78 kilometres of rail connecting them to the main rail network and transshipment facilities at the new port on Guinea's Atlantic coast. In all, it has provided employment for around 25,000 workers, 82% of them Guinean, over the construction phase.

For the operational phase, a spokesperson for Rio Tinto said the Simfer venture was expected to require a workforce of about 6,000 to work in the mine and at a transshipment vessel terminal at the port. The mine and rail construction is scheduled to be completed next year, while work at the port will continue through 2027, the spokesperson said.

Chris Aitchison, managing director at Rio Tinto-Simfer, said he was concerned about the risks raised by sudden job losses, which the industry refers to as demobilisation.

"It's the what's next?" he said. "In other jurisdictions when we demobilise there's a pathway for employees or people that have been engaged in execution to move to other projects."

In comparable projects, such as Mongolia's Oyu Tolgoi copper mine, for example, more diversified economies meant former mining employees had other job options.

The workforce sources said the job-cutting had begun. In Dantilia, a hub in the Faranah region near Sierra Leone's border, 8,000 of 10,000 workers have lost their jobs the last three months. The other 2,000 have been told their jobs will end in the coming months.

In Kamara, part of the same district, around 1,500 workers have already been dismissed, the workers said.

"We are waiting in hope but for now they don't have any solutions, and they haven't promised anything yet," a pick-up driver for the Winning Consortium Simandou told Reuters, asking not to be named. "There is no other job."

Three Western company sources said concern was mounting that reduced staffing could increase the risk of accidents, as well as of social unrest.

They said they were worried about the likelihood of community protests that could take the form of blockades along the Simandou railway, where trains have already killed cattle, angering local residents who depend on their livestock.

Risk assessments carried out by the consortia in the last six months flagged the places where people or livestock could stray onto tracks and derail trains, prompting the construction of fencing that the original design did not provide for, company sources said.

In March, Reuters reported that a dozen workers had died in accidents during Simandou's railway construction between June 2023 and November 2024. In addition, at least five local residents were killed in traffic accidents involving vehicles from the works.

Rio Tinto and WCS reported a further five worker deaths.

Mines minister Bouna Sylla said the government was strict with the partners on safety and environmental safeguards.

Guinea's limited infrastructure, narrow skill base, and lack of income buffers magnify the impact of the sudden loss of jobs.

Speaking to media in the days ahead of Simandou's official launch on November 11, Sylla acknowledged the layoffs would be painful.

"It's not easy for people who've been earning a salary, waking up early for work every day, to suddenly lose it," Sylla said. He outlined government plans for new infrastructure projects, including roads, refineries and power plants, but he did not give any timing.

The official launch at the new export port at Morebaya on Guinea's Atlantic coast was resolutely upbeat, with brass bands, honour guards, traditional dancers and visiting dignitaries. Doumbouya looked on, dressed in a white Guinean boubou tunic.

In an attempt to provide thousands of future jobs, Guinea's military government has touted "Simandou 2040" as a 15-year strategy to transform the country into a diversified economy, based on investment in agriculture, education, transport, technology, finance and health for the entire population.

The government holds a 15% stake in Simandou and the plan's estimated $200 billion cost would be partly funded by mining revenues, although it has said the bulk should come from private capital.

Sylla said Guinea's infrastructure agency the Administration et Contrôle des Grands Projets was working on feasibility studies. The government also commissioned a KPMG report on re-employment programmes, which will be published after the elections, two sources said.

KPMG did not respond to a request for comment. The infrastructure agency said the plans included 3,000 kilometres of new highways to be developed over 15 years.

But nearly 30 years after Rio started exploring the deposit, the question of whether Simandou can deliver prosperity for most of Guinea is unanswered.

The IMF in its "Selected issues" paper on Guinea's economy, published in May 2024, modelled the macroeconomic effects of Simandou.

It found it could boost the country's real GDP by 26% by 2030, but it also said the reduction in poverty could be minimal at just 0.6 percentage points without active policies to manage the transition.

The project's impact in increasing the number of skilled workers could even lead "to worsening of inequality, especially in rural areas," it said.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:06 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/HIZA5NHUMNOQ5OVT4DZTNCQX5I.jpg?auth=42415b2bb34f6b7ad7453cff8d3239e66569738f52573f8b24e6971782d522b9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Can Ukraine survive without the EU's 'reparation loan'?</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/can-ukraine-survive-without-eus-reparation-loan-2025-12-18/</link><description>KYIV, Dec 18 (Reuters) - European Union leaders are set to review on Thursday proposals for using the proceeds from immobilised Russian sovereign assets, mostly held in Belgium, to support Ukraine's financial needs for the coming years - the so-called "reparations loan".

The main issue still to be resolved is Belgium's demand that others in the 27-nation bloc share the financial risks if Russia were to successfully sue either Belgium or the Belgian central securities depository Euroclear, where they are held.

President Volodymyr Zelenskiy called this week for unity in Europe on the allocation of frozen assets, saying that Ukraine faced financial difficulties and would be unable to "remain strong economically" without this financing.

How much money does Ukraine need?

The International Monetary Fund (IMF) estimates that Ukraine will need about 135 billion euros ($158.57 billion) for 2026 and 2027.

For the next year alone, the Ukrainian state budget plans for total spending of 4.8 trillion hryvnias ($112 billion) against revenues of 2.9 trillion hryvnias. The budget deficit is set at around 1.9 trillion hryvnias or 18.5% of gross domestic product.

Finance Minister Serhiy Marchenko said the country would need more than $45 billion in external financing in 2026.

Roksolana Pidlasa, head of the parliamentary budget committee, said the government still needed to secure $18-20 billion in external financing to be able to cover the 2026 budget gap.

With no immediate peace deal with Russia in sight, Ukraine plans to spend the bulk of state revenues - 2.8 trillion hryvnias or around 27.2% of GDP - to fund its defence efforts in 2026.

The front line with Russian forces stretches more than 1,200 km (750 miles) in the east and south, and Ukraine has about one million people in its defence forces.

Demand for weapons and ammunition keeps rising and the daily cost of fighting Russian forces is estimated at $172 million in 2025, compared with $140 million a year ago, officials said.

Ukraine needs international financial assistance to be able to fund its social and humanitarian spending in addition to defence aid. Since Russia's full-scale invasion in February 2022, Ukraine has received more than $160 billion in foreign financial aid from partners.

Even if a peace deal were signed quickly, that would not remove financial pressures on Kyiv, analysts said. Ukraine's military needs would stabilise, but not ease quickly. The army would still need re-equipping, rotation, modernisation, and sustained logistical support, they added.

Pidlasa said a positive decision on the reparation loan as soon as possible was crucial. The best-case scenario would be to have a fully approved decision in January, with the first tranches to start arriving in the first quarter of 2026, she said, while adding that Ukraine could manage with its own resources in the first quarter of next year.

An EU approval of the reparation loan would also help to unlock other funding. Last month, Ukraine secured preliminary approval from the IMF on its new four-year, $8.2 billion programme to help maintain macroeconomic and financial stability. But final approval depended on a positive decision on the reparation loan, Pidlasa said.

($1 = 0.8514 euros)</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:12 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RW3CYGFLFJK6VL5BOV6WOYOUL4.jpg?auth=74be352afc22273fb72b8332825db7cd14644b102d19ff71dd3a6a066f8290d8&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Bolivia president removes fuel subsidies</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/bolivia-president-removes-fuel-subsidies-2025-12-18/</link><description>LA PAZ, Dec 17 (Reuters) - Bolivian President Rodrigo Paz, who took office last month, on Wednesday said his government would remove long-standing fuel subsidies in a bid to shore up public accounts.

"This does not mean abandonment (by the government), it means order, justice; redistribution that's real, clear and transparent," he said in a nationwide address.

While Paz said the details of the move would be laid out in a pending government decree, they appeared to apply immediately to the agriculture and business sectors, which the president previously said he would target first.

Paz also said he would open the door to allowing direct diesel imports, as state-run oil company YPFB has struggled to secure supply.

Bolivia froze fuel prices in 2006, with a liter of diesel costing 3.72 bolivianos ($0.5431) and premium gasoline at 3.74 bolivianos. Diesel will now cost 9.80 bolivianos per liter and premium will cost 6.96 bolivianos per liter.

Oil and Gas Minister Mauricio Medinaceli said prices would be fixed for six months, though he did not rule out further adjustments.

Paz has inherited an economy in turmoil and faces tricky negotiations in the legislature to pass reforms that economists say are needed to stabilize the country's finances.

($1 = 6.8500 bolivianos)</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:19 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/C5BJH3L5WRKF3IQOT2N2XLH53Q.jpg?auth=a64c69d7e2eb9df8c69f755fe0eeaae19f95cb12b710a8eb24dadce1ccbc24d2&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Zelenskiy tells Europe: Use frozen assets to end Russia's appetite for war</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/zelenskiy-tells-europe-use-frozen-assets-end-russias-appetite-war-2025-12-17/</link><description>KYIV, Dec 17 (Reuters) - President Volodymyr Zelenskiy called on Ukraine's allies on Wednesday to secure support for Kyiv and show Russia that continuing its war is "pointless," ahead of a crucial European Union summit on Moscow's frozen assets.

"The outcome of these meetings – the outcome for Europe – must be such that Russia feels that its desire to continue fighting next year will be pointless, because Ukraine will have support," Zelenskiy said in his evening address.

He called on Ukraine's partners to take a decision on using the nearly $250 billion of frozen Russian sovereign assets in the European Union, most of it held in Belgium's Euroclear, to support a loan for Ukraine.

EU governments agreed last week to freeze the assets for as long as needed instead of voting every six months on extending this status. Some European leaders have opposed the plan as they fear it opens them up to legal risk.

"We need all our partners to have the courage to see the truth, acknowledge the truth and act accordingly," Zelenskiy said. He added that Russia was showing with its actions it intended to continue fighting next year.

"Allies in the United States often say that Russia seems to want to end the war. But Russia is sending completely different rhetoric and signals, including official orders to its army."

In Moscow on Wednesday, President Vladimir Putin said Russia would take more land in Ukraine by force if Kyiv and European politicians whom he cast as "young pigs" did not engage over U.S. proposals for a peace settlement.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:26 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/A2HKYPLDMVMXFA5NEXBKN7B3EE.jpg?auth=6fa2c9fe554cfed929e53cf2548cc4337a5a0564b516f2342ff40742c83191ea&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>EU leaders to agree Ukraine financing in 2026-27, Belgium's approval key</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-leaders-agree-ukraine-financing-2026-27-belgiums-approval-key-2025-12-18/</link><description>BRUSSELS, Dec 18 (Reuters) - European Union leaders will decide on Thursday how to finance Ukraine in 2026 and 2027 to keep it fighting Russia's invasion, with the use of Russian assets frozen in the EU the preferred option, but hinging on Belgium's uncertain approval.

The EU wants to keep Ukraine financed and fighting because it sees Russia's war as a threat to its own security. EU leaders are also keen to show European countries' agency and strength after U.S. President Donald Trump last week called them "weak".

With U.S. financial help for Kyiv drying up under the Trump administration and EU national budgets already under strain, the EU is looking to use the 210 billion euros of Russian central bank assets frozen in the bloc as a basis for a loan to Ukraine.

The stakes are high because without the EU's financial help Ukraine will run out of money in the second quarter of next year and most likely lose the war to Russia, which the EU fears would bring closer the threat of Russian aggression against the EU.

"If we do not find an answer to that question (of how to finance Ukraine in 2026 and 2027), we will not enable Ukraine to defend itself," a senior EU diplomat said. "That would have severe implications ... for the security of the rest of Europe."

"It would also have severe implications for the credibility of Europe and underline that we are as weak as Trump apparently thinks we are," the diplomat said.

One of the financing options could be for the EU to borrow the needed amount against the security of the EU budget and then lend the money on to Ukraine, but such a move would require unanimity among the 27 EU countries and Moscow-friendly Hungary has already said it would veto it.

Another option would be for each willing EU country itself to raise money on the market and pass it on to Kyiv, but that would mean a rise in the already high debt and deficit levels and a lack of longer-term financing certainty for Ukraine.

Diplomats said the use of the Russian assets was therefore in practice "the only game in town" and favoured by most countries because it ensured a large sum for Ukraine without increasing national debts or any immediate fiscal effort.

But to use it, EU leaders first need to convince Belgium, which holds 185 billion euros of the total 210 billion euros frozen in Europe, that they will not leave it alone with the bill if Russia successfully sues in international courts over the plan.

Most EU countries are willing to give such guarantees. But Belgian Prime Minister Bart de Wever has argued that because damages awarded to Russia in a successful court case could far exceed the amount held by Belgium and the trial could take place many years from now, he effectively needs a blank cheque from other governments for an indefinite period.

"There are limits to the guarantees member states could give," another senior EU diplomat said.

"De Wever seems to want indefinite guarantees, and no EU member state can offer indefinite guarantees. No EU government can go to its own parliament and ask for indefinite guarantees for indefinite amounts of euros. That's simply not possible," the senior diplomat said.

The discussions among leaders on Thursday will therefore focus on narrowing down the scope of the guarantees to a form that would also be acceptable to other EU countries, diplomats said, stressing a financing solution for Ukraine will be found.

"This is not a European Council where we can part ways on Friday and not have anything," a third senior EU diplomat said.

"So a solution will be available on Friday morning."</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:35 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/5L65KEXDIBMENARGNF6R5MLLTQ.jpg?auth=7ec6aced293cb415bd7d318e1d5fef7fd8e48e4b987a11fd335cd99aa3ab6166&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Takeaways from Trump's year-end address to the nation</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/takeaways-trumps-year-end-address-nation-2025-12-18/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Dec 17 (Reuters) - U.S. President Donald Trump used a pre-holiday address from the White House on Wednesday to portray his first year in office as a success story, even as Americans worry about the economy and Republicans face tough midterm elections in 2026.

Here are four takeaways from the speech :

Trump began his remarks with 14 words that captured the central theme of the night: "Good evening, America. Eleven months ago, I inherited a mess, and I'm fixing it."

In other words: It's not my fault.

The president, responding to voters' anxiety over the cost of living, laid blame at the feet of former President Joe Biden in the nearly 20 minutes that followed, mentioning his name seven times. The economy? Biden's fault. Crime? Biden. Healthcare? Biden. Bad immigration policy? You guessed it.

Trump has often blamed Biden for problems that have festered during his first year back in office, from Russia's war in Ukraine to the eyesore of offshore wind farms. He followed that playbook again on Wednesday, particularly when it came to the high cost of living, which he sought to cast as fleeting - just as Biden once did when prices rose.

"What a difference a year makes," Trump said, dismissing the mood of consumers , adding that the U.S. is "poised for an economic boom the likes of which the world has never seen."

Trump chose to give the address from the Diplomatic Reception Room at the White House, rather than the Oval Office, and the setting allowed him to speak like he does at his signature rallies: behind a podium, standing up.

The president gripped that podium and delivered his talking points at a blistering pace, standing between two flags and against a backdrop of green garland.

Trump did not offer either good cheer or empathy to Americans struggling with high costs for food, housing and holiday gifts, however. And his only holiday-themed greeting at all came at the end with a brief "Merry Christmas" and "Happy New Year" wish to viewers.

Though White House spokeswoman Karoline Leavitt had told reporters Trump might tease new policy in his speech, the president offered little hint of his forthcoming plans.

He said his administration would pursue aggressive new housing policies next year, promised to name a new Federal Reserve chair soon and unveiled a plan to send checks for $1,776 to U.S. troops.

Otherwise, the topics of his speech largely reflected a greatest hits version of his political rallies. He railed against Somalis in Minnesota, whom he accused of stealing from the United States; talked about men playing in women's sports; and reiterated his often-used remark that the country a year ago was "dead."

Notably absent from the speech was a major focus on foreign policy issues that have captured a significant share of Trump’s second term in office.

Heading into the remarks, Trump allies speculated about how prominently the speech would focus on an escalating confrontation with Venezuela.

Trump has ramped up pressure on the South American nation’s leadership in recent weeks, and on Tuesday he ordered a "blockade" of all sanctioned oil tankers entering and leaving the country. It’s not clear whether Trump intends to try to force out the country’s president, Nicolas Maduro.

That question wasn’t answered on Wednesday. Instead, Trump focused largely on the economy, allowing himself only a short victory lap for his work on the Middle East and peacemaking generally.

Trump’s allies have warned his aides in recent weeks that he needs to shift focus from international conflicts to kitchen-table issues, according to a person familiar with the matter. Whether he was effective or not, for at least 18 minutes on a Wednesday night, he seemed to heed the advice.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:39 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/3QKDWWLE6JNYPN2OWYHA7YNEGY.jpg?auth=5925760a40650e14749a0de8ecd900fb5311f8963101910a2a63c75400345640&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US demands that Honduras proceed immediately with stalled election count</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/honduras-special-election-recount-still-paralyzed-amid-protests-2025-12-17/</link><description>TEGUCIGALPA, Dec 17 (Reuters) - The U.S. Department of State demanded that Honduras' National Electoral Council immediately begin a manual count of ballots from last month's presidential election, which has been stalled by protests and wrangling over alleged fraud.
The electoral council has blamed protests for preventing it from starting the manual count of hundreds of thousands of ballots that it said showed inconsistencies and were therefore excluded from the initial tally.

Adding those ballots to the overall count could easily overturn conservative Nasry Asfura's current razor-thin margin of 43,000 votes - out of more than 3 million cast - over center-right candidate Salvador Nasralla.

"Any call to disrupt public order or the CNE's (election council's) work will be met with consequences," the U.S. State Department's Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs said in a post on X. "The voices of 3.4 million Hondurans must be respected and upheld."

A spokesperson for the Honduras presidency did not respond to a request for comment about Washington's remarks.
The chaotic vote-tallying process has fueled tensions and political clashes that were already at a high pitch after U.S. President Donald Trump backed Asfura, the 67-year-old former mayor of Tegucigalpa, and suggested that Washington's support for Honduras was conditional on Asfura winning the election.
Nasralla, a television host and three-time presidential candidate, told Reuters that he believed Trump's comments had damaged his chances.

Trailing far behind in third place is Rixi Moncada of the ruling leftist party LIBRE.

Nasralla has said he believed the election was marred by fraud. Both Nasralla and LIBRE have demanded a manual recount of all ballots that were cast, but the election council has said it only needs to look at the ballots that were excluded from the initial count.

On Wednesday afternoon, LIBRE leaders called on their supporters to gather at the presidential palace to protest what they called an electoral coup and interference by Trump.

"Today, democracy in Honduras is in serious trouble. They want to manipulate our democracy and make decisions that only the people should make," President Xiomara Castro told thousands of protesters who were dressed in the ruling party's red colors and chanted "vote-by-vote."

Election officials have blamed the stalled manual count of suspect tally sheets on LIBRE protesters blocking the building where they work.

"Our officials cannot enter to perform their duties," Ana Paola Hall, president of the National Electoral Council, said on Tuesday night.

In a document addressed to fellow members on the electoral council, Hall said there was no legal basis for granting a manual recount of all votes unless there was concrete evidence of irregularities.

The electoral council has until December 30 to declare the winner of the election, who would assume office at the end of January for a four-year term.

Major international election observers, including the European Union and the Organization of American States, have expressed concern over the chaotic and delayed vote count but have not reported evidence of systemic fraud.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:43 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4E3LZOOKJNKHXP33V45V2JQ2GM.jpg?auth=d78795619b96d42d2b190cf6baec19b4026b0453381c187832f30d214e6a2ddb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Belarus' Lukashenko says US admission of failure to overturn re-election could revive relations</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/belarus-lukashenko-says-us-admission-failure-overturn-re-election-could-revive-2025-12-18/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US military says it conducted strike on a vessel in eastern Pacific, killing four men</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-military-says-it-conducted-strike-vessel-eastern-pacific-killing-four-men-2025-12-18/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia to introduce legislation to crack down on hate, PM says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-introduce-legislation-crack-down-hate-pm-says-2025-12-18/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:46:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU must reform or risk irrelevance, Blair and Dimon say</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/eu-must-reform-or-risk-irrelevance-blair-dimon-say-2025-12-18/</link><description>LONDON, Dec 18 (Reuters) - The European Union must reform or risk becoming irrelevant as the rivalry between China and the U.S. sparks a new era without precedent, posing challenges on security, energy, technology and trade, a report led by Tony Blair and Jamie Dimon says.

Based on conversations with government, business and civil leaders, the report sets out how a convergence of structural shifts is reshaping nations, markets and institutions, threatening those countries and groupings that once relied on the U.S. for security while growing trade ties with China.

Blair, British prime minister from 1997 to 2007, and Dimon, the head of JPMorgan Chase, said Europe needed to integrate further to prioritise defence and economic growth.

"If it cannot stand on its own against Russia, it will be even less able to manage systemic competition with the U.S. or China," their report said. "Reform is not optional; it is required to remain relevant."

The blunt summary comes as the EU hosts a summit to discuss funding for Ukraine and how it can respond to the "changed landscape for rules-based economic relations", and as U.S. President Donald Trump heaps pressure on the bloc, including with a new National Security Strategy.

The head of the EU Commission, Ursula von der Leyen, has said that Europe must reform and be responsible for its own security . Supporters of the bloc would note that while Europe's share of global GDP is declining, the U.S. is on the same path.

The report also set out the challenge posed to middle powers such as India and the Gulf states from the new dynamic, as part of a broad overview of how geopolitics, artificial intelligence and political populism were upending the world order.

Alexander George, an author of the "World Rewired: Navigating a Multi-Speed, Multipolar Order" report, said people had previously been able to look to moments in history for guidance.

"We're really living in a new world which has never actually existed before," he said. "It's like this 3D chess board."

The report said the U.S. retained enduring power but faced its greatest threats at home where political volatility makes it harder to tackle high debt, while China's trajectory will hinge on whether it can maintain growth despite demographic and debt constraints.

On middle powers it said the steep U.S. tariffs on India in retaliation for its purchase of Russian oil showed the limitations to a multi-alignment approach, while the UAE's move to strengthen U.S. technology ties showed that countries were having to choose between the U.S. and China on tech.

The report was produced by Dimon's JPMorgan Chase, which has launched a $1.5 trillion, decade-long plan to support industries deemed vital to U.S. economic security and resilience, and the Tony Blair Institute for Global Change.

Blair is the chair of JPMorgan's international council which advises the firm on strategy and geopolitics.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:24:36 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/6NDW6V4NKJKHFIRMZCKDI5Q7JI.jpg?auth=e0591dedd7075b74c09b6f84557325a0e6c8fde307a58c79b33a57e282122831&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russian attack on Ukraine's central Cherkasy injures six, causes blackouts, governor says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-attack-ukraines-central-cherkasy-injures-six-causes-blackouts-governor-2025-12-18/</link><description>Dec 18 (Reuters) - Russia launched a "massive" drone attack on Ukraine's central Cherkasy region, injuring six people and triggering a blackout in part of Cherkasy city, the local governor said on Thursday.

"A difficult night for our Cherkasy region," Governor Ihor Taburets said on the Telegram messaging app.

Taburets said the attack targeted critical infrastructure and that part of the region's main city was without power. He also reported damage to more than a dozen of private houses.

The military said Russia had launched 82 drones on Ukraine overnight, and Ukrainian forces destroyed 63 of them.

The governor of the southern Mykolaiv region said Russia attacked energy infrastructure there, leaving settlements in the Voznesensk and Mykolaiv districts without power, though it was later restored to most households.

Russia has sharply increased the number and intensity of its attacks on Ukrainian infrastructure in recent months, targeting gas, energy and distribution facilities and plunging entire cities into darkness. An attack over the weekend left more than a million households across Ukraine without power.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:25:08 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>China voices support for Venezuela amid US blockade, but makes no aid pledges</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-voices-support-venezuela-says-it-opposes-unilateral-bullying-2025-12-17/</link><description>BEIJING, Dec 18 (Reuters) - China opposed what it said was "unilateral bullying" after Washington ordered a blockade of sanctioned tankers entering and leaving oil-rich Venezuela, but did not say exactly how it would come to the South American country's aid or offer any refuge for its embattled leader.

Earlier this week, U.S. President Donald Trump ordered a complete blockade of all sanctioned oil tankers attempting to leave Venezuelan waters, and those arriving, as Washington massed troops and warships in the region.

China is the biggest buyer of Venezuelan crude, which accounts for roughly 4% of its imports, with shipments in December on track to average more than 600,000 barrels per day, analysts have said.

Beijing opposes all forms of "unilateral bullying" and supports countries in safeguarding their sovereignty and national dignity, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi told his Venezuelan counterpart Yvan Gil on a phone call on Wednesday.

Wang did not name the United States or Trump in the official readout of the call. Wang also did not elaborate on the form or extent of the support that China might or could offer to Venezuela, with which Beijing previously said it had forged an ironclad friendship.

The U.S. is squeezing Venezuela's principal source of revenue in its attempt to target terrorism, drug smuggling and human trafficking, according to Trump. Last week, the U.S. Coast Guard seized an oil tanker off the coast of Venezuela.

President Nicolas Maduro has said the U.S. wants the OPEC nation's crude oil resources, and the military build-up was to overthrow him. In an interview with Politico, Trump said Maduro's days were " numbered , opens new tab ".

For years, China has extended credit lines to Venezuela under loans-for-oil deals. In a meeting with Chinese President Xi Jinping in Moscow this year, Maduro told Xi that Venezuela was looking forward to expanding cooperation in trade and energy.

At the same time, Beijing has been making an intense effort to co-exist with the U.S., its most important trading partner. After months of acrimonious dispute over trade and tariffs, Trump and Xi in October managed to hammer out a consensus on how to handle thorny trade issues.

China says it opposes any acts that violate the UN Charter or encroach on the sovereignty and security of other countries.

"China believes the international community understands and supports Venezuela's position in defending its legitimate rights and interests," Wang said.

United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has urged the de-escalation of tensions, asking the U.S. and Venezuela to honour their obligations under international law, including the UN Charter and any other applicable legal framework to safeguard peace in the region.

The presidents of Mexico and Brazil have also urged restraint and dialogue.

Russian President Vladimir Putin , in a phone call to Maduro last week, "reaffirmed his support for the policy of N. Maduro's government, aimed at protecting national interests and sovereignty in the face of growing external pressure."

Venezuela on Wednesday requested the UN Security Council meet to discuss the "ongoing U.S. aggression", according to a letter to the 15-member body seen by Reuters.

China supports Venezuela's request for an urgent meeting of the council, a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said on Thursday, when asked at a regular news briefing what role China, as a "responsible" major power, would play.

Asked whether what Caracas has described as U.S. "aggression" could put China and the U.S. on a collision course in the region, the spokesperson reiterated Wang Yi's comments and did not say more.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:31:26 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/HUI4FULDF5P2RP56JMWC2SSTNY.jpg?auth=14e2d56ce9e219b6dddb0f878c3e9007ab578b98aa46c9560a854528f0ed7c2d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Ukrainian negotiators to meet US team on Friday, Saturday, Zelenskiy says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/ukrainian-negotiators-meet-us-team-friday-saturday-zelenskiy-says-2025-12-18/</link><description>KYIV, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Ukrainian peace negotiators are en route to the United States and plan to meet the U.S. negotiating team on Friday and Saturday, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Thursday.

Zelenskiy told reporters in a WhatsApp media chat that there were no final aligned peace proposals for now, reiterating his plea to partners to strengthen Ukraine in case Russia refuses to stop its war.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:58:30 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/A2HKYPLDMVMXFA5NEXBKN7B3EE.jpg?auth=6fa2c9fe554cfed929e53cf2548cc4337a5a0564b516f2342ff40742c83191ea&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Putin says Russia will take more land in Ukraine if Europe sinks peace moves</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-says-western-calls-preparation-war-with-russia-a-lie-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela requests UN Security Council meet over ‘ongoing US aggression’</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/venezuela-requests-un-security-council-meet-over-ongoing-us-aggression-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No evidence alleged Bondi gunmen received military training in the Philippines, says security adviser</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/no-evidence-alleged-bondi-gunmen-received-military-training-philippines-says-2025-12-18/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exclusive: Poland to start producing anti-personnel mines to lay along eastern border</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/poland-start-producing-anti-personnel-mines-lay-along-eastern-border-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 12 killed in Nigeria mining site attack, group says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/least-12-killed-nigeria-mining-site-attack-group-says-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US House defeats bids to rein in Trump Venezuela campaign</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-house-defeats-bids-rein-trump-venezuela-campaign-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil's Supreme Court votes to affirm Indigenous land rights in defiance of Congress</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/brazil-supreme-court-affirms-indigenous-land-rights-defying-congress-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alleged Bondi gunman charged with 15 murders as funerals of victims begin</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/sydney-funerals-begin-bondi-beach-hanukkah-shooting-victims-2025-12-16/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:59:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin says Russia will take more land in Ukraine if Europe sinks peace moves</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-says-western-calls-preparation-war-with-russia-a-lie-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela requests UN Security Council meet over ‘ongoing US aggression’</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/venezuela-requests-un-security-council-meet-over-ongoing-us-aggression-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No evidence alleged Bondi gunmen received military training in the Philippines, says security adviser</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/no-evidence-alleged-bondi-gunmen-received-military-training-philippines-says-2025-12-18/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exclusive: Poland to start producing anti-personnel mines to lay along eastern border</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/poland-start-producing-anti-personnel-mines-lay-along-eastern-border-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 12 killed in Nigeria mining site attack, group says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/least-12-killed-nigeria-mining-site-attack-group-says-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US House defeats bids to rein in Trump Venezuela campaign</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-house-defeats-bids-rein-trump-venezuela-campaign-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil's Supreme Court votes to affirm Indigenous land rights in defiance of Congress</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/brazil-supreme-court-affirms-indigenous-land-rights-defying-congress-2025-12-17/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alleged Bondi gunman charged with 15 murders as funerals of victims begin</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/sydney-funerals-begin-bondi-beach-hanukkah-shooting-victims-2025-12-16/</link><description /><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia sentences Briton who it says fought for Ukraine to 13 years in a prison camp</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/russia-sentences-briton-who-it-says-fought-ukraine-13-years-prison-camp-2025-12-18/</link><description>MOSCOW, Dec 18 (Reuters) - A British man who Moscow says fought for Ukraine against the Russian army has been sentenced to 13 years in a maximum security prison camp after being convicted of being a paid mercenary, Russian prosecutors said on Thursday.

The office of Russia's Prosecutor General named the jailed Briton as 30-year-old Hayden Davies and said he had been tried by a court in a part of Russian-controlled Donetsk, one of four Ukrainian regions which Moscow claimed as its own in 2022.

The Russian statement did not say how Davies had pleaded.

It said Davies had arrived in western Ukraine in August 2024, signed a contract to fight for the International Legion for the Defence of Ukraine, undergone military training, and then fought against the Russian army in Donetsk.

Davies had been captured by Russia in winter 2024 carrying a U.S.-made assault rifle and ammunition, it said.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:30:09 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Ukraine says 180,000 consumers were left without power after Russian overnight attack</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/ukraine-says-180000-consumers-were-left-without-power-after-russian-overnight-2025-12-18/</link><description>KYIV, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Around 180,000 consumers were left without electricity supplies across five Ukrainian regions after a Russian attack overnight, Ukraine's acting energy minister Artem Nekrasov said on Thursday.

Nekrasov said on the Telegram messenger that the southern regions of Mykolaiv and Zaporizhzhia, the central regions of Cherkasy and Dnipropetrovsk, and the north-eastern region of Sumy were attacked during the night.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:30:27 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/P23JP6OIZJKTJD22X3HPIO7OAU.jpg?auth=7c13d555c2133fc4b9bd59ae01bd60fed0d473695f8b9e5e80b61c39a439b504&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Over 1,000 civilians killed in Sudan's Darfur when paramilitary group seized camp, UN says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/over-1000-civilians-killed-sudans-darfur-when-paramilitary-group-seized-camp-un-2025-12-18/</link><description>GENEVA, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Over 1,000 civilians were killed when a Sudanese paramilitary group took over a displacement camp in Sudan's Darfur region in April, including about a third who were summarily executed, according to a report by the U.N. Human Rights Office on Thursday.

"Such deliberate killing of civilians or persons hors de combat may constitute the war crime of murder,” said the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Turk in a statement accompanying the 18-page report.

The Zamzam camp in Sudan's western region of Darfur housed around half a million people displaced by the civil war and was taken over by Rapid Support Forces between April 11-13.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russia says it hopes Trump does not make 'a fatal mistake' on Venezuela</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/russia-says-it-hopes-trump-does-not-make-a-fatal-mistake-venezuela-2025-12-18/</link><description>MOSCOW, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Russia's foreign ministry said on Thursday that it hoped that U.S. President Donald Trump's administration did not make a fatal mistake over Venezuela and said that Moscow was concerned about U.S. decisions that threatened international navigation.

Trump on Tuesday ordered a "blockade" of all sanctioned oil tankers entering and leaving Venezuela as Washington tried to increase pressure on Nicolas Maduro's government.

There has been an effective embargo in place after the U.S. seized a sanctioned oil tanker off the coast of Venezuela last week, with loaded vessels carrying millions of barrels of oil staying in Venezuelan waters rather than risk seizure.

"We hope that the D. Trump administration, which is characterized by a rational and pragmatic approach, will not make a fatal mistake," Russia's foreign ministry said in a statement.

The ministry said that Venezuela was a friendly country to Russia, and that Moscow hoped the U.S. would not wade into a situation that would have "unpredictable consequences for the entire Western Hemisphere".

Russia quoted Simon Bolivar, a brilliant Venezuelan military tactician who liberated much of South America from centuries of Spanish rule, as saying that every nation had the right to choose its own rulers and that other countries should respect this.

Russia, the ministry said, wanted a normalisation of dialogue between Washington and Caracas, and reaffirmed Russia's "solidarity with the Venezuelan people in the face of the trials they are going through."

Russia supports "the Maduro government's course aimed at protecting the national interests and sovereignty of the Motherland."</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:53:22 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/3D7SB73DJVJVNK45276V6OLJNU.jpg?auth=0ca29ecc519bf203bbe07c17cd8cb747594042e51d320b970a76924689ae2efa&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Saudi, French and U.S. officials push Hezbollah disarmament plan</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-french-us-officials-push-hezbollah-disarmament-plan-2025-12-18/</link><description>PARIS/BEIRUT, Dec 18 (Reuters) - French, Saudi Arabian and American officials will hold talks with the head of the Lebanese army on Thursday in Paris aimed at finalising a roadmap to enable a mechanism for the disarmament of the Hezbollah group , diplomats said.

Israel and Lebanon agreed to a U.S.-brokered ceasefire in 2024, ending more than a year of fighting between Israel and Hezbollah that severely weakened the Iran-backed militants.

Since then, the sides have traded accusations over violations with Israel questioning the Lebanese army's efforts to disarm Hezbollah. Israeli warplanes have increasingly targeted Hezbollah in southern Lebanon and even in the capital.

With growing fear the ceasefire could unravel, the Paris meeting aims to create more robust conditions to identify, support and verify the disarmament process and dissuade Israel from escalation, four European and Lebanese diplomats and officials told Reuters.

With legislative elections due in Lebanon in 2026, there are fears political paralysis and party politics will further fuel instability and make President Joseph Aoun less likely to press disarmament, the diplomats and officials said.

"The situation is extremely precarious, full of contradictions and it won't take much to light the powder keg," said one senior official speaking on condition of anonymity.

"Aoun doesn't want to make the disarming process too public because he fears it will antagonise and provoke tensions with the Shi'ite community in the south of the country."

With the Lebanese army lacking capacity to disarm Hezbollah, the idea would be to reinforce the existing ceasefire mechanism with French, U.S. and possibly other military experts along with U.N. peacekeeping forces, the diplomats and officials said.

The parties hope to organise a conference at the start of next year to reinforce the Lebanese army as well as a separate conference to help reconstruction, most notably for the south.

As officials convened for the talks, multiple Israeli strikes hit towns in southern Lebanon and areas of the Bekaa Valley on Thursday, Lebanon’s state news agency NNA reported.

The Israeli military said it struck Hezbollah targets across several areas, including a military compound used for training, weapons storage and artillery launches, saying the activity violated understandings between Israel and Lebanon and posed a threat to Israel. It also said it struck a Hezbollah militant in the area of Taybeh in southern Lebanon.

Commenting on the attacks, parliament speaker and Hezbollah-allied Amal Movement leader Nabih Berri said the strikes were an "Israeli message" to the Paris conference, NNA added.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:53:33 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Turkey urges peaceful Syria-SDF talks, warns patience running out – foreign minister</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/turkey-urges-peaceful-syria-sdf-talks-warns-patience-running-out-foreign-2025-12-18/</link><description>ANKARA, Dec 18 (Reuters) - Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan said on Thursday that Turkey did not want to resort to military action again against Syria's Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), but warned that the patience of the actors involved was running out over what he described as delays in implementing an integration deal.

"We just hope that things go through dialogue, negotiations and peacefully. We don't want to see any need to resorting to military means again. But SDF should understand the patience of the relevant actors are running out," Fidan told an interview with TRT World.

"They should come to a place where their commitment to the agreement of 10th of March should be honoured. Everybody is expecting from them to honour that agreement without any delay and without any twisting because we don't want to see a deviation from this agreement," he added.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IR62FGQBGFOJXHYXYXLWRJG7OU.jpg?auth=faa000c5d8e06a1bb4f513e3760bd649c343e87b4fa7b48fe32f82b48f06423b&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item></channel></rss>