<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Reuters Feed</title><link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/reur/reuters</link><description>Scraped articles from Reuters</description><item><title>Israel and US launch strikes on Iran, targeting its leadership</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/israel-us-launch-strikes-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON/DUBAI/CAIRO, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran on Saturday, plunging the Middle East into a new conflict that President Donald Trump said would end a security threat to the United States and give Iranians a chance to topple their rulers.

The strikes put nearby oil-producing Gulf Arab countries on edge as fears of escalation in the region grew, and Israel said Tehran responded by launching missiles towards Israel.

The first wave of strikes in what the Pentagon named "OPERATION EPIC FURY" mainly targeted Iranian officials, a source familiar with the matter said.

An Israeli official said Iran's Supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, and President Masoud Pezeshkian were both targeted but the result of the strikes was not clear. A source with knowledge of the matter had earlier told Reuters that Khamenei was not in Tehran and had been transferred to a secure location.

An Iranian source close to the establishment said several senior commanders in Iran's Revolutionary Guards and political officials had been killed. Reuters could not independently confirm the report.

The renewed confrontation between Iran and its long-time foes further dimmed hopes of a diplomatic solution to Tehran's nuclear dispute with the West. A third round of indirect talks between the U.S. and Iran this week failed to provide a breakthrough that could avert a new war.

Iran's Revolutionary Guards said a first wave of retaliatory Iranian missile and drone attacks had been launched against Israel and that all U.S. bases and interests in the region were within Iran's reach, an Iranian official told Reuters.

Bahrain said the service center of the U.S. Fifth Fleet had been subjected to a missile attack. Video footage from witnesses in Bahrain showed a thick grey plume of smoke rising from near the small island state's coastline as sirens wailed.

At least half a dozen witnesses, including Reuters correspondents, heard loud booms in various parts of the United Arab Emirates capital Abu Dhabi, a major oil producer and close U.S. ally.

One witness told Reuters she heard five booms in rapid succession that caused windows in the house near Abu Dhabi's Corniche to vibrate. Other witnesses in the Al Dhafra and Bateen areas heard loud booms as well.

Fellow Gulf Arab state Qatar said it had downed all missiles targeting the country, the state news agency reported.

Explosions were heard near Iran's Kharg Island. Iran exports 90 percent of its crude oil via Kharg, for shipping through the narrow Strait of Hormuz.

Global airlines cancelled flights across the Middle East.

In a video message published on social media, Trump cited Washington's decades-long dispute with Iran, including the seizure of the 1979 U.S. embassy in Tehran, when students held 52 Americans hostage for 444 days, as well as a range of other attacks the U.S. has blamed on Iran since the 1979 Islamic revolution brought the clerics to power.

He urged Iranians to stay sheltered because "bombs will be dropping everywhere". But he also added: "When we are finished, take over your government. It will be yours to take. This will be probably your only chance for generations.”

The U.S. military initiated a series of strikes against targets in Iran, two U.S. officials told Reuters, speaking on condition of anonymity. The scope of the air and sea operations was not immediately clear. The campaign is expected to last for multiple days, said a U.S. official.

Iran was preparing a crushing retaliation, an Iranian official told Reuters.

“We are being killed by the regime and by Israel. We are the victims of this regime’s hostile policies,” said Maryam, 54, a housewife in Tehran, as she headed to northern Iran with her family.
Witnesses said people were rushing to banks to withdraw cash. Long queues formed at gas stations across cities. Many also worried about a potential internet blackout that would cut off communication with their families abroad.

Trump had built up a vast U.S. military presence in the region to try to force Tehran to make concessions in the nuclear talks. He said the U.S. had launched a "massive and ongoing" operation against the Islamic Republic, vowing to ensure Tehran will not obtain a nuclear weapon.

Iran's ballistic missile programme has been a significant sticking point in negotiations. Trump said Iran was developing long-range missiles that threaten the U.S.

"Our objective is to defend the American people by eliminating imminent threats from the Iranian regime," Trump said.

Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the joint U.S.-Israeli attack on Iran "will create the conditions for the brave Iranian people to take their destiny into their own hands."

"The time has come for all sections of the people in Iran ... to remove the yoke of tyranny ... and bring a free and peace-loving Iran," Netanyahu said in a statement.

The attack follows a 12-day air war in June between Israel and Iran and repeated U.S.-Israeli warnings that they would strike again if Iran pressed ahead with its nuclear and ballistic missile programmes.

Defence Minister Israel Katz said the strieks - launched against Muslim-majority Iran during Ramadan, the holy Muslim month of fasting observed from dawn to sunset - was a pre-emptive attack to remove threats to Israel.

An Israeli defence official said the operation had been planned for months in coordination with Washington, and that the launch date was decided weeks ago.

The Israeli military announced the closure of schools and workplaces, with exceptions for essential sectors, and a ban on public airspace. Israel closed its airspace to civilian flights.

The U.S. and Iran renewed negotiations in February to try to resolve the nuclear dispute.

Iran, which denies seeking atomic bombs, said it was prepared to discuss curbs on its nuclear programme in exchange for lifting sanctions but ruled out linking the issue to its missiles.

Last June, the U.S. joined an Israeli military campaign against Iranian nuclear installations, in the most direct American military action ever against the Islamic Republic.

Tehran retaliated then by launching missiles toward the U.S. Al Udeid air base in Qatar, the largest in the Middle East.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:16 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/F3RMO3NPSVOYFKIFRCMSNH4W7M.jpg?auth=acb7239537bb2a9e9d113e71c8b764c8f24498bed5673c2c6f7ec67c2ecd4740&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Airlines suspend Middle East flights after US, Israel strikes on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/airlines-suspend-middle-east-flights-after-us-israel-strikes-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>DUBAI, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Global airlines suspended flights across the Middle East on Saturday after the United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran, plunging the region into a renewed military confrontation.

Flight maps showed the airspace over Iran virtually empty as Israel said it struck Iran and the U.S. military initiated a series of strikes against targets in the country. Iran retaliated with a salvo of missiles.

The escalation dimmed hopes for a diplomatic solution to Tehran's nuclear dispute with the West and reignited conflict after weeks of U.S. military buildup in the region.

It marks the latest upheaval for air travel in the usually busy region amid escalating tensions in the Middle East. With Russian and Ukrainian airspace closed to most airlines due to years of war, the Middle East has become a more important route for flights between Europe and Asia.

Conflict zones are an increasing operational burden on airlines as aerial attacks raise worries about accidental or deliberate shoot-downs of commercial air traffic. Longer flight times also require more fuel, adding to their costs.

Israel, Iran, Iraq and Jordan closed their airspace following the attacks and a map of the region on Flightradar24 showed airplanes avoiding these areas.

A number of Qatar Airways flights departed on Saturday morning, circled over Kuwait or Saudi Arabia before returning to Qatari airspace and were circling off Doha, according to Flightradar24.

The Russian Ministry of Transport said on Saturday that Russian air carriers had suspended flights to Iran and Israel.

Germany's Lufthansa (LHAG.DE) , opens new tab said it was suspending flights to and from Dubai on Saturday and Sunday and halting temporarily the Tel Aviv, Beirut and Oman routes until March 7. Air France cancelled flights to and From Tel Aviv and Beirut.

Iberia also cancelled flights to Tel Aviv, while Wizz Air (WIZZ.L) , opens new tab suspended flights to and from Israel, Dubai, Abu Dhabi and Amman with immediate effect until the same date, it said.

Kuwait's aviation authority said it was halting all flights to Iran until further notice, according to the state news agency, while Oman Air said it had suspended all flights to Baghdad due to the regional developments.

The United Arab Emirates "partially and temporarily" closed its airspace as a precaution, its state news agency said.

"Due to the temporary closure of several airspace in the region on 28 February, some flydubai flights have been impacted," a spokesperson for the Emirati carrier said.

KLM, the Dutch arm of Air France-KLM (AIRF.PA) , opens new tab , has brought forward the suspension of its Amsterdam–Tel Aviv service, cancelling the flight scheduled for Saturday after strikes in Iran, a spokesperson said.

The airline had announced on Wednesday that flights would be halted from Sunday, March 1. Only one flight to Tel Aviv had been scheduled for Saturday.

Virgin Atlantic said it had decided to temporarily avoid Iraqi airspace, resulting in some re-routing of its flights. Qatar Airways said it had halted air traffic temporarily as a precaution.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:18 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/JN6CBRPC4RIRXH2RAQHWDMS6D4.jpg?auth=7f6f38b34445b4754b228372470e49d0066120ab8e3590cf73050300884f5ec2&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Pakistan, Afghan Taliban forces clash as diplomatic efforts intensify</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/pakistan-afghan-taliban-forces-clash-diplomatic-efforts-intensify-2026-02-28/</link><description>KABUL, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Fighting between Pakistan and Afghanistan's Taliban military entered its third day on Saturday, following overnight clashes as the international community expressed increasing concern about the conflict and called for urgent talks.

Pakistan's strikes on Friday hit Taliban military installations and posts, including in Kabul and Kandahar, in one of the deepest Pakistani incursions into its western neighbour in years, officials said.

Islamabad accuses the Taliban of harbouring Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) militants, who it claims are waging an insurgency inside Pakistan, a charge the Taliban denies.

Pakistan described its actions as a response to cross-border assaults, while Kabul denounced them as a breach of its sovereignty, saying it remained open to dialogue but warned any wider conflict would result in serious consequences.

The fighting has raised the risk of a protracted conflict along the rugged 2,600-km (1,615-mile) frontier.

Diplomatic efforts gathered pace late on Friday as Afghanistan said its foreign minister, Amir Khan Muttaqi, spoke by telephone with Saudi Arabia's Prince Faisal bin Farhan about reducing tensions and keeping diplomatic channels open.

The European Union called for both sides to de-escalate and engage in dialogue, while the United Nations urged an immediate end to hostilities.

Russia urged both sides to halt the clashes and return to talks, while China said it was deeply concerned and ready to help ease tensions.

The United States supports Pakistan's right to defend itself against attacks by the Taliban, a State Department spokesperson said.

A U.S. official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Washington did not view Pakistan as the aggressor in the latest escalation and that Islamabad was under pressure to address its security challenges, adding Washington hoped the situation would not escalate further.

Exchanges of fire continued along the border overnight.

Pakistani security sources said an operation dubbed "Ghazab Lil Haq" was ongoing and that Pakistani forces had destroyed multiple Taliban posts and camps in several sectors. Reuters could not independently verify the claims.

Both sides have reported heavy losses with conflicting tolls that Reuters could not verify. Pakistan said 12 of its soldiers and 274 Taliban were killed while the Taliban said 13 of its fighters and 55 Pakistani soldiers died.

Taliban deputy spokesman Hamdullah Fitrat said 19 civilians were killed and 26 wounded in Khost and Paktika. Reuters could not verify the claim.

Pakistan's Defence Minister Khawaja Muhammad Asif said "our cup of patience has overflowed" and described the fighting as "open war", warning that Pakistan would respond to further attacks.

Taliban Interior Minister Sirajuddin Haqqani said in a speech in Khost province that the conflict "will be very costly," and that Afghan forces had not deployed broadly beyond those already engaged.

He said the Taliban had defeated "the world, not through technology, but through unity and solidarity," and through "great patience and perseverance," rather than superior military power.

Pakistan's military capabilities far exceed those of Afghanistan, with a standing army of hundreds of thousands and a modern air force.

In stark contrast, the Taliban lacks a conventional air force and relies largely on light weaponry and ground forces.

However, the Islamist group is battle-hardened after two decades of insurgency against U.S.-led forces before returning to power in 2021.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:19 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/GDL6TRGHRJJMZH67BZ452JTLBU.jpg?auth=1f66069e1d0611a99047f5cf4fa849785c913985c8fdbab9fc763e17ed791764&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Satellite images show more aircraft at Saudi airbase used by US forces</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/satellite-images-show-more-aircraft-saudi-airbase-used-by-us-forces-2026-02-27/</link><description>Feb 27 (Reuters) - Satellite images showed a rise in the number of military support aircraft including refuelling tankers at a Saudi airbase used by the U.S. military during a four-day period in February, as Washington built forces in the region amid tensions with Iran.

Saudi Arabia, a longstanding U.S. ally, told Iran last month it would not allow its airspace or territory to be used for military actions against Tehran, which held indirect negotiations with Washington on Thursday over its nuclear programme.

In a high-resolution satellite image taken on February 21, at least 43 aircraft were visible at Saudi Arabia's Prince Sultan Airbase - which has hosted U.S. forces for decades - compared with 27 aircraft visible in a February 17 image.

The number dropped to 38 in a February 25 image.

The aircraft in the February 21 image included 13 Boeing KC-135 Stratotankers and six Boeing E-3 Sentry aircraft known as AWACS, among a total of 29 large, swept-wing aircraft parked at the base, William Goodhind, a forensic imagery analyst with Contested Ground, told Reuters.

In the February 17, medium-resolution image, 11 large, swept-wing aircraft were visible, according to a Reuters tally.

Asked for comment, the Pentagon said it had "nothing to provide". The U.S. military does not usually comment on force movements.

The Saudi government's media office did not immediately respond to a request for comment.

Oman, which is mediating between the United States and Iran, said the sides made progress in talks on Thursday, though there was no sign of a breakthrough that could avert potential U.S. strikes.

Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Albusaidi said on Thursday the sides plan to resume negotiations soon after consultations in their countries' capitals, with technical-level discussions scheduled to take place next week in Vienna.

U.S. President Donald Trump said on February 19 that Iran must make a deal in 10 to 15 days, warning that "really bad things" would otherwise happen.

A comparison of satellite imagery in early February with those taken in January also showed a build-up of aircraft and other military equipment across the region.

Recent satellite images have also shown Iran repairing and fortifying sites, including a sensitive military site reportedly bombed by Israel in 2024.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:21 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/KZ5YCAIGM5K25KUJDXZNLNGIQY.jpg?auth=a375a627cd3832b9acd627a985b4f04443030276a9538b062f337f7c2063977c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US-Iran talks end with no deal but potential signs of progress</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/us-iran-nuclear-talks-resume-geneva-against-backdrop-military-threat-2026-02-26/</link><description>GENEVA, Feb 26 (Reuters) - (This Feb 26 story has been corrected to fix the day of the week to Thursday, not Tuesday, in paragraph 5)

The United States and Iran made progress in talks over Tehran's nuclear program on Thursday, mediator Oman said, but hours of negotiation ended with no sign of a breakthrough that could avert potential U.S. strikes amid a massive military buildup.

The two sides plan to resume negotiations soon after consultations in their countries' capitals, with technical-level discussions scheduled to take place next week in Vienna, Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Albusaidi said in a post on X after the day's meetings in Switzerland.

Badr Albusaidi will hold talks with U.S. Vice President JD Vance and other U.S. officials in Washington on Friday, MS NOW reported late on Thursday. Neither the White House nor Oman's embassy in Washington immediately responded to requests for comment.

Any substantial move toward an elusive agreement between longtime foes Washington and Tehran could reduce the imminent prospects for U.S President Donald Trump to carry out a threatened attack on Iran that many fear could escalate into a wider war.

But Thursday's indirect talks wrapped up without a deal, still leaving the region on edge.

The Omani minister's upbeat assessment followed indirect talks between Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araqchi and U.S. envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner in Geneva, with one session in the morning and the second in the afternoon.

"We have finished the day after significant progress in the negotiation between the United States and Iran," Badr Albusaidi said.

But with many analysts seeing the latest diplomacy as the last chance before Trump could decide to go to war, Badr Albusaidi provided no details and stopped short of saying the two sides had overcome their biggest stumbling blocks to a deal.

Describing the talks as some of the most serious that Iran has had with the U.S., Araqchi told Iranian state television: "We reached agreement on some issues, and there are differences regarding some other issues."

“It was decided that the next round of negotiations will take place soon, in less than a week," he said. The Iranians, he added, had clearly expressed their demand for lifting of U.S. sanctions, which Washington has long insisted will only come after deep concessions from Tehran.

There was no immediate comment from the U.S. negotiating team on the outcome of the talks. But Axios quoted a senior U.S. official as saying the Geneva negotiations were “positive.”

The discussions about the decades-long dispute over Iran's nuclear work come as fears grow of a Middle East conflagration. Trump has repeatedly threatened action if there is no deal, and the U.S. military has amassed its forces in waters near the Islamic Republic.

A senior Iranian official told Reuters earlier on Thursday that the U.S. and Iran could reach a framework for a deal if Washington separated "nuclear and non-nuclear issues."

The Trump administration has insisted that Iran's ballistic missile program and its support for armed groups in the region must be part of the negotiations.

After the morning session, Badr Albusaidi said the two sides had exchanged "creative and positive ideas".

But a senior Iranian official said at the time that some gaps still had to be narrowed.

Washington, which believes Tehran seeks the ability to build a nuclear bomb, wants Iran to give up all uranium enrichment, a process that makes fuel for atomic power plants but that can also yield material for a warhead.

Iran has long denied wanting a bomb and said earlier on Thursday it would show flexibility at the talks. Reuters reported on Sunday that Tehran was offering undefined new concessions in return for removal of sanctions and recognition of its right to enrich uranium.

U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio said on Wednesday that Iran's refusal to discuss its ballistic missile program was a "big problem" which would have to be addressed eventually.

The missiles were "designed solely to strike America" and pose a threat to regional stability, he said, but offered no proof to back the claim that U.S. territory could be targeted.

Trump said on February 19 that Iran must make a deal in 10 to 15 days, warning that "really bad things" would otherwise happen.

He briefly laid out his case for a possible attack on Iran in his State of the Union speech on Tuesday, underlining that while he preferred a diplomatic solution, he would not allow Tehran to obtain a nuclear weapon.

In June, the U.S. joined Israel in hitting Iranian nuclear sites and has been ramping up the pressure on Tehran again since January, when Trump threatened to intervene over its crushing of nationwide protests with thousands killed.

Since then, Trump has deployed fighter jets and aircraft carrier strike groups in the region.

Iran responded to last summer's strikes by firing fusillades of missiles at Israel and has threatened to retaliate fiercely if attacked again, raising fears of a wider regional conflict that has alarmed Gulf oil producers.

Within Iran, Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei faces the gravest crisis of his 36-year tenure, with an economy buckling under tightened sanctions and renewed protests following the major unrest and crackdown in January.

President Masoud Pezeshkian said on Thursday that Khamenei has banned weapons of mass destruction, which "clearly means Tehran won't develop nuclear weapons," reiterating a religious decree issued in the early 2000s.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:23 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/KZKPAICGORPOVE2JFMC5M7MGFE.jpg?auth=6820be33a0d74dbd317755287faefa3a14015cb56b38b1ccbd781ac5ff9efe0f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Trump says of Iran: 'Sometimes you have to use force'</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/trump-says-more-iran-talks-expected-friday-2026-02-27/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 27 (Reuters) - U.S. President Donald Trump expressed disappointment on Friday about U.S. negotiations with Iran over its nuclear program and warned that "sometimes you have to use force," amid a massive military presence in the region that could presage strikes on the Islamic Republic.

Trump has increased diplomatic and military pressure on Iran in the weeks since an Iranian crackdown on protesters, attempting to force the country's rulers to forswear nuclear weapons and other activities Washington sees as destabilizing.

After the latest round of talks on Thursday in Geneva ended without a deal, Trump's patience appeared to be wearing thin, although he said he had not made a final decision on the use of force.

"They don't want to say the key words, 'We're not going to have a nuclear weapon,'" Trump said on Friday before an event in Corpus Christi, Texas. "So I'm not happy with the negotiation."

Iran denies it is seeking to develop nuclear weapons and wants any accord to include the lifting of U.S. sanctions against it.

'PEACE DEAL WITHIN REACH': ALBUSAIDI

Trump spoke a day after negotiations between U.S. envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner and Iranian officials in Geneva ended without news of a deal, although Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Albusaidi, who was a mediator, said the talks made significant progress.

Albusaidi told CBS earlier on Friday, before Trump's latest remarks, that a "peace deal is within our reach ... if we just allow diplomacy the space it needs to get there."

Iran has agreed in principle that it would never have nuclear material that could be used to create a weapon, Albusaidi said, adding that "if we can capture that and build on it, I think a deal is within our reach."

A big U.S. military force, including two aircraft carrier groups, is in the region waiting on Trump's order.

While Trump's timing for a final decision is unclear, the State Department said Secretary of State Marco Rubio is to hold talks in Israel with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday and Monday.

The United States joined Israel’s bombing campaign against Iran in June, striking major nuclear facilities.

Asked about the potential for use of force, Trump said the United States has the greatest military in the world.

"I'd love not to use it, but sometimes you have to," he said.

Trump said more discussions on Iran would take place later in the day.

He did not specify with whom, but Oman, which has been acting as a mediator between the two countries, sent its foreign minister to Washington on Friday for discussions on the issue with U.S. Vice President JD Vance, according to a source familiar with the matter.

Top U.S. defense officials were at the White House on Thursday for talks.

U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio said in a statement on Friday that the State Department had designated Iran as a “State Sponsor of Wrongful Detention.”

Rubio said for decades Iran has wrongfully detained Americans and citizens of other nations “to use as political leverage against other states,” adding that the U.S. could consider additional measures, including a potential “geographic travel restriction on the use of U.S. passports to, through, or from Iran.”

Trump planned events in Corpus Christi later on Friday and then was to fly to Palm Beach, Florida, for the weekend at his Mar-a-Lago club.

A source briefed on the internal White House deliberations told Reuters that Trump is “very clear-eyed on all the options before him.”

There is a recognition internally that taking on Iran would be more difficult than the U.S. capture of Venezuelan leader Nicolas Maduro, and there was also internal pessimism as to whether negotiations will bear fruit, the source said.

"Nobody is super optimistic about the negotiations," the source said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:25 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/DVX7CLH4GJIIZLECCB5FFBKVEE.jpg?auth=bd7f2913ef8cc8469df900bda98e9ca0f918af1c0760a17c3412dd5c89167441&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Argentina Senate approves Milei-backed labor reform</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/argentina-senate-approves-milei-backed-labor-reform-2026-02-28/</link><description>BUENOS AIRES, Feb 27 - Argentina’s Senate on Friday approved a labor reform backed by President Javier Milei, giving it final clearance to become law and landing the libertarian leader one of his most significant legislative wins.

Milei's administration argues the reform, which passed with 42 votes in favor, 28 against, and two abstentions, will spur investment and create formal jobs, while labor unions contend it weakens worker protections, including the right to strike.

The reform is expected to bolster investor confidence in Milei’s market-driven reforms.

Passage of the bill is seen by analysts as a signal that Milei has the political backing to advance his broader free‑market agenda.

Since taking office, Milei has stabilized the exchange rate and sharply cooled inflation, bringing monthly price increases down from double digits to 2.9% in January, gaining accolades from the International Monetary Fund.

One of the bill's most contentious provisions establishes an employer-financed severance fund consisting of contributions currently earmarked for the national pension system. The change could make it easier for companies to lay off workers and opposition lawmakers say the fund would impact the pension system's resources.

The reform also relaxes hiring rules, changes the vacation system, allows the standard workday to be extended from eight to 12 hours, and permits salaries to be paid in foreign currency.

Unions, which have mounted protests including a nationwide strike, object to new limits on the right to strike that require essential services to maintain minimum operations during work stoppages.

The labor reform is one of several legislative priorities for Milei’s administration. Lawmakers are also advancing changes to the law protecting Andean glaciers, a move the government says will unlock mining investment and which environmental groups strongly oppose.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:27 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/VMQVP77KP5LEHFW74TAYIYA76M.jpg?auth=8e8092d908f187e4ad2ca5d7c1a0335b59a4320a857e9d1ae4253e645974194f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Bolivian military plane crash death toll rises to 20, AFP reports</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/bolivian-military-plane-crashes-el-alto-near-la-paz-2026-02-27/</link><description>LA PAZ, Feb 27 (Reuters) - The death toll has risen to 20 in the crash on Friday evening of a Bolivian Air Force Hercules aircraft during bad weather in the city of El Alto, near Bolivia's capital La Paz, AFP reported citing police.

The plane was carrying new banknotes from the country's central bank.

The military aircraft had departed from the city of Santa Cruz and crashed after landing and skidding off the runway onto a neighboring avenue, according to local authorities.

Social media footage showed chaotic scenes of people flocking to the scene of the crash, appearing to pick up money that lay strewn on the ground following the accident. Local authorities on the scene were warding off people using water hoses and tear gas. Reuters was unable to identify the images.

Bolivia's central bank was set to address reporters later on Friday evening.

The El Alto International Airport was closed temporarily following the crash, national airline Boliviana de Aviacion said in a statement, adding the aircraft involved in the accident did not belong to its fleet.

Video broadcast on local media showed the aircraft was severely damaged, as were a number of vehicles along the avenue where the crash took place.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:28 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Bill Clinton to lawmakers investigating Epstein: 'I saw nothing'</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/bill-clinton-give-private-testimony-congress-about-epstein-2026-02-27/</link><description>Feb 27 (Reuters) - Bill Clinton told lawmakers on Friday that he "saw nothing that gave me pause" when he spent time with Jeffrey Epstein, as the former president gave closed-door testimony about his relationship with the late sex offender.

Clinton's closed-door appearance before the House of Representatives Oversight Committee marked the first time a current or former president has been compelled to testify before Congress.

Democrats on the panel said President Donald Trump should be subpoenaed as well, but the committee's Republican chairman, James Comer said that was not going to happen.

Both men socialized with Epstein before his 2008 conviction of soliciting prostitution from a minor. Both have repeatedly said they did not see any evidence of sex trafficking, and neither have been accused by authorities of criminal activity related to the late financier, who entertained a long list of business and financial leaders at his lavish residences in New York, Florida and the Caribbean.

In his testimony, Clinton told the committee that he would not have flown on the late financier's plane if he had known about his alleged sex trafficking of underage girls, and would have reported him if he did.

"We are only here because he hid it from everyone so well for so long," Clinton said, speaking near his main residence in Chappaqua, New York.

Clinton flew on Epstein's plane several times in the early 2000s after he left office, and a tranche of millions of documents released by the Justice Department includes photos of Clinton with women whose faces are redacted.

"I saw nothing, and I did nothing wrong," Clinton said.

Comer described the hearing as cordial and said Clinton was cooperative. "He's a charming individual, obviously," he said.

Clinton said the committee should not have subpoenaed his wife, former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, who told the panel on Thursday that she did not remember ever meeting Epstein and had nothing to share about his sex crimes.

She said she was also asked about UFOs and a 2016-era conspiracy theory during the seven-hour session.

Comer said some of Hillary Clinton's answers had been inconsistent and would be examined for possible perjury.

He did not rule out the possibility of subpoenaing Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick, who visited Epstein's Caribbean island after his 2008 conviction. "Stay tuned on that," he said.

Democrats said the investigation would not be credible if it does not examine Trump's role.

"President Clinton's presence here today under oath highlights the Donald Trump-sized gaping hole in Chairman Comer's investigation," said Democratic Representative James Walkinshaw of Virginia.

Democrats are also accusing Trump's Justice Department of withholding records of a woman who accused Trump of sexually abusing her when she was a minor. The Justice Department has said it is looking at the material and will publish it if appropriate, and has also warned that the material includes unfounded accusations about Trump.

Trump's name appears frequently in the Epstein files. He socialized extensively with Epstein in the 1990s and 2000s and says he broke off ties before Epstein's 2008 conviction. Authorities have not accused him of criminal wrongdoing in connection with Epstein, but the association has dogged him for decades.

At the White House, Trump expressed sympathy for Clinton, a Democrat.

"I don't like seeing him deposed," Trump said. "But they certainly went after me more than that."

The Clintons agreed to testify near their home in Chappaqua after the House threatened to hold them in contempt of Congress for refusing to cooperate. Some Democrats supported the move.

Both Clintons accuse Republicans of conducting a partisan exercise designed to protect Trump from scrutiny, noting that others in the inquiry were allowed to submit written statements rather than testify in person.

Epstein died in jail in 2019 while facing federal sex-trafficking crimes. His death was ruled a suicide.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:30 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/WLMVHWMY4ZNF7FXHFOPFGUQBUU.jpg?auth=c5c66c42123d5981f3ff65d2e772565d9c19c2275236da9dc306ccc694f90ab7&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Global reaction to Israeli, US attacks on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/global-reaction-israeli-us-attacks-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israel and the United States launched strikes on Iran on Saturday, plunging the Middle East into a renewed military confrontation as President Donald Trump vowed to destroy Tehran's missile arsenal and prevent it from developing a nuclear weapon.

Below is international reaction to the attacks:

"The peacemaker once again showed his face," Medvedev, a former Russian president, said. "All negotiations with Iran are a cover operation. No one doubted it. No one really wanted to negotiate anything."

"The question is who has more patience to wait for the inglorious end of their enemy. The USA is only 249 years old. The Persian Empire was founded more than 2,500 years ago. Let's see in 100 years…"

LEBANESE PRIME MINISTER NAWAF SALAM

"I reiterate that we will not accept anyone dragging the country into adventures that threaten its security and unity."

"The attack is described by Israel as a preventive strike, but it is not in line with international law. Preventive attacks require an immediately imminent threat."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:34 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EBFCGMUG5VPQTKL4AQ4BWKE6ZE.jpg?auth=42cc0b9efcbb82efb670a9e93de0bc3a2909d3e414869b907cb7a3cc58cbb6f3&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Airlines cancel flights after US, Israel strikes on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/airlines-cancel-flights-after-us-israel-strikes-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Global airlines cancelled flights across the Middle East on Saturday after the United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran, plunging the region into a new conflict.

Airspace over Iran and Iraq was empty on Saturday morning, maps by flight-tracking service Flightradar24 showed.

Below is the latest on flights listed by airline in alphabetical order:

Air France (AIRF.PA) , opens new tab cancelled flights  to and from Tel Aviv in Israel and Beirut in Lebanon for Saturday.

KLM brought forward the suspension of its Amsterdam–Tel Aviv service, cancelling the flight scheduled for Saturday. The Dutch arm of Air France‑KLM had announced on Wednesday that flights would be halted from Sunday, but has now advanced that date.

Only one flight to Tel Aviv had been scheduled for Saturday.

The airline said it was monitoring regional updates.

Japan Airlines (9201.T) , opens new tab cancelled a flight on Saturday from Tokyo Haneda to Doha as well as a return flight on March 1, Nikkei said.

The German airline (LHAG.DE) , opens new tab suspended flights to and from Tel Aviv in Israel, Beirut in Lebanon, and Oman until March 7 and flights to and from Dubai on Saturday and Sunday.

They also said they would not add Israeli, Lebanese, Jordanian, Iraqi and Iranian airspace until March 7.

Virgin Atlantic said it will temporarily avoid Iraqi airspace, resulting in some pre-planned rerouting of its flights and cancelled its VS400 service from London Heathrow to Dubai on Saturday.

The airline (WIZZ.L) , opens new tab halted flights to and from Israel, Dubai, Abu Dhabi and Amman with immediate effect until March 7.

It added that operational decisions would continue to be reviewed, and the flight schedule could be adjusted as the situation evolves.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:36 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/DJPRRSSV25JFPDVZ4BRAGVUBPQ.jpg?auth=fe17d834e3e5beff691fdb05ac02bcf3cf7cb36c1b08796e8ba268ebcf174934&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>North Korean leader presents new sniper rifles to party officials</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/north-korean-leader-presents-new-sniper-rifles-party-officials-2026-02-28/</link><description>SEOUL, Feb 28 (Reuters) - North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has presented new sniper rifles as ceremonial gifts to party and military officials, calling them a "wonderful weapon" and a sign of his trust, state media KCNA news agency said on Saturday.

KCNA reported Kim met leading cadres and commanding officers at the headquarters of the Workers' Party of Korea on Friday and handed each a new-generation rifle developed by the country's Academy of Defence Science.

"As was already made public, this new-generation sniper's rifle our Academy of Defence Science developed and produced is really a wonderful weapon,” Kim was quoted as saying.

The gifts were presented to mark the Ninth Congress of the party.

Recipients included members of the party's Central Military Commission, senior commanders of the Korean People's Army and guard units, as well as Kim's sister Kim Yo Jong, whom KCNA for the first time identified as director of the General Affairs Department of the party's Central Committee.

Photographs published by KCNA showed Kim's teenage daughter, known as Ju Ae, attending the gift ceremony and aiming a rifle at a firing range.

Ju Ae, believed to be in her early teens, has been increasingly prominent in state media, accompanying her father on field guidance including inspections of weapons projects amid speculation by analysts that she is being groomed as the country's fourth-generation leader.

South Korea's National Intelligence Agency (NIS) believes the public role indicates she has started to provide policy input and that she is being treated as the de facto second-highest leader .

KCNA also released a photograph of Kim Yo Jong holding a rifle alongside Hyon Song Wol, an aide to the North Korean leader who is known to be close to his wife.

North Korea wrapped up its week-long Ninth Congress with a military parade.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:37 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/MBOICKPUNFPL5MTGH4TOT6ZXKM.jpg?auth=8e5e6152e4e2e23983048a28203e18aa6aace7f85693d601cc37efe6d7408c89&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Lebanon's prime minister warns against dragging country into 'adventures'</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/lebanons-prime-minister-warns-against-dragging-country-into-adventures-2026-02-28/</link><description>BEIRUT, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Lebanese Prime Minister Nawaf Salam on Saturday said he would not accept anyone dragging "the country into adventures that threaten its security and unity", in an indirect message to the Iran-backed Lebanese armed group Hezbollah.

In a statement released after Israel and the United States launched strikes on Iran , Salam noted the "serious developments" in the region and called on "all Lebanese to act with wisdom and patriotism, placing Lebanon and the Lebanese people’s interests above any other consideration".

Hezbollah has fought numerous conflicts with Israel since it was established by Iran's Revolutionary Guards in 1982.

Reuters reported on Tuesday that Israel had warned Lebanon that it would strike the country hard, targeting civilian infrastructure including the airport, in the event that Hezbollah gets involved in any U.S.-Iran war.

"I reiterate that we will not accept anyone dragging the country into adventures that threaten its security and unity," Salam said in a statement sent to Reuters.

Israel dealt heavy blows to Hezbollah during a war in 2024, killing its leader Hassan Nasrallah along with thousands of its fighters and destroying much of its arsenal.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:39 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/XHPIL3CLQFNS7L7WROKI5BU4RA.jpg?auth=1c1584d49d8308fd331adb1a6e09c970a25fca0d433987c0aa401f3409c7c08f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Tram derails in central Milan leaving two dead, 40 injured</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/tram-derails-central-milan-least-one-dead-2026-02-27/</link><description>MILAN, Feb 27 (Reuters) - Two people were killed and around 40 injured when a tram derailed in central Milan on Friday, a spokesperson for local firefighters said.

The tram, one of the newest models in operation in Milan, came off the tracks in Vittorio Veneto street, close to the city's Central Station, crashing into the window of a shop.

Local emergency services said 13 ambulances were on the scene.

Civil protection teams set up a tent to assist the injured, according to a Reuters eyewitness.

The Milan transport company, ATM, said in a statement it was "deeply shocked", expressed its sympathy to those affected and said it was working with authorities to try to understand the cause.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:41 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EOFENWF2JZI5NI7NWALG2NVXMY.jpg?auth=377bada9ab9e1f8784ecce0d27f132401d4a23e3ebe002d2842619bdd3a6426f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Trump warns some Americans may die amid US strikes in Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/trump-says-us-carrying-out-major-combat-operations-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - U.S. President Donald Trump said on Saturday that the United States had begun "major combat operations" in Iran , warning that there may be U.S. casualties.

The strikes , which Trump said were aimed at destroying Iranian missiles and annihilating its navy, follow repeated U.S.-Israeli warnings that they would strike Iran again if it pressed ahead with its nuclear and ballistic missile programs.

"My administration has taken every possible step to minimise the risk to U.S. personnel in the region. Even so, and I do not make this statement lightly, the Iranian regime seeks to kill," Trump said in a video shared on Truth Social.

"The lives of courageous American heroes may be lost and we may have casualties that often happens in war, but we're doing this, not for now. We're doing this for the future, and it is a noble mission."

The U.S. military has named the operation "EPIC FURY," the Pentagon said on X.

This is the second time the U.S. has carried out strikes on Iran since Trump returned to the White House last year. The first was in June when Washington carried out a series of attacks on Iranian nuclear sites.

Saturday's strikes, unlike the first, are expected to be carried out over several days, a U.S. official told Reuters.

Tehran is preparing for retaliation, with the response set to be crushing, an Iranian official told Reuters.

The Israeli military said that Tehran had launched missiles towards Israel in response.

In his message, Trump told the members of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard, Iran's armed forces, to lay down their weapons, promising that they would be granted immunity.

The other option, according to Trump, is "certain death."

Washington and Tehran held a series of talks in recent weeks about Iran's nuclear ambitions. The most recent one was held on Thursday with no deal.

"Iran refused, just as it has for decades and decades. They rejected every opportunity to renounce their nuclear ambitions, and we can't take it anymore," Trump said.

The president first floated the idea of strikes on Iran in January amid two-week-long nationwide protests, during which thousands of people were killed by authorities.

He warned that the U.S. would come to the rescue of protesters if Iranian officials were to shoot and kill them. Trump later encouraged the protesters to continue protesting, saying that help was on the way .

Trump mentioned the killing of protesters during his statement on the strikes, telling Iranians to take cover because bombs will drop "everywhere."

"When we are finished, take over your government. It will be yours to take. This will be probably your only chance for generations," he said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:43 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/KBUEI6OGGZPAJIFHDGKAH3RQEQ.jpg?auth=6bb57e6f2450a8e7246d8d371029a0f6edda72af1633ff08e54304337724004b&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russia weighs halt to peace talks unless Ukraine cedes territory, Bloomberg News reports</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-weighs-halt-peace-talks-unless-ukraine-cedes-territory-bloomberg-news-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Russian officials increasingly see little reason to continue U.S.-led peace talks with Ukraine unless Kyiv signals it is prepared to give up territory as part of a settlement, Bloomberg News reported on Saturday, citing people familiar with the matter.

Talks scheduled for next week will be critical to determining whether the sides can move towards an agreement to end the war, the report said.

Reuters could not immediately verify the report.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:45 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/TXLB6J222VJALHMNRSPGP33D6E.jpg?auth=9eb38c524ee7e1c4186e9bc89f7e5aea536debc87e4dd984cdc99689863c9910&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US and Israel launch "pre-emptive" attack against Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-says-it-launched-pre-emptive-attack-against-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israel said it launched a pre-emptive attack against Iran on Saturday, pushing the Middle East into a renewed military confrontation and further dimming hopes for a diplomatic solution to Tehran's long-running nuclear dispute with the West.

The New York Times, citing a U.S. official, reported that U.S. strikes on Iran were underway. A source told Reuters that Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, was not in Tehran and had been transferred to a secure location.

The attack, coming after Israel and Iran engaged in a 12-day air war in June, follows repeated U.S.-Israeli warnings that they would strike again if Iran pressed ahead with its nuclear and ballistic missile programmes.

"The State of Israel launched a pre-emptive attack against Iran to remove threats to the State of Israel," Defence Minister Israel Katz said.

An Israeli defence official said the operation had been planned for months in coordination with Washington, and that the launch date was decided weeks ago.

Explosions were heard in Tehran on Saturday, Iranian media reported, and sirens sounded across Israel around 08:15 local time in what the military said was a proactive alert to prepare the public for the possibility of an incoming missile strike.

The Israeli military announced the closure of schools and workplaces, with exceptions for essential sectors, and a ban on public airspace. Israel closed its airspace to civilian flights, and the airports authority asked the public not to go to any of the country's airports.

The U.S. and Iran renewed negotiations in February in a bid to resolve the decades-long dispute through diplomacy and avert the threat of a military confrontation that could destabilise the region.

Israel, however, insisted that any U.S. deal with Iran must include the dismantling of Tehran's nuclear infrastructure, not just stopping the enrichment process, and lobbied Washington to include restrictions on Iran's missile programme in the talks.

Iran said it was prepared to discuss curbs on its nuclear programme in exchange for lifting sanctions but ruled out linking the issue to missiles.

Tehran also said it would defend itself against any attack.

It warned neighbouring countries hosting U.S. troops that it would retaliate against American bases if Washington struck Iran.

In June, the U.S. joined an Israeli military campaign against Iranian nuclear installations, in the most direct American military action ever against the Islamic Republic.

Tehran retaliated then by launching missiles toward the U.S. Al Udeid air base in Qatar, the largest in the Middle East.

Western powers have warned that Iran's ballistic missile project threatens regional stability and could deliver nuclear weapons if developed. Tehran denies seeking atomic bombs.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:46 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/KJXDOGBT6NP5NPMTU6APLMRM34.jpg?auth=bee7a5338d5896ef1e65d9d0b8ca55e308d4adb05254bc9718e0de37c3b9d96a&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Israel's operation against Iran was coordinated with US, Israeli official says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-operation-against-iran-was-coordinated-with-us-israeli-official-says-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - The Israeli operation against Iran on Saturday was coordinated with the U.S., an Israeli defence official told Reuters.

The operation was planned for months and the launch date was decided weeks ago, the official added.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:48 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/H4HKTHIEMFLRHNCU22O4YQ6IQM.jpg?auth=cb63ccb655326adb65eb0e0907ba486e8c83ec0808e65623fb4d26342d7e3764&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Israel has launched preventative attack against Iran, defence minister says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-has-launched-preventative-attack-against-iran-defence-minister-says-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israel has launched a preventative missile attack against Iran, the Israeli defence minister said on Saturday.

Israel’s military on Saturday said it had protectively sounded air raid sirens in areas across the country “to prepare the public for the possibility of missiles being launched toward Israel” in retaliation.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:50 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Cuba says attacking speedboat had nearly 13,000 rounds of ammunition</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/cuba-says-attacking-speedboat-had-nearly-13000-rounds-ammunition-2026-02-28/</link><description>HAVANA, Feb 27 (Reuters) - A commando of Cuban exiles who intended to infiltrate Cuba on a speedboat was armed with nearly 13,000 rounds of ammunition, 13 rifles and 11 pistols, Cuban officials said on Friday, providing new details about Wednesday's deadly exchange of gunfire at sea.

The government in Havana has said 10 Cuban nationals coming from the United States entered Cuban waters and opened fire on a border guard vessel, leading Cuban forces to return fire killing four and wounding six others, who were taken into custody.

In an attempt to dispel doubts about its account to date, senior Cuban Interior Ministry officers displayed the captured armaments from the studio on a special television program, including bins full of at least some of the 12,846 recovered rounds.

They also showed pictures of the vessels, each peppered with bullet holes from the firefight they said took place at a range of 20 meters (66 feet).

The confrontation took place at a fraught moment in U.S.-Cuban relations, with U.S. President Donald Trump pressuring the island by imposing a virtual oil blockade after capturing and ousting Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, a crucial Cuban ally, on January 3.

Cuba has identified the assailants as Cuban exiles, some of whom had been previously placed on a list of accused terrorists, who came from the United States with the intent to sow chaos and attack military units on the Communist-ruled island.

"The intent of this group is to infiltrate, to promote public disorder. To incite the people to unite. To carry out something violent. Attack military units in order to incite social unrest and to unite the people in order to steal the revolution. That has been duly proven," said Colonel Victor Alvarez of the Interior Ministry.

U.S. politicians have expressed skepticism over Cuba's version of events. Secretary of State Marco Rubio on Wednesday said his government would independently investigate, adding that it was not a U.S. operation and that no U.S. government personnel were involved.

Cuban officers said the infiltrators set out from Marathon in the Florida Keys on two vessels but ditched one at some point due to technical difficulties. They united on one speedboat, which a U.S. official said was reported stolen in Florida.

Cuba said it recovered a drone, radios, knives, a portable power plant, bolt cutters and other materiel. They also found emblems of the November 30th Movement and People's Self-Defense, anti-communist groups that oppose the Cuban government.

Cuba says a patrol of five border guard members on a 9-meter boat spotted the incoming vessel shortly after 7 a.m., with some members of the incoming crew in the water, about one nautical mile off a cay on the Caribbean island's northern coast, about 100 miles (160 km) from Marathon.

The infiltrators opened fire at a distance of 185 meters, striking the captain of the Cuban vessel in the abdomen, Cuba said. Bleeding heavily, the wounded captain remained at the helm and steered toward the enemy vessel, leading to a firefight at a distance of about 20 meters, the officers said.

Cuba called its response "proportional."

"It is a defensive model that practically never uses firearms, and the use of firearms is proportional to the type of action being carried out against our force," said Interior Ministry Colonel Ybey Carballo.

The captured Cuban nationals were receiving medical care and face charges including armed aggression, illegal entry into national territory, crimes associated with terrorist acts, and arms trafficking, prosecutor Edward Robert Campbell told the program. He said they face prison terms of up to 10 to 15 years for the lesser offenses and 20 to 30 years - or even the death penalty - for the more serious charges.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:53 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/466BJJQ7PVGY5O53NZ3KL65MHM.png?auth=b9c3bf166c40a6778eb5672993fde7c30a15f48329026674eff92afd8da1d0ca&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US copper mountain still growing after December import surge</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-copper-mountain-still-growing-after-december-import-surge-2026-02-27/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 27 (Reuters) - The huge premium for delivering physical copper to the United States may have gone but the tariff trade tailwinds are still blowing hard.

U.S. imports of refined metal appeared to be waning after the White House pushed back a decision on imposing tariffs in July, collapsing the arbitrage between the CME-traded U.S. price and the London Metal Exchange (LME) international price .

But inbound flows jumped again to almost 200,000 metric tons in December, driving U.S. inventories yet higher.

The U.S. sucked in 1.4 million tons of refined copper over the course of 2025, a year-on-year increase of 730,000 tons, according to the World Bureau of Metal Statistics (WBMS), which sources data from official customs statistics.

That year-on-year jump is a good indication of the size of the metal mountain now sitting in the country.

CME stocks rose by 452,000 tons last year, pretty much matching total deliveries to exchange warehouses after U.S. President Donald Trump announced a national security investigation into the country's copper import dependency in February .

Exchange inventory has increased by another 93,000 tons since the start of 2026 with the relentless build only now starting to show signs of slowing.

However, the flow of metal has not stopped; it has been redirected to LME warehouses in Baltimore and New Orleans.

LME stocks in the two locations have grown from zero at the start of January to 36,450 tons and 10,825 tons respectively with another 30,200 tons sitting in LME off-warrant storage.

The shift in delivery focus makes sense since the spot arbitrage has flipped from a CME premium to a CME discount relative to the LME price.

CME prices are still trading at a sizeable premium to the LME on a forward basis, which suggests lingering uncertainty as to the likelihood of tariffs further down the line.

The Trump administration has flagged a potential decision around the middle of this year with the option of phasing in tariffs on refined metal from the start of 2027.

The imposition of 50% tariffs on imports of copper products such as tube and wire appears to be having the desired effect.

Inbound volumes of copper and alloy semi-manufactured products have fallen sharply since July, which is good news for U.S. fabricators and may persuade the administration to extend the measures to refined metal.

But since the core rationale of tariffs is to reduce U.S. import dependency, it might be argued that just the threat of tariffs on refined copper has already worked.

The United States has accumulated a strategic stockpile without it costing the U.S. taxpayer a cent.

What might catch the White House's attention is the continued export flow of scrap copper.

Exports of secondary copper totaled over one million tons last year, a year-on-year rise of almost 10%, according to the WBMS.

While no-one has yet committed to building a new primary processing plant in the U.S., there has been significant investment in recycling capacity.

That makes the accelerating leakage of copper scrap increasingly problematic, particularly since the single biggest destination is China.

When the U.S. imposed tariffs on copper products in July last year, the Trump administration said it would require that at least 25% of "high-quality" scrap be retained for domestic consumption.

There's been no further clarification of what exactly constitutes "high quality" scrap and since the country already consumes around 40% of the secondary metal that it generates, the threshold is already met on paper at least.

But with the European Union mulling its own restrictions on "scrap leakage", this part of the copper supply chain may be more likely to see U.S. government action than refined metal.

That said, if the copper market has learnt anything over the last year, it's that pricing U.S. tariff risk is very tricky indeed.

( Andy Home is a Reuters columnist. The opinions expressed are his own)

Enjoying this column? Check out Reuters Open Interest (ROI) for thought-provoking, data-driven commentary on markets and finance. Follow ROI on LinkedIn , opens new tab and X , opens new tab .

And listen to the Morning Bid daily podcast on Apple , opens new tab , Spotify , opens new tab , or the Reuters app , opens new tab . Subscribe to hear Reuters journalists discuss the biggest news in markets and finance seven days a week.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:55 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/57JSWAIXQVIC7BN4RJBNPWZSX4.jpg?auth=d0448aa1ee905c6e05e662aea745a61fe618a040cb916f7368b25874eb04fbcb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Morning Bid: AI horror stories</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/global-markets-view-usa-2026-02-27/</link><description>Feb 27 - Everything Mike Dolan and the ROI team are excited to read, watch and listen to over the weekend.

From the Editor

Hello Morning Bid readers!

Markets were jittery this week, as anxiety about the potential impact of the artificial intelligence revolution left investors nervous about their asset allocations and their future job prospects.

This week’s wave of worry was initially set off by a 7,000-word piece, "The 2028 Global Intelligence Crisis," , opens new tab published by research firm Citrini on Sunday. It made for pretty grim reading: the loss of millions of office jobs will destroy demand, plunging the economy into a deflationary tailspin.

Is that possible? Sure, in the sense that anything is possible. But when markets are being spooked by apocalyptic long-form blogposts, it’s time to ask if we are in the midst of an AI doom bubble .

The software sector got a slight boost on Tuesday when a new round of plug-ins from Anthropic highlighted the potential for AI upstarts to partner with legacy firms instead of replacing them.

But, as is often the case, fear trumps hope, and both the S&amp;P 500 and the Nasdaq fell on Thursday .

This was - perhaps surprisingly - after the announcement of another strong quarter from Nvidia - its 14th consecutive revenue beat . The $4.5 trillion chipmaker on Wednesday posted better-than-expected results for the January quarter and also forecast above-market estimates for current quarter revenue. Its share price initially rose, but then pulled back, likely because the good news was already baked in and concerns - such as rising competition and customer concentration - remain.

Meanwhile, two months into the year, the country with the best performing equity market by far is Korea. The benchmark KOSPI index may have slid slightly on Friday, but it’s up more than 48% in the year to date. This eye-popping figure might suggest fevered speculation is at play, but that’s not necessarily the case - and there is reason to believe it could still have room to run .

Moving over to M&amp;A, the months-long battle between Paramount Skydance and Netflix to acquire Warner Bros Discovery appears to be over, with the former coming out on top with its revised $31-a-share offer.

Turning back to anxiety, another major source of it this week was the ongoing standoff between the United States and Iran over Tehran’s nuclear program. The two held indirect talks in Geneva on Thursday.

While crude prices fell following claims that progress in the negotiations had been made, Brent crude was up again early on Friday, trading above $71 a barrel. Discussions will resume in Vienna next week, which means the waiting game continues.

One party that may benefit from the geopolitical noise is OPEC+. The volatile headlines have weighed on prices, giving the producer group cover to stick to its “balanced market” narrative , despite many facts on the ground that suggest otherwise. OPEC+ is expected to announce a 137,000 barrel per day increase in output when it meets on Sunday.

Speaking of energy, one would have needed a lot of it to stay up though all of President Donald Trump’s State of the Union address on Tuesday, which clocked in at a record one hour and 47 minutes. It offered little in the way of new ideas for addressing Americans’ affordability concerns, with the exception of a plan to boost Americans’ retirement savings . The president also vowed to move forward with his tariff agenda even after a large portion of it was quashed by the Supreme Court last week.

One notable takeaway from the speech was the president's claim that hyperscalers "have the obligation to provide for their own power needs" as they build out energy-hungry data centers to fuel the AI boom. The administration wants to avoid stressing the grid and pushing up consumers’ electricity prices.

But the pressure is already building, and whether or not companies cover their own power needs, ambitious AI expansion plans are likely to be hobbled by severe power-infrastructure bottlenecks.

It’s a reminder that instead of fretting about viral AI doomsday reports, we should probably spend a little more time considering the very real physical limitations that could slow down this technological revolution.

For more commodities and markets news, check out Reuters Open Interest . You can learn:

As we head into the weekend, check out the ROI team’s recommendations for what you should read, listen to, and watch to stay informed and ready for the week ahead.

I’d love to hear from you, so please reach out to me at anna.szymanski@thomsonreuters.com , opens new tab .

This weekend, we're reading...

JAMIE MCGEEVER, ROI Markets Columnist: Amid the flood of AI scenarios, one standout this week is the 2026 Global Intelligence Crisis from Citadel Securities, which offers a forensic rebuttal of Citrini's viral doomsday thesis. It is intriguing that one of the world's largest market makers felt compelled to counter a Substack post from a relatively small research firm. Jittery markets, anyone? , opens new tab

ANDY HOME, ROI Metals Columnist: This Reuters exclusive examines a Pentagon-created AI program to set prices for critical minerals. It is beginning with niche "spice" metals - germanium, gallium, antimony, and tungsten, where China now heavily influences pricing - but aims to expand to other critical materials, potentially revolutionizing how metal markets operate .

GAVIN MAGUIRE, ROI Global Energy Transition Columnist: Climate futurist Michael Barnard, writing in CleanTechnica, examines how the U.S. is entrenching legacy energy systems while Europe, China, and others rapidly build more efficient new infrastructure - and asks how capital markets will respond , opens new tab .

CLYDE RUSSELL, ROI Asia Commodities and Energy Columnist: This insight by Fastmarkets explores what the EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism could mean for green steel, which has so far struggled to gain a foothold because buyers aren't willing to pay more and governments have been slow to regulate its use , opens new tab .

We're listening to...

RON BOUSSO, ROI Energy Columnist: The latest Energy Unplugged podcast from Aurora Energy Research features a great conversation with Nat Bullard, co‑founder of Halcyon, discussing how the energy transition is unfolding very differently around the world , opens new tab .

And we're watching...

MIKE DOLAN, Finance &amp; Markets Columnist: I sat down with Carmel Crimmins, host of Reuters Econ World, this week to discuss how "middle powers" are de‑risking from the U.S., recalibrating their relationships with China and pursuing alternative trade deals in a multipolar world that leaves them with few other options , opens new tab .

Want to receive the Morning Bid in your inbox every weekday morning? Sign up for the newsletter here . You can find ROI on the Reuters website , and you can follow us on LinkedIn , opens new tab and X , opens new tab .

Opinions expressed are those of the authors. They do not reflect the views of Reuters News, which, under the Trust Principles , opens new tab , is committed to integrity, independence, and freedom from bias.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:57 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/VBJT5GGQXNMY5OEO5A6HRDQZEI.jpg?auth=94887abc7c7b52f60f5f1a86f6f9753d3a01666ac7af44b34036a04160c995fa&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Why gold beat the Dow in a milestone race</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/why-gold-beat-dow-milestone-race-2026-02-27/</link><description>NEW YORK, Feb 27 (Reuters) - Financial markets recently reached two milestones. On January 26 , gold hit $5,000 an ounce for the first time, and eleven days later , the Dow Jones Industrial Average cracked 50,000. Bullion got to its mark first – and that wasn’t supposed to happen.

Imagine if a prediction market in December 2020 had offered a proposition bet on which historic breakthrough would happen first. At that point, the Dow (.DJI) , opens new tab was already 61% of the way toward its big round number, while gold was just 37% of the way there.

Extrapolating data trends from 1985 through 2020, you would have expected the Dow to reach 50,000 by 2027 and gold not to hit the $5,000 target until 2035.

But gold's trajectory took an astonishingly sharp upturn in the last five years. Its price doubled between 2022 and 2024 alone. That surge helped the precious metal beat the stock index by what essentially amounts to a photo finish.

So why did the trendlines fail to predict the outcome?

In the case of the Dow, the index picked up speed in recent years as capital poured into U.S. markets after the pandemic, but this surge was nothing compared to the rapid spike in the yellow metal.

Analysts have offered several explanations for the dramatic acceleration in gold's gains. One underlying factor is geopolitical instability. Historically, turmoil tends to heighten demand for safe-haven assets.

And there have been plenty of reasons to worry in recent years, including the now four-year-old Russia-Ukraine war , conflicts in the Middle East , and U.S. President Donald Trump's tariff drama as well as his vow to gain control over Greenland .

Inflationary anxieties have further bolstered gold’s appeal, stoked by what many observers see as Trump’s efforts to step up political influence over the Federal Reserve. The president has long called for much lower interest rates .

His nomination of Kevin Warsh , a previous proponent of tighter monetary policy, as the next Fed chair quelled those fears somewhat at the end of January, causing gold to back off from its January 28 peak. But it remains above the $5,000 per ounce threshold.

Meanwhile, worries about a potential pickup in inflation have undermined confidence in the dollar. In response, a number of nations’ central banks have stepped up their purchases of gold in lieu of the U.S. currency.

China’s central bank certainly moved in that direction, and its households and investors also helped drive the rally. The World Gold Council , opens new tab reported a 28% year-over-year increase in the population’s purchases of gold bars and coins in 2025. Chinese gold ETFs have also enjoyed record inflows over the last year.

In short, the Dow’s rise appears to have been an acceleration of existing trends, while gold’s extreme surge was dependent on many exogenous factors and a bit of speculation – which obviously can’t be predicted beforehand.

Ultimately, though, does reaching these financial milestones truly matter?

The achievements occasioned some predictable claims , opens new tab from analysts and the financial press. These assets crossed "critical" psychological thresholds, some argued, with the suggestion that doing so could generate momentum in that direction.

But even if big round numbers like $5,000 or $50,000 have some psychological impact on investors, it's likely to be fleeting.

Consider what happened after the Dow reached previous “psychologically important” thresholds: 1,000 (November 14, 1972), 5,000 (November 21, 1995), 10,000 (March 29, 1999), and 25,000 (January 4, 2018).

In two cases, the Dow rose over the next 12 months by double digits, but it fell in the other two. Whatever warm feeling arises from seeing a commodity or index clear a seemingly significant new level can thus fade quickly once new market-moving information arrives.

One may argue that the rise of passive investing and factor-based trading could amplify any positive momentum garnered from breaking through a big round milestone – but the recent moves in gold suggest that this is not necessarily the case.

The lesson to draw from all of this is that investors would be wise to avoid relying too heavily on either the extrapolation of past price trends or the lasting effect from the latest headline-grabbing market achievements.

Milestones make for great copy, but shaky strategy.

(The views expressed here are those of Marty Fridson , the publisher of Income Securities Advisor. He is a past governor of the CFA Institute, consultant to the Federal Reserve Board of Governors, and Special Assistant to the Director for Deferred Compensation, Office of Management and the Budget, The City of New York.)

Enjoying this column? Check out Reuters Open Interest (ROI), , opens new tab your essential new source for global financial commentary. Follow ROI on LinkedIn , opens new tab and X , opens new tab .

And listen to the Morning Bid daily podcast on Apple , opens new tab , Spotify , opens new tab , or the Reuters app , opens new tab . Subscribe to hear Reuters journalists discuss the biggest news in markets and finance seven days a week.

(This column has been refiled to correct the sign-off and duplicated chart)</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:29:59 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/YCHTSEJHAFIM3KDSMOU6ENXOAA.jpg?auth=4ee10a8e423a62f3810946fe014b6b16b50bc64477bd96eadf071f2940f1d7b5&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>AI fears give tech CEOs convenient cover for cuts</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/commentary/breakingviews/ai-fears-give-tech-ceos-convenient-cover-cuts-2026-02-27/</link><description>NEW YORK, Feb 27 (Reuters Breakingviews) - How many workers does a world with Claude need? Block (XYZ.N) , opens new tab CEO Jack Dorsey upped the urgency of the debate over whether productive chatbots will reduce employment on Thursday, when he announced , opens new tab that the payments company would fire nearly half its workers. Whether artificial intelligence really can do the work of thousands of humans, or just provides impetus to slim down a bloated organization, is unclear. Nonetheless, investors added more than $6 billion to the company’s market value on Friday morning. Such gains will help prod other firms into finding AI savings, real or illusory.

It’s hard for bosses, and more difficult for outsiders, to judge the optimal number of workers for a tech firm. When times are good, there’s the temptation to overhire, ensuring that there are enough engineers to satisfy growing demand and fix emerging problems. That comes at the obvious cost of profitability, but valuations rarely paid the price, while CEOs could reasonably fret about the dangers of underinvestment. Just look at Southwest Airlines, which learned this lesson in 2022 when a software meltdown led to over 10,000 flight cancellations.

Dorsey claims that machine learning has reset this balance of concerns, and rapidly. He said that Block had seen a 40% increase in production code shipped per engineer since September, as well as fruits of an order-of-magnitude jump in the capability and intelligence in its in-house AI framework, Goose. Hence fewer employees will do more, and faster.

Coding-adept chatbots really are remarkable. But Block also had a lot of fat to cut. The company’s headcount exploded during the pandemic, more than tripling between the pre-Covid year of 2019 and the peak in 2023.

Meanwhile, it engaged in questionable deals and breakneck expansion. It agreed to pay $29 billion in stock for buy-now-pay-later company Afterpay in 2021. Such businesses are worth far less today. Rival Klarna, for example, was valued at $46 billion that summer in a private funding round, and now trades at $5 billion. Block also bought music streaming service Tidal in a bizarre expansion, adding musician Jay-Z to the board. Then there was a big push into highly speculative cryptocurrencies, including making bitcoin wallets and a mining system. The stock has performed poorly over the past five years.

Block was far from the only technology company to overextend, especially in the frothy period exiting the pandemic. Its stock gain from pivoting away from that era, AI-driven or not, is concrete. With software valuations plummeting and machine learning fears top of mind , the signal to bosses is to fire away.

Follow Robert Cyran on Bluesky , opens new tab .</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:30:02 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/WQVINX2RMNPRPJTAIT3XZ7RH5U.jpg?auth=b94e48dfef55d7f8b2d710c3c352b233ef805b1f07a4eee6272d68c8ade1b109&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>SpaceX’s nascent monopoly faces durability test</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/commentary/breakingviews/spacexs-nascent-monopoly-faces-durability-test-2026-02-26/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 26 (Reuters Breakingviews) - Investing in an Elon Musk company is less a bet on financial outperformance than a statement of faith in his vision for the future. SpaceX plans to launch one million satellites that will serve as distributed cloud servers in space. These orbital data centers will supposedly harness the power of the sun to process artificial-intelligence workloads. To make it happen, Musk thinks , opens new tab he may need a satellite factory on the moon. He’ll undoubtedly need plenty of cash – which is where a potential SpaceX initial public offering comes in.

At its core, SpaceX is today a profitable satellite communication and launch business with a major lead over would-be rivals. Reuters reported , citing two people familiar with the matter, that Musk's group generated some $8 billion in EBITDA last year on $15 billion to $16 billion of sales. Starlink, its satellite broadband unit, accounted for 50% to 80% of total revenue. The implied group margin of roughly 50% is impressive for what is in large part a broadband supplier with 10 million subscribers , opens new tab worldwide.

At a $1 trillion valuation, using SpaceX's price tag from its recent merger with Grok chatbot maker xAI, it might look like the company is preparing to capture a hefty share of the global telecom market in short order. But the reality is that satellite connectivity is a complement to conventional networks – not a replacement for them. Most consumers in developed markets will find that a fixed-line broadband connection meets their needs at home, while 4G and 5G are readily available on-the-go. Demand for satellite services comes from people and places that telecom companies otherwise struggle to reach.

This isn’t a tiny market, but it will get crowded. Amazon.com (AMZN.O) , opens new tab recently got the greenlight from the U.S. Federal Communications Commission to add around 4,500 more satellites to its planned constellation – taking the total to just under 8,000. Some 200 satellites have been launched so far, with the full fleet due to be in service by 2029. China, meanwhile, is developing two low-earth-orbit networks of its own: one for government and security uses and another aimed at international customers, with tens of thousands of planned satellites in total.

Though SpaceX will list with an effective monopoly in satellite communications, its deep-pocketed rivals have the ability and resources to drain Musk's moat. China’s space efforts are backed by various state-linked entities, which should bolster their chances of success. For its part, Amazon is designing , opens new tab its user terminals with low production costs in mind. If it passes these savings on, and thereby undercuts Starlink, it could gain a market foothold.

Musk’s recent political entanglements also appear to have put a theoretical cap on the size of Starlink’s government and defense business, at least outside its home market. In February 2025, Reuters reported that U.S. negotiators had used Starlink access as a bargaining chip when trying to broker a critical minerals deal with Ukraine. Though Musk denounced the claims on X, the episode clearly unsettled Ukraine’s European allies, who are seeking sovereign alternatives to the satellite service.

To this end, France invested $1.6 billion in Eutelsat Communications – the operator of the OneWeb constellation – (ETL.PA) , opens new tab last summer. The French state is now the largest shareholder in the group, which has some 600 satellites in low-earth orbit. Germany and Italy have also expressed an interest in building their own constellations for secure government and military communications. Were Musk and the U.S. still viewed as reliable partners, such measures may not even be on the table.

Threats to Starlink’s continued domination could also come from within. The recent merger of Musk’s xAI and the rockets-and-satellites group leaves SpaceX exposed to new regulatory and financial risks. According to documents seen , opens new tab by Bloomberg, xAI reported a net loss of $1.5 billion for the three months to the end of September 2025, while it burned through some $8 billion in cash in the first nine months of the year. This makes growing the top and bottom lines at Starlink look even more critical for the combined group. And there is regulatory risk, as multiple jurisdictions are investigating the Grok chatbot, which produced and circulated sexually explicit images on social network X.

All the noise around the company, and limited financial disclosures, make it tricky to value. Assume, for the sake of argument, that 70% of SpaceX's recent $1 trillion merger value is attributable to Starlink, roughly in line with its revenue contribution. That would imply a valuation of around $700 billion for the satellite unit.

Analysts at Quilty Space reckon Starlink could bring in roughly $16 billion in revenue and $11 billion in EBITDA this year. At an enterprise value of $700 billion, this would imply a forward sales multiple of 44 and an EBITDA multiple of 64. That's in the same ballpark as super-racy Palantir Technologies' (PLTR.O) , opens new tab equivalent valuations of 42 times 2026 revenue and 72 times 2026 EBITDA, using Visible Alpha data, and is therefore in a different stratosphere to the single-digit multiples of Eutelsat and telecom groups like T-Mobile US (TMUS.O) , opens new tab and Verizon Communications (VZ.N) , opens new tab .

Granted, the older communications groups are barely growing compared with Starlink, which arguably justifies a more Palantir-style multiple for Musk's business. Even then, however, it's hard to make the numbers work. Using analysts' long-term forecasts, to factor in growth expectations, Palantir trades at just under 18 times 2030 EBITDA. Applying that multiple to Starlink would imply that the satellite unit of SpaceX needs to produce $39 billion of EBITDA that year in order to justify a $700 billion enterprise value for the division.

Longtime SpaceX bulls Morgan Stanley, by comparison, think Starlink's revenue could reach almost $50 billion by 2030, which using a 50% margin would imply $25 billion of EBITDA. That's impressive, but well short of what's needed to buttress the valuation. And Morgan Stanley's forecasts look very much like a blue-sky scenario. Even if Musk pulls off a trillion-dollar stock market launch, that’s no guarantee of a smooth ride.

Follow Jennifer Johnson on Bluesky , opens new tab and LinkedIn , opens new tab .</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:30:04 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/PAPCTKZUHRLBTKQQ45BJ5OQENM.jpg?auth=775d3b1fc046fbd5dab6cae9612bbfce562297e6239c2e49a8b3277d877873b2&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>EU’s markets Big Bang depends on local fireworks</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/commentary/breakingviews/eus-markets-big-bang-depends-local-fireworks-2026-02-27/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 27 (Reuters Breakingviews) - The European Union’s decade-long mission to beef up its financial markets has spawned multiple acronyms. What started out as the Capital Markets Union (CMU) has morphed into the Savings and Investment Union (SIU). A more appropriate moniker for reviving European savings and markets might be S&amp;M, as it has involved more pain than pleasure. Even now, any meaningful progress will depend on what happens at a national level.

The campaign to kick-start European markets was born of multiple crises. The initial drive to make trading and capital raising more efficient received an impetus after the 2008 financial crisis and subsequent euro zone sovereign debt meltdown exposed the bloc’s reliance on shaky banks. Brexit removed the City of London from the EU's single market. More recently, former European Central Bank boss Mario Draghi's report on competitiveness identified a 750-billion-euro investment gap for financing renewable energy, and other critical needs.

Now the EU faces even more urgent pressure to reform. U.S. President Donald Trump's at-times hostile stance has exposed the bloc's dependence on U.S. technology titans and historic lack of investment in defence. European leaders this month agreed unanimously , opens new tab to accelerate the SIU.

Reforming capital markets in a bloc of 27 countries with a combined economic output of around $20 trillion is a daunting task. The EU’s relative weakness when it comes to using equity and fixed income securities as a source of financing owes much to culture and history. The bloc has a long-standing dependence on banks, different legal frameworks, and language barriers which discourage cross-border investment.

However, a fragmented capital market with multiple local regulators and differing rules and infrastructures also points to tantalising potential efficiencies. Despite ten years of work these benefits remain out of reach. Initial public offerings in the EU raised just $17.7 billion last year, less than half the equivalent U.S. sum, as per LSEG data. Annual equity trading volumes relative to stock market capitalisation – a measure of liquidity and hence market depth – are roughly a third of the U.S. level, according to a 2025 report by the Association for Financial Markets in Europe.

Scratch beneath the surface, though, and change is happening. A package of reforms to make stock market listings easier is slowly being implemented, as are moves to boost securitisation. Perhaps the most significant reforms were those proposed by the European Commission in December , opens new tab . These aim to break down barriers for cross-border capital flows by streamlining regulation and tackling a fragmented market in equities. Myriad national players are involved in the business of trading and settling securities, and the preponderance of domestic regulators and rules pushes up costs. The United States has the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation, which dominates the clearing and settlement of securities. By contrast, Europe has more than 30 securities depositaries charging fees nearly two-thirds higher than their counterparts stateside. This imposes a 1 billion euro , opens new tab per year cost on the continent's traders and investors, AFME reckons.

In an ideal world, all local obstacles could be removed by meshing together different players to create a single exchange on which all EU citizens can trade, connecting a capital-hungry German tech group with a Spanish saver. To some degree, that’s happening. Large players like Euronext (ENX.PA) , opens new tab and Nasdaq (NDAQ.O) , opens new tab have snapped up smaller regional bourses, centralising technology and infrastructure. Euronext bought the Athens stock exchange last year. Yet big countries like Germany and France have limited appetite for creating continent-wide operators if it means losing control of a national champion.

Brussels can still help by making regulation more efficient and removing barriers to competition. The Commission’s latest proposals include steps to make trade settlement more competitive while transferring more regulatory powers to the European Securities and Markets Authority. It is even encouraging disruption with a plan to foster blockchain-based technology that could simplify the trading and settling of shares or bonds.

These reforms move in the right direction, but will take time and may not work as intended. The drive to streamline regulation may end up increasing bureaucracy if the powers of a single supervisor overlap with local watchdogs. Countries that already benefit from vibrant markets, such as Ireland or Luxembourg, may see few benefits.

Besides, more efficient markets can only achieve so much. The United Kingdom has one of the most liquid bourses in Europe yet is struggling to attract new listings. And European stock exchanges may not be as sleepy as they first appear. Strip away the so-called Magnificent 7 tech stocks and the U.S. market is only 1.5 times more liquid than Europe’s, as measured by stock turnover relative to market capitalisation, think tank New Financial notes.

Other reforms are therefore necessary, which explains why lawmakers and market participants now talk more about the SIU than the CMU. When it comes to boosting savings and investment, governments can make big changes without pan-European coordination. Take Sweden. Draghi's report , opens new tab notes that the Scandinavian country has attracted more IPOs over the last 10 years than Germany, France, the Netherlands and Spain combined. Last year it notched up two of the top , opens new tab five offerings in Europe, Middle East and Africa, including the $3.7 billion raised by security group Verisure.

Sweden’s success is down to smart incentives and a multi-decade process of reforms, which include stripping back taxes and incentivising individuals to save and invest in their pensions. Some 36% of Swedish household assets are held in stocks, outstripping Germany, France and even the UK.

Many European countries are trying to copy Stockholm’s success. Both France and Germany have started to encourage more personal pension savings. Yet they have a lot of catching up to. Europe's long history of government-run pay-as-you-go retirement schemes means pension assets are just , opens new tab 32% of GDP, versus 142% in the U.S. in 2022.

Reforms are getting harder. Europe’s ageing population has less incentive to save and governments have more debt. Past efforts have also proved misguided. The UK subsidised individual investment accounts to the tune of 8 billion pounds in 2024, yet many customers park their tax-free savings in bank deposits, doing little for growth.

This means there’s plenty of upside. New Financial estimates that, in a plausible scenario where each member state improved its performance to match the average of better-performing countries, Europe’s pool of long-term capital could grow by more than half to $44 trillion. Rather than dreaming up new pan-European acronyms, bureaucrats would be better off concentrating on local improvements.

Follow @Unmack1 , opens new tab on X</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:30:07 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/V2JHKABKQNLP7LQKMJFYTPEHPI.jpg?auth=9b6f7321ed9fa2c17ff8e4a2eaad27cfe9a0a93ebecf2953d9bcb0c9cded2a7e&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Trump’s tariff upset has plenty of upside: podcast</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/trumps-tariff-upset-has-plenty-upside-podcast-2026-02-26/</link><description>Follow on Apple or Spotify . Listen on the Reuters app.

The US may be on the hook for $175 bln worth of refunds after the Supreme Court deemed the president’s tariffs illegal. In this Viewsroom podcast, Breakingviews columnists discuss the opportunities for countries now eyeing a weakened Trump and what’s likely to come next.

Follow Aimee Donnellan on LinkedIn .

Follow Jonathan Guilford on X and LinkedIn .

(The hosts are Reuters Breakingviews columnists. The opinions expressed are their own.)

Further Reading

Corporate America will harry trade warriors

EU’s best tariff move is to stall a weaker Trump

The Supreme Court ignites a new tariff frenzy</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:30:11 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IMBTCDAOIZFQNFCKCDMDQ3SGTY.jpg?auth=b0ee63c743ac9f4be0b43b73c820caad533fd108c8ec8ce01178b286944a37a6&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Top US general, Hegseth monitoring Iran strikes from Trump resort, person familiar says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/top-us-general-hegseth-monitoring-iran-strikes-trump-resort-person-familiar-says-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Pentagon chief Pete Hegseth and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff General Dan Caine are monitoring the U.S. operation in Iran from President Donald Trump's Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida, where Trump is currently located, a person familiar with the matter told Reuters.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:53:17 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/K7QTTJOJV5M7XILHFWBXQGIZCI.jpg?auth=f31506b36c00db9f6927c72d92520405525ff641c031f1d5eafb6268129e5ef0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>UK says Iran must never be allowed to develop nuclear weapons</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-says-iran-must-never-be-allowed-develop-nuclear-weapons-2026-02-28/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Britain said on Saturday that Iran must never be allowed to develop nuclear weapons and stood ready to defend its interests, following strikes by the United States and Israel against Iran.

A government source said Britain had not taken part in the strikes, and that British Prime Minister Keir Starmer would hold an emergency response meeting, a so-called COBRA meeting, on Saturday.

"Iran must never be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon and that is why we have continually supported efforts to reach a negotiated solution," a government spokesperson said in a statement.

"As part of our longstanding commitments to the security of our allies in the Middle East, we have a range of defensive capabilities in the region, which we have recently bolstered. We stand ready to protect our interests," the spokesperson said.

Britain does not want to see further escalation into a wider regional conflict, the spokesperson added.

Britain's immediate priority was the safety of its nationals in the region, and it would provide consular assistance, according to the statement.

The government also issued a notice on Saturday advising against all travel to Israel and the Palestinian territories, after advising on Friday against non-essential travel in the regions.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:53:43 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IH6HEWEG7RLFDCKOFAZ5JENJWQ.jpg?auth=fbab2f42eb5d69592d570bac11ad0cba50060106c058e68e0a3094aeb9811002&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Insight: After El Mencho's killing, his cartel's power endures deep inside the US</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/after-el-menchos-killing-his-cartels-power-endures-deep-inside-us-2026-02-28/</link><description>MEXICO CITY, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The Mexican government's killing of one of the world's biggest kingpins, known as " El Mencho ," is being heralded as a major blow to drug trafficking.

But it did little to dismantle his cartel's critical U.S. operations, which will continue fueling its dominance unless Washington steps up the fight inside its own territory, U.S. and Mexican security sources said.

Mexican special forces killed the elusive drug lord Nemesio Oseguera in a U.S.-backed raid on Feb. 22. It was the biggest takedown of a cartel kingpin in at least a decade.

El Mencho's Jalisco New Generation Cartel responded by torching buildings and blockading roads across Mexico in a terrifying display of its territorial reach that grabbed headlines worldwide.

On the U.S. side of the border, the cartel also has extensive networks that receive far less attention yet are the lifeblood of its power and profits, current and former U.S. and Mexican officials said. These enable it to source military-grade weapons, smuggle billions of dollars' worth of fuel, and launder billions more in cartel cash.

"The United States has become increasingly important to cartels, especially the Jalisco New Generation Cartel, for it to thrive," said Alamdar Hamdani, the former U.S. attorney for the Southern District of Texas.

White House spokeswoman Anna Kelly said that the Trump administration "has worked closely with the Mexican government to stop the scourge of drugs and criminals entering our country" and that this cooperation led to the "elimination of infamous narcoterrorist 'El Mencho.'"

"The president will continue to do everything in his power to keep America safe from these vicious criminals and the drugs they use to poison our country," she added.

Washington heaped pressure on Mexico to step up the cartel fight ahead of the raid against the once untouchable drug lord.

Such actions are risky for the Mexican government because they can spark a wave of violence in a country where the drug war has already cost tens of thousands of lives.

The decision by Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum to escalate her crackdown has prompted renewed calls for the U.S. to do more on its side of the border.

"The United States can't turn a blind eye to Mexico's demands any longer," said Mexican Congressman Alfonso Ramirez Cuellar, a close ally of Sheinbaum.

He said the U.S. needed to improve efforts to go after money laundering, fuel smuggling and, above all, weapons smuggled from the U.S. into Mexico.

"We can't stop drug traffickers if the United States continues allowing them to strengthen their military capabilities," he said.

The U.S. has built and prosecuted hundreds of cases related to cartel-related activity inside the U.S. in recent years.

But the Trump administration last year diverted thousands of agents , including many specializing in drugs, firearms, and money laundering, away from such cases and to the mass deportation effort.

Reuters also reported in September that the number of people charged with drug conspiracies and money laundering fell significantly last year.

"The Trump administration has predominantly focused on highly militarized actions against drugs abroad and has not paid similar attention to actions at home," said Vanda Felbab-Brown, a security expert.

A spokesperson from the U.S. Department of Justice said the administration was "acutely focused on securing the border, prosecuting violent traffickers, deporting any and all members of cartel networks and ensuring they are held accountable for their horrific crimes against the American people."

The department also pointed to a string of recent cases, including against high-ranking members of the Jalisco cartel.

The office of Mexico's president did not respond to requests for comment.

Roberto Velasco, the Undersecretary for North America at Mexico's Foreign Ministry, said the Mexican government has repeatedly emphasized in bilateral meetings and working groups that stopping arms trafficking is a top Mexican priority.

"While there has been some significant progress, we believe much more can be done to control this flow and to target the networks in the United States that facilitate it, empowering transnational criminal organizations," he said.

Reuters spoke to a dozen current and former U.S. and Mexican officials after El Mencho's killing and reviewed U.S. court documents from 10 recent cases related to the cartel to gain better insight into its U.S. operations.

What emerged was a picture of U.S.-based activities that are critical to the cartel's firepower and profits and unlikely to be impacted by the death of its leader. Reuters reporting also revealed how U.S. companies and professionals – from fuel traders to cell phone retailers to stockbrokers – are complicit in cartel activity.

"There's a lot of economic integration - both legal and illegal," said Alexia Bautista, a former Mexican diplomat.

When Mexican Special Forces descended on a cabin in a picturesque mountain town where El Mencho was waiting for a visit from his girlfriend , the cartel leader's men fought back – armed predominantly with U.S. weapons, Mexican Army chief Ricardo Trevilla said at a press conference.

Some 80% of the 23,000 weapons the Mexican government has seized since Sheinbaum took office in late 2024 came from the U.S., he added.

The Jalisco cartel, in particular, has become adept at sourcing heavy, military-grade artillery from U.S. gun shops across the country, according to U.S. and Mexican authorities.

Through one of its gun-running networks, the cartel obtained guns from more than a dozen U.S. states, including .50 caliber rifles capable of downing helicopters and FN SCAR assault rifles designed for U.S. Special Forces, according to a Reuters investigation .

While such firepower can be purchased legally in the U.S., the arms become illegal once they enter Mexico, which has tight gun regulations.

"We complain about the Mexicans' lack of effort to go after the drugs down there, but then why does the U.S. dismiss their argument that we could do better on the guns going southbound?" said Derek Maltz, former acting administrator for the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration.

"The U.S. has to step up in a lot of areas," he said, citing not only arms trafficking prosecutions but also public health and mental illness programs to curb American drug demand.

Americans' insatiable demand for narcotics has long fueled the cartels' profits. But while drugs are the cash cow, in less than a decade the groups have quietly built a multi-billion dollar cross-border petroleum empire.

The Jalisco cartel dominates this business, which would have been impossible to expand without a network of knowingly or unknowingly complicit U.S. companies that includes refiners, fuel traders, transport companies and storage facilities, as Reuters reported in October.

"This is no longer stealing fuel from (state energy company) Pemex ," said Guadalupe Correa, a professor at George Mason University who has studied how cartels diversify their income streams. "It's a huge, transnational business."

The cartel orchestrates two versions of the scheme, according to U.S. and Mexican authorities.

In Mexico, cartel members steal crude oil from Pemex that is then smuggled across the border where it gets sold to U.S. companies. In the other direction, cartel members purchase mostly diesel and gasoline from U.S. companies via shell companies. The fuel arrives in Mexico disguised as something else, in what boils down to a very lucrative tax fraud.

Sheinbaum confirmed last year that U.S. business people had been involved in the fuel smuggling cases under investigation. "One cannot explain otherwise how fuel comes from the U.S. to Mexico, and enters illegally," she said.

HUNDREDS OF MILLIONS IN CARTEL-RELATED ASSETS IN U.S.

In late 2024, El Mencho's son-in-law Cristian Gutierrez Ochoa was arrested in a $1.2 million house in Riverside, California.

According to the court records, Gutierrez, who pled guilty to an international money laundering conspiracy in June 2025, said he bought the five-bedroom property using drug proceeds funneled through a Mexico-based shell company set up to look like a tequila producer.

Real estate is one of myriad ways Jalisco cartel cleans its cash in the U.S.

In many of the schemes, the involvement of U.S. businesses is key, said Carlos Olivo, a former DEA agent who specialized in tracing the cartel's U.S. financial networks. He said the cartel's money flows through restaurants, textiles, the music industry, the agricultural sector and even the U.S. stock market.

"In total, we're talking about hundreds of millions in assets in cartel-related money in the United States," he said.

In response to questions about this story, a DEA spokesperson said the cartels employed a wide range of money laundering schemes and "also use trade-based money laundering schemes, cryptocurrency, bulk cash, and Chinese underground banking systems to fund their operations."

Alejandro Celorio, a former Mexican diplomat, said he hoped that Sheinbaum's decision to go after the most powerful cartel leader in the country would inspire the U.S. to redouble its efforts – inside its own borders.

"As the world's leading commercial and military power, the U.S. could certainly investigate more deeply how money and drugs move within U.S. territory," Celorio said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:24:36 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4QUCCPSZ7VLA3BTEYECHODDII4.jpg?auth=28d89e28f9bd4b81055cf1c74cef486276c644f7f93d395fb356e1a5fd4268f5&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>US-Israeli attack triggers fear and panic in Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/us-israeli-attack-triggers-fear-panic-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>DUBAI, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Long queues formed at gas stations and many Iranians began heading out of cities in search of safety, witnesses said, as an attack by the United States and Israel on Iran spread fear and panic throughout the country.

Explosions rocked Tehran and columns of smoke rose into the sky on Saturday morning, shaking the city at the start of the Iranian working week. One man, speaking to Reuters from the capital, said he was rushing to get his children from school.

"We are scared, we are terrified. My children are shaking, we have nowhere to go, we will die here," said Minou, a 32-year-old mother of two from the northern city of Tabriz, one of many areas where explosions were reported.

"What is going to happen to my children?," she said, crying as she spoke by phone.

Iran's top security body said it expected attacks to continue in Tehran and some other cities, and therefore urged people to "travel to other cities where possible so that you may remain safe from the harm of these two regimes’ acts of aggression". Schools and universities would be closed until further notice.

The attack marks the latest upheaval for Iranians just weeks after thousands of people were killed in a government crackdown on nationwide unrest, and comes just eight months after last year's 12-day war with Israel, during which the United States bombed Iranian nuclear sites .

U.S. President Donald Trump said the operation would end a security threat to the United States and offer Iranians a chance to topple their rulers. The Pentagon said that U.S. strikes against Iran were named "OPERATION EPIC FURY."

An Iranian from the central city of Yazd said he hoped that the attack would topple the clerical establishment that has run the country since the 1979 Islamic Revolution. "Let them bomb," the resident of Yazd said.

But Samira Mohebbi, speaking from the northern city of Rasht, disagreed.

"I am against this regime, to hell with them. But I don't want my country to be attacked by foreign forces, I don't want my Iran to turn into Iraq," she said, referring to the neighbouring country that suffered years of chaos and bloodshed following the U.S.-led invasion that toppled Saddam Hussein.

Security forces blocked roads in the area of Tehran that is home to the offices of Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, President Masoud Pezeshkian, and parliament, witnesses said.

The attacks came after the latest round of negotiations between the United States and Iran in Geneva on Thursday failed to secure a breakthrough over Tehran's nuclear programme, though Omani mediators had reported progress.

"They said the nuclear talks are going well. They fooled us again," said a resident of Tehran.

Western governments have long suspected Iran aims to build a nuclear bomb. Tehran has always denied this.

Witnesses said people were rushing to buy hard currency.

In Isfahan, another area where attacks were reported, some said they were unable to withdraw cash from ATMs.

Reza Saadati, 45, said he was taking his family to the city of Urumieh near the Turkish border. "If the border is open, we will cross and then fly to Istanbul," he said.

Mohammad Esmaili, 63, speaking from the town of Ilam, some 500 km (300 miles) from Tehran, said he would leave the town with his family. "God knows what will happen to us. Pray for us," he said.

A mother of three from Tehran said: "People are shocked, scared. What is going to happen to us? Save us please."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:24:38 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/AYZ2SIURQRJDDDLCWACUOXA7PQ.jpg?auth=64e713883070b0bceb9c1c5126bb390c5776d3137de7328e0efdb779b7de6adb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Greece advises Greek-flagged vessels to avoid some shipping routes after strikes on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/greece-advises-greek-flagged-vessels-avoid-some-shipping-routes-after-strikes-2026-02-28/</link><description>ATHENS, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Greece's shipping ministry advised Greek-flagged vessels on Saturday to exercise maximum vigilance and avoid the Persian Gulf, the Gulf of Oman and the Strait of Hormuz following strikes by the United States and Israel against Iran, according to an advisory seen by Reuters.

"The developing situation affects the safety of navigation in the wider Persian Gulf, the Straits of Hormuz, the Gulf of Oman and the North Arabian Sea," the document said, advising managing companies to implement the highest level of security measures in those areas and Israeli ports until further notice.

It added that it could not rule out the spread of the crisis to the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden due to links between Iran and Iran-aligned Houthi militants.

The advisory also warned ships to be vigilant for potential missile or drone attacks, strikes on port facilities, harassment or electronic interference and disruptions to the electronic navigation systems of ships.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:24:51 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/CMHOPRUJQFKGBF62JK3VOTQN54.jpg?auth=8d82933f3e0f7f7b50017e21c57fd57eaad2c8955c6b9b7a026e364bc422d768&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russia suspends flights to Iran and Israel</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/russia-suspends-flights-iran-israel-2026-02-28/</link><description>MOSCOW, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The Russian Ministry of Transport said on Saturday that Russian air carriers had suspended flights to Iran and Israel.

Israel said it launched a pre-emptive attack against Iran on Saturday, pushing the Middle East into a renewed military confrontation and further dimming hopes for a diplomatic solution to Tehran's long-running nuclear dispute with the West.

The ministry said that in connection with the closure of Iranian and Israeli airspace, Russian air carriers, in cooperation with the ministry and Rosaviatsiya aviation watchdog, had worked out alternative flight routes in advance to ensure safe flights to the Persian Gulf countries.

Flight times will increase due to the longer distances, it said.

Rosaviatsiya said in a separate statement published later on Saturday that it had issued recommendations for Russian air carriers after Bahrain, Iraq, Qatar and Kuwait had closed their airspace to ensure flight safety, and UAE authorities had also introduced temporary restrictions on the use of their airspace.

The Russian airspace watchdog said carriers are advised to choose alternative routes when flying to the Persian Gulf countries, observing all safety measures and actively monitoring the recommendations of the aviation authorities of foreign states.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:25:08 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/T2BUMVIUORIF3EEHRO5QTMZ4EY.jpg?auth=9f5ea76cd70cb0ddf9dc25f129752971c36b73e16d2686f54001ae0be1fc0ad9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iran fires missiles at Gulf Arab states, one killed in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-fires-missiles-gulf-arab-states-one-killed-abu-dhabi-2026-02-28/</link><description>DUBAI, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Several Gulf Arab states said they were targeted by Iranian missiles on Saturday after Tehran pledged to retaliate against strikes by the United States and Israel, bringing conflict to a part of the Arab world that prides itself on relative safety.

State media in the United Arab Emirates said one person had been killed in Abu Dhabi, but gave no details.

Kuwait, Qatar, the UAE, and Jordan, all of which have a U.S. military presence, said they had intercepted the Iranian missiles.

"All occupied territories and the criminal U.S. bases in the region have been struck by the powerful blows of Iranian missiles. This operation will continue relentlessly until the enemy is decisively defeated," Iran's Revolutionary Guards said.

Bahrain confirmed an attack inside its territory and said a service center of the U.S. Fifth Fleet had been struck. Video from a Reuters witness showed a plume of grey smoke rising near the small island nation's coast as sirens wailed.

Loud booms were heard across Abu Dhabi, according to five witnesses including two Reuters correspondents. Some residents received a phone alert telling them to shelter in the closest secure building and stay away from windows because of missile threats.

One witness told Reuters she heard five booms in rapid succession that caused windows in a house near Abu Dhabi's Corniche to vibrate. Other witnesses in the Al Dhafra and Bateen areas heard loud booms as well.

Fighter jets could be seen flying around the Yas Island area of Abu Dhabi on Saturday afternoon.

In Qatar, the military said in a statement that it had intercepted incoming Iranian missiles before they reached Qatari territory after "joint coordination". Several successive waves of blasts were heard in the Qatari capital Doha.

After the U.S. Embassy issued a warning to take shelter in Doha, many residents carried on their usual activities. Shoppers were in supermarkets, beachgoers headed to the seaside and a yellow double-decker tour bus filled with tourists drove through the city's West Bay district.

Later, when the government pushed a shelter-in-place warning to mobile phones, fewer people were seen out in the streets and traffic thinned.

The Kuwaiti army says it dealt with missiles in Kuwaiti airspace, while Jordan said it had downed two Iranian ballistic missiles.

Global airlines suspended flights across the Middle East, with flight maps showing the airspace over Iran virtually empty.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:46:01 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/7NAXLYAZVJPAXHBYLADJN4UA4I.jpg?auth=c3588102ce5389f72a9ca183e6a8afdb94da4802495ecd723a6a84a28ae06f67&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>NATO closely following developments in Iran and region, spokesperson says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/nato-closely-following-developments-iran-region-spokesperson-says-2026-02-28/</link><description>BRUSSELS, Feb 28 (Reuters) - NATO is closely following developments in Iran and the region , NATO spokesperson Allison Hart said on Saturday.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:46:46 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/K7QTTJOJV5M7XILHFWBXQGIZCI.jpg?auth=f31506b36c00db9f6927c72d92520405525ff641c031f1d5eafb6268129e5ef0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Greeks rally to mark anniversary of deadly 2023 train crash ahead of trial</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/greeks-rally-mark-anniversary-deadly-2023-train-crash-ahead-trial-2026-02-28/</link><description>ATHENS, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Tens of thousands of Greeks rallied in Athens and other cities on Saturday to mark the anniversary of a 2023 train crash, the country's deadliest rail disaster in history, demanding justice ahead of a criminal trial set to begin next month.

Trains and ferries came to a halt and urban transport was disrupted as workers walked off the job to join the demonstrations. Protesters laid flowers and held banners reading "Justice" outside parliament, where the names of the 57 victims - mostly students - have been spray‑painted in red on the ground.

The victims died when a passenger train and a freight train collided head-on at Tempi in central Greece.

The disaster has become a stark symbol of state failings, including safety lapses and years of neglect of the rail network.

Fuelled by mistrust of politicians, who are largely shielded from prosecution under Greek law, last year’s mass protests were the biggest in years.

Thousands of police officers were deployed in Athens on Saturday. Demonstrations were also held abroad.

"We seek one thing: Justice," said Pavlos Aslanidis, head of the victims' relatives association in a speech.

A judicial investigation concluded this year and dozens of non-politicians will stand trial on March 23 on charges ranging from traffic disruption leading to deaths to negligent manslaughter and causing bodily harm.

Protesters want reforms and political accountability. "It wasn't an accident, it was murder," read one banner in Athens.

Probes have found that a project co-funded by the European Union to install safety systems was launched in 2014 but was years behind schedule in 2023. Relatives have also accused authorities of trying to cover up evidence.

The centre-right government, which denies wrongdoing, says justice will shed light on the case and has pledged full railway reform by 2027.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:58:05 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/JLVCOMXPB5P2DPXLPBBNMUCYFU.jpg?auth=977ac81a47ba1df4d722bb88f782022247872b1b69b86b12b0273e1db9476cbb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Israel shuts schools, bans gatherings as Iran launches retaliatory missiles</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/israel-shuts-schools-bans-gatherings-iran-launches-retaliatory-missiles-2026-02-28/</link><description>TEL AVIV, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israel banned public gatherings, shut schools and workplaces and moved hospital patients to underground facilities on Saturday as Tehran launched missiles towards Israel in retaliation for a joint U.S.-Israeli attack on Iran.

Defence Minister Israel Katz declared a state of emergency across the country, warning the public of Iranian missile and drone attacks.

The military ordered the public to follow emergency guidance as it announced tens of thousands of reservists were being called up for service, including to reinforce its land borders. The police urged against non-essential travel so as to allow security and emergency vehicles to move freely.

Protected by a sophisticated air defence system, some Israelis went to the beach in Tel Aviv on Saturday ahead of the initial Iranian response, saying they felt safe and voicing support for an operation against Iran.

"It's about time," said Shira Dorany as she took a walk along Tel Aviv's Mediterranean-front promenade.

"I don't want to wait anymore for what's coming. Now, it's coming. Let's finish it."

There were few reports of damage or injuries from Iran's initial missile barrages. Israelis generally have access to bomb shelters and are warned to rush to them by a nationwide alert system.

Israel and Iran last year faced off in an aerial war, after Israel launched a surprise attack on Iran in June that the United States later joined. The war lasted 12 days, killing over 30 people in Israel and more than 900 in Iran.

Tel Aviv, where several military sites are located, suffered multiple strikes during last year's war, as did parts of southern Israel where there are some military bases.

Israel on Saturday closed its airspace to civilian flights though land borders with Egypt and Jordan remained open, according to a spokesperson from the airport authority.

The U.S. Embassy in Jerusalem said government personnel had been advised to shelter in place, after on Friday warning staff they should leave the country if they wished to.

In Jerusalem, people were seen rushing to buy food and withdraw money as explosions from missile interceptions echoed across the city.

At the Sheba Medical Center near Tel Aviv, medical workers were moving entire hospital wards underground.

"(Sheba) switched to advanced preparedness mode in preparation for the strike in Iran. We are in the process of moving all our departments and services into protected areas," said Itai Pessach, the medical center's director general.

At the beach in Tel Aviv, Maayan Eliasi, 43, said Israeli strikes on Iran were necessary "to establish that we are strong."

"We are not scared, and we are here to protect our land."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:58:51 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/HNHDY5W3CRNN5M6OSEWZS6GTXM.jpg?auth=1035d49133f27bf78f2591084ae7b8a18ee131aa1e9a094ca9d41f6f710286eb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Four people killed in Syria after an Iranian missile falls on building, state media reports</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/four-people-killed-syria-after-an-iranian-missile-falls-building-state-media-2026-02-28/</link><description>DAMASCUS, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Four people were killed and several others wounded when an Iranian missile struck a building in the southern Syrian city of Sweida on Saturday, the state news agency SANA said.

Other missile debris fell in the city of Quneitra and the Yarmouk Basin in Daraa province in southern Syria, according to Reuters witnesses and videos shared by residents.

The sounds of warplanes were heard repeatedly in the skies over Syria on Saturday, after the United States and Israel announced a military operation against Iran.

Dozens of interceptor missiles were seen in the skies over Damascus, according to two witnesses, one of them a Reuters reporter.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:59:10 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russian Rosatom evacuates people from Iran, keeps staff at Bushehr plant</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/russian-rosatom-evacuates-people-iran-keeps-staff-bushehr-plant-2026-02-28/</link><description>MOSCOW, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Russian state nuclear corporation Rosatom has evacuated nearly 100 people from Iran, but its personnel remain at the Bushehr nuclear power plant, the company said on Saturday, citing CEO Alexei Likhachev.

The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran on Saturday, targeting its leadership and plunging the Middle East into a new conflict.

Rosatom said it had evacuated all employees' children, as well as "non-essential staff" and anyone who wished to leave the country - a total of 94 people.

"We are constantly monitoring the situation and assessing the risks. If necessary, additional measures will be taken in cooperation with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs to ensure the safety of our employees," Likhachev said.

He did not provide details on the situation at Bushehr but said that nuclear facilities "should not be targeted under any circumstances."

Bushehr, built by Russia, is Iran's only operational nuclear power plant. Russian personnel work at the site.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:59:12 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4U4NKMASN5KARKSFV3PNHRTK3E.jpg?auth=a455e5723efa7ecd0ab267b6b966d874c940c3c143553dc8db7c50dd5822cc4d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>France's Macron calls for urgent meeting of U.N. security council on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/frances-macron-calls-urgent-meeting-un-security-council-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>PARIS, Feb 28 (Reuters) - French President Emmanuel Macron on Saturday called for an urgent meeting of the United Nations Security Council, saying the outbreak of a war between the United States, Israel and Iran has "serious consequences" for international peace and security.

Macron spoke separately with leaders of Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Qatar, Jordan and the president of the autonomous region of Kurdistan, his office said.

France was ready to deploy the necessary resources to protect its closest partners at their request, Macron said on X.

"The current escalation is dangerous for everyone. It must stop. The Iranian regime must understand that it now has no other option but to engage in good-faith negotiations to end its nuclear and ballistic missile programs, as well as its actions to destabilize the region," Macron said.

"This is absolutely essential for the security of everyone in the Middle East," he added.

"The Iranian people must also be able to build their future freely. The massacres perpetrated by the Islamic regime discredit it and necessitate that the people be given a voice. The sooner the better."

The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran on Saturday, plunging the Middle East into a new conflict that President Donald Trump said would end a security threat to the United States and offer Iranians a chance to topple their rulers.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:59:33 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/BYGZR7B5FBLCDM3TQG5YOS3LNY.jpg?auth=db9cab5133574200eae9d68bf2c1bf7204d5ed2cf53d60bcbd83321172a3f597&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Brazilian government condemns strikes on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazilian-government-condemns-strikes-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>SAO PAULO, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The Brazilian government on Saturday condemned US-Israel attacks on Iranian targets and expressed grave concern over the military action.

"The attacks occurred amid a negotiation process between the parties, which is the only viable path to peace, a position traditionally defended by Brazil in the region," the government said in a statement.

The Brazilian government appealed to all parties to respect international law and exercise maximum restraint to avoid escalating hostilities and protect civilians.

Its embassies in the region are monitoring developments, with particular attention to Brazilian communities in affected countries, according to the statement.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:43:13 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/S4IVGNXR7VLSPHY753T2RXSUFI.jpg?auth=087f7cfc7100b7c5fc37229e05a173cf9b028a22445eea61fe0824c01010899d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Russia says Trump and Israel are plunging the Middle East into the abyss with Iran attack</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/russia-says-trump-israel-are-plunging-middle-east-into-abyss-with-iran-attack-2026-02-28/</link><description>MOSCOW, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Russia on Saturday criticised U.S. President Donald Trump and Israel for embarking on a dangerously irresponsible attack on Iran which Moscow said was plunging the entire Middle East into the abyss.

The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran , targeting its leadership and plunging the Middle East into a new conflict that Trump said would end a security threat to the U.S. and give Iranians a chance to topple their rulers.

"Washington and Tel Aviv have once again embarked on a dangerous adventure that is rapidly bringing the region closer to a humanitarian, economic, and possibly radiological catastrophe," Russia's foreign ministry said.

"By plunging the Middle East into an abyss of uncontrolled escalation, they are actually encouraging countries around the world, primarily in the region, to acquire more and more serious means against emerging threats."

Dmitry Medvedev, deputy chairman of Russia's powerful Security Council, chided U.S. President Donald Trump on Saturday for the attack on Iran and questioned Washington's staying power given the relatively short history of the United States compared to that of Persia's civilisation.

"The peacekeeper is at it again. The talks with Iran were just a cover. Everyone knew that," Medvedev, a former Russian president, said in English.

"So who has more patience to wait for the enemy’s sorry end now? The US is just 249 years old. The Persian Empire was founded over 2500 years ago. Let’s see what happens in 100 years or so…"</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:43:36 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/K7QTTJOJV5M7XILHFWBXQGIZCI.jpg?auth=f31506b36c00db9f6927c72d92520405525ff641c031f1d5eafb6268129e5ef0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iran defence minister, Guards commander killed in Israeli attacks, three sources say</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-defence-minister-guards-commander-killed-israeli-attacks-three-sources-say-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Iran's Defence Minister Amir Nasirzadeh and Revolutionary Guards commander Mohammed Pakpour are believed to have been killed in Israeli attacks, two sources familiar with Israel's military operations and one regional source said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:29:16 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Germany, France and UK tell Iran to stop attacks in region</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/germany-france-uk-tell-iran-stop-attacks-region-2026-02-28/</link><description>BERLIN, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Germany, France and Britain condemned Iranian attacks on countries in the region on Saturday, saying Iran must refrain from indiscriminate military strikes and resume negotiations.

"We condemn Iranian attacks on countries in the region in the strongest terms," French President Emmanuel Macron, German Chancellor Friedrich Merz and British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said in a joint statement.

"We call for a resumption of negotiations and urge the Iranian leadership to seek a negotiated solution. Ultimately, the Iranian people must be allowed to determine their future," they said.

The leaders said they had consistently urged Iran to end its nuclear programme, curb its ballistic missile program, refrain from its destabilizing activity in the region and cease appalling violence and repression against its own people.

Adding that their countries did not participate in strikes on Saturday, they said they were in close contact with international partners, including the U.S., Israel, and partners in the region.

"We reiterate our commitment to regional stability and to the protection of civilian life," they added.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:29:20 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/CMHOPRUJQFKGBF62JK3VOTQN54.jpg?auth=8d82933f3e0f7f7b50017e21c57fd57eaad2c8955c6b9b7a026e364bc422d768&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iranian minister says 'we may have lost a few commanders', according to NBC News reporter on X</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iranian-minister-says-we-may-have-lost-few-commanders-according-nbc-news-2026-02-28/</link><description>NEW YORK, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Iran's foreign minister said on Saturday that "we may have lost a few commanders, but that's not such a big problem," according to an NBC News reporter on X.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:52:33 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2OT46IMSVO2LHG3HHCW3T5WGM.jpg?auth=1bb42dc711388997fd45b2f1aac58ca16ebd233c55b315fd77faa5f6343d7aff&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Ukraine's Zelenskiy says it is important that US act decisively on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/ukraines-zelenskiy-says-it-is-important-that-us-act-decisively-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>KYIV, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy, addressing U.S. strikes in Iran on Saturday, said it was important that Washington act decisively, but also that hostilities did not escalate into a wider war.

"Whenever there is American resolve, global criminals weaken," Zelenskiy, who has previously called for the Iranian government to be overthrown, wrote on social media.

"This understanding must also come to the Russians," he added.

Tehran is a close ally of Moscow, which has been at war with Ukraine since 2022. Iran has supplied Russia with thousands of long-range Shahed drones, the designs for which have also been used to build drones in Russian factories.

Zelenskiy said Moscow had fired over 57,000 Shahed-type drones at Ukraine during the war.

"It is fair to give the Iranian people a chance to rid themselves of a terrorist regime and to guarantee security for all nations that have suffered from terror originating in Iran," he wrote, adding that it was important to preserve lives where possible.

"It is important to prevent the war from expanding. It is important that the United States is acting decisively."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/BADEQC3BDVNLXGMM36HKCG43GU.jpg?auth=e00bd1f5271f498773ee61b00f7d0d55363b09d59df92d20c8cb1c36eb41b1c6&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Exclusive: Ahead of strikes, Trump was told Iran attack is high risk, high reward</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/ahead-strikes-trump-told-iran-attack-was-high-risk-high-reward-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Ahead of the U.S. attack on Iran, President Donald Trump received briefings that not only delivered blunt assessments about the risk of major U.S. casualties but also touted the prospect of a generational shift in the Middle East in favor of U.S. interests, a U.S. official told Reuters.

The launch of what the Pentagon called "Operation Epic Fury" on Saturday plunged the Middle East into a new and unpredictable conflict. The U.S. and Israeli militaries struck sites across Iran, triggering retaliatory Iranian attacks against Israel and nearby Gulf Arab countries .

The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the briefers described the operation to the president as a high-risk, high-reward scenario.

Trump himself appeared to echo that sentiment when he acknowledged the stakes at the onset of the operation, saying "the lives of courageous American heroes may be lost."

"But we're doing this not for now, we're doing this for the future, and it is a noble mission," Trump said in a video address announcing the start of major combat operations.

"For 47 years, the Iranian regime has chanted death to America and waged an unending campaign of bloodshed and mass murder ... We're not gonna put up with it any longer."

The briefings from Trump's national security team help explain how the president decided to pursue arguably the riskiest U.S. military operation since the invasion of Iraq in 2003.

Ahead of the strikes, Trump received multiple briefings from officials including CIA Director John Ratcliffe, U.S. General Dan Caine, the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio and Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth.

On Thursday, Admiral Brad Cooper, who leads U.S. forces in the Middle East as the head of Central Command, flew to Washington to join discussions in the White House Situation Room.

A second U.S. official said that prior to the strikes, the White House had been briefed on a number of risks associated with operations against Iran, including retaliatory strikes on multiple U.S. bases in the region by Iranian missiles that could overwhelm defenses, as well as Iranian proxies attacking U.S. troops in Iraq and Syria.

The official said that despite the massive military buildup by the United States, there were limits to the air defense systems that had been rushed into the region.

Experts caution that the unfolding conflict could take dangerous turns and the first official said the Pentagon's planning did not appear to guarantee the outcome of any conflict.

Trump called on Iranians to topple the government but that is easier said than done, said Nicole Grajewski with the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.

"The Iranian opposition is pretty fragmented. It's unclear what the population is willing to do in terms of rising up," Grajewski said.

Both U.S. officials requested anonymity due to the sensitivity of the internal discussions.

The White House did not immediately respond to requests for comment. The Pentagon declined to comment.

In the weeks leading up to the attack, Trump ordered a major military buildup in the Middle East. Reuters reported military planning to carry out a sustained campaign against Iran , if that is what the president chose. Plans included targeting individual officials , officials said.

An Israeli official said Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei and President Masoud Pezeshkian were both targeted but the result of the strikes was not clear.

Trump made clear on Saturday that his objectives in Iran were sweeping, saying he would end the threat posed by Tehran to the United States and give Iranians a chance to topple their rulers. To accomplish this, he outlined plans to lay waste to much of Iran's military as well as deny it the ability to build a nuclear weapon. Iran denies seeking a nuclear weapon.

"We are going to destroy their missiles and raze their missile industry to the ground... We're going to annihilate their navy," he said. "We're going to ensure that the region's terrorist proxies can no longer destabilize the region or the world and attack our forces."

Trump's decision demonstrates an increasing risk appetite, far greater than when he ordered U.S. special operations forces into Venezuela last month to seize that country's president in an audacious raid.

The unfolding campaign against Iran is also riskier than when Trump ordered U.S. forces to bomb Iran's nuclear sites in June.

Iran's Revolutionary Guards threatened all U.S. bases and interests in the region and said Iran's retaliation would continue until "the enemy is decisively defeated."

Experts warn that Iran has many options for retaliation, including missile strikes but also drones and cyber warfare.

Daniel Shapiro, a former senior Pentagon official for Middle East issues, said that despite the U.S. and Israeli strikes, Tehran would still be capable of causing some pain.

"Iran has many more ballistic missiles that can reach U.S. bases than the U.S. has interceptors ... some Iranian weapons will get through," said Shapiro, also a former U.S. ambassador to Israel. "(The strikes are) a major gamble."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:29:49 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/YU7B3IEYKRIWZGH2A5VGKAYTJ4.jpg?auth=c7ed68cbc5fab6abf39176e503f8527c30ab721837e1e8ecf00182997055d298&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Zelenskiy says next three-way peace talks depend on security situation, diplomacy</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/zelenskiy-says-next-three-way-peace-talks-depend-security-situation-diplomacy-2026-02-28/</link><description>KYIV, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Saturday that the time and place of the next round of peace talks between the U.S., Russia and Ukraine would depend on the security situation in the Middle East and the level of "real diplomatic possibilities".

Zelenskiy said he would issue fresh directives to Ukraine's negotiating team at the talks, without detailing what they were.

On Thursday, he had said the next round of talks would probably take place in Abu Dhabi in early March.

However, the UAE has since been caught up in hostilities after the U.S. and Israel launched aerial attacks on Iran.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:30:21 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/Z5GATXTMJ5OLVE62ODFWAVD74U.jpg?auth=669691c2a44c835aaf737fa933e40fe551ac8434485d7ac1743b3b5d880ab7fa&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iran's supreme leader Khamenei to give speech within minutes after U.S., Israeli strikes on Iran, Al-Alam TV says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-supreme-leader-khamenei-give-speech-within-minutes-after-us-israeli-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei will speak within minutes, Iran's Al-Alam TV reported, hours after U.S., Israeli strikes targeted top Iranian leaders on Saturday.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/32KPVYWRPJLCHCK3GVCF3WDL4E.jpg?auth=cc820ceb02e245c6142eb30b9cfca9ebdb90fd49152bbad1bddaa52e5562ea82&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Exclusive: CIA assessed that Revolutionary Guards figures could replace Khamenei if he is killed</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/prior-iran-attacks-cia-assessed-khamenei-would-be-replaced-by-hardline-irgc-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - In the run-up to the U.S. and Israeli attacks on Saturday, the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency assessed that even if Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was killed in the operation, he would likely be replaced by hardline figures from the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), two sources briefed on the intelligence said.

The assessments, which were produced over the past two weeks, looked broadly at what could occur in Iran following a U.S. intervention and the extent to which a military operation could trigger regime change in the Islamic Republic -- now a pronounced objective for Washington.

The IRGC is an elite military force whose purpose is to protect Shi'ite Muslim clerical rule in Iran.

The intelligence agency reports did not conclude any scenario with certainty, said the sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity to discuss intelligence matters.

The Central Intelligence Agency declined to comment.

President Donald Trump has for weeks signaled the U.S. was interested in seeing regime change in Iran, but has not given in any detail Washington’s thinking on who could lead the country.

In an early morning video address on Saturday, Trump described Tehran as a "terrorist regime" and encouraged the Iranian people to take over the government, saying the U.S. military strikes would set the stage for an uprising.

The U.S. and Israeli assault comes after weeks of deliberation inside the U.S. government about whether to strike Iran following the deadly protests that broke out there in December.

U.S. officials in recent weeks have tried to strike a nuclear deal with Tehran in an attempt to stave off intervention.

In a briefing last week, Secretary of State Marco Rubio told top congressional lawmakers known as the Gang of Eight that a U.S. operation would likely move forward, but that Trump could change his mind, particularly if nuclear negotiations were successful. Those talks in Geneva did not result in an agreement.

Rubio notified the Gang of Eight on Friday night that the operation to attack Iran was likely to commence in the following hours but said Trump could still change his mind, two sources familiar with the matter said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:33:44 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IPGJRAK5OFPBXAC726G3JLD4TY.jpg?auth=9855b0bcc8e679526685ce6cd17023c9dc7c9a4d7abbd37ddeddd08124754de9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Trump's Iran strikes mark his biggest foreign policy gamble</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trumps-iran-strikes-mark-his-biggest-foreign-policy-gamble-2026-02-28/</link><description>WASHINGTON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - With his large-scale attack on Iran, Donald Trump has seized a legacy-defining moment to demonstrate his readiness to exercise raw U.S. military power. But in doing so, he is also taking the biggest foreign policy gamble of his presidency, one fraught with risks and unknowns.

Trump joined with Israel on Saturday to plunge into war with Iran, providing little explanation to the American public for what could become the biggest U.S. military campaign since the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.

Trump has pivoted away from a preference for swift, limited operations like last month’s lightning raid in Venezuela to what experts warn could be a more protracted conflict with Iran that risks escalating into a regional conflagration engulfing the oil-rich Middle East.

He has also set out a daunting objective of regime change in Tehran, pushing the idea that air strikes can incite a popular uprising to oust Iran's rulers.

It is an outcome that outside air power has never directly achieved without the involvement of some kind of armed force on the ground, and which most analysts doubt will succeed this time.

"Most Americans will wake up Saturday morning and wonder why we are at war with Iran, what is the goal, and why U.S. bases in the Middle East are under attack," said Daniel Shapiro, a former senior Pentagon official and U.S. ambassador to Israel who is now at the Atlantic Council think-tank in Washington.

Trump's fixation on Iran has emerged as the starkest example yet of how foreign policy, including his expanded use of military might, has topped his agenda in the first 13 months of his second term, often overshadowing domestic issues like the cost of living that public opinion polls show are much higher priorities for most Americans.

His own aides have been privately urging him for weeks to focus more on voters' economic worries, highlighting the political dangers ahead of this November's midterm elections in which Trump's Republican Party is at risk of losing one or both chambers of Congress.

The brief pre-dawn video that Trump posted on his Truth Social platform announcing what the Pentagon has dubbed “Operation Epic Fury” provided only broad reasons for going to war now with a country the U.S. has tussled with for decades while averting all-out hostilities.

He insisted he would end what he said was Tehran’s ballistic missile threat – which most experts say does not pose a threat to the U.S. - and give Iranians a chance to topple their rulers.

Trump said that to accomplish his goals U.S. forces would lay waste to much of Iran's military as well as deny it the ability to have a nuclear weapon. Iran denies that its nuclear program has military aims.

Trump’s sudden resort to force, using huge U.S. military assets built up in the region in recent weeks, appeared all but certain to close the door for now on diplomacy with Iran. The latest round of nuclear talks in Geneva on Thursday failed to achieve a breakthrough.

Some Trump aides have previously suggested that he might be able to bomb Tehran back to the negotiating table to force deep concessions. Instead, Iran responded on Saturday by launching missiles at U.S. allies Israel and oil-producing Gulf Arab countries.

Trump’s focus in the video on the urgency of the threat posed by Iran’s ballistic and nuclear programs had echoes of the case President George W. Bush made for war against Iraq in 2003, which later turned out to be based on faulty intelligence and false claims.

Trump’s assertion in Tuesday’s State of the Union address that Iran will soon have a missile that can hit the United States is not backed by U.S. intelligence reports, according to sources familiar with the assessments, and experts have also cast doubt on his aides' recent claims of Tehran’s ability to quickly advance its nuclear capabilities.

With Saturday's strikes, Trump, who had originally threatened to strike Iran in January in support of street protesters facing a violent crackdown, also erased all doubt that part of what he seeks now is regime change in Tehran.

But analysts question whether Trump, who has ruled out deploying U.S. troops on the ground, has a strategy that could unseat Iran’s longtime cleric-dominated government, which has proved resilient in the face of crippling sanctions and periodic mass protests.

The first wave of strikes mainly targeted Iranian officials, a source familiar with the matter said. Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was not in Tehran at the time of the attacks and had been transferred to a secure location, said a source with knowledge of the matter. However, several senior commanders in Iran's Revolutionary Guards and political officials have been killed, an Iranian source close to the establishment said.

Even if the strikes do succeed in eliminating top leaders, that could have the unintended consequences of sowing chaos across a sprawling nation of 93 million or even lead to a military-run government that might be even more intransigent with the West and oppressive to its people, analysts said.

"He wants to change the government," said Jon Alterman at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, a think-tank in Washington. "But it’s hard to change the government from the air. It’s hard to change the minds of Iranians through the air."

Tyson Barker, a former senior U.S. official who is now with the Atlantic Council, said Trump’s call for the Iranian people to rise up was also not likely to work.

"They're really exposing these poor Iranian people by saying, 'Stand up and overthrow your government. We got your back'," Barker said.

Trump, whose appetite for military operations has grown since the start of his second term, received briefings ahead of the Iran strikes that not only delivered blunt assessments about the risk of major U.S. casualties but also touted the prospect of a shift in the Middle East in favor of U.S. interests, a U.S. official told Reuters.

Trump appears to have been emboldened by U.S. bombing of Iran’s main nuclear facilities in June, which he considered a major success, and the in-and-out raid that captured Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro in January and has given the U.S. considerable sway over the OPEC country’s vast oil reserves.

He may have forced his own hand with Iran with his frequent threats of military action while building up a huge naval force that he could not sustain indefinitely in the region.

Analysts see Iran as a much tougher, better-armed foe than Venezuela, even though its air defenses and missile capabilities were severely degraded in joint U.S.-Israeli strikes in June.

"Iran is a more formidable military power, and even what the response is right now in the Gulf - they're willing to cross lines that they weren't willing to cross before," said Nicole Grajewski, with the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.

But Mark Dubowitz, CEO of the Foundation for the Defense of Democracies, a nonprofit research institute considered pro-Israel and hawkish on Iran, said Tehran is in such a weakened state that it is worth Trump taking the risks to curb Tehran’s nuclear capabilities.

Whether or not the Iranian government falls, he said severely degrading Iran's nuclear and missile programs could be a victory for Trump.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:33:45 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/SBHIIUV33BJAVJVIQ73WUGA7GE.jpg?auth=682002af96f99688ba310591b74fea4949b5cfc481447685d8f666d5b1df3929&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>UN nuclear watchdog sees no 'radiological impact' from strikes on Iran</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/un-nuclear-watchdog-sees-no-radiological-impact-strikes-iran-2026-02-28/</link><description>VIENNA, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The U.N. nuclear watchdog said on Saturday it had seen no "radiological impact" from U.S. and Israeli attacks on Iran or retaliatory strikes in other countries in the region, though it did not say whether Iranian nuclear sites had been targeted.

"The IAEA is closely monitoring developments in the Middle East, and urges restraint to avoid any nuclear safety risks to people in the region," the International Atomic Energy Agency said on X. "The IAEA is in permanent contact with countries in the region, so far no evidence of any radiological impact."</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:34:39 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/MDZTAACFWJID3FSFDQCENLC4DM.jpg?auth=011c5ffb4fd0ec0ca013264eae79b1ff6b8261eb736cd56c02fb2d8b7a022d65&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>UN Security Council to meet on Saturday on Iran conflict</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/un-security-council-meet-saturday-iran-conflict-2026-02-28/</link><description>Feb 28 (Reuters) - The U.N. Security Council will meet on Saturday after the United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran , plunging the Middle East into a new conflict.

U.N. diplomats said the 15-member body would meet at 4 p.m. local time in New York (2100 GMT). The meeting will be chaired by Britain, which holds the monthly council presidency.

Russia's U.N. mission said Russia and China requested an emergency meeting "in connection with the unprovoked act of armed aggression by the United States and Israel against the Islamic Republic of Iran."

It said the meeting was also called for by France, Bahrain, and Colombia.

"During the Security Council meeting, we will demand from the United States and Israel to immediately cease their illegal and escalatory actions and embark on a path toward a political and diplomatic settlement," the Russian statement said.

A U.N. diplomat said U.N. Secretary-General Antonio Guterres plans to speak at the Security Council session.

Earlier on Saturday, Guterres issued a statement condemning military escalation in the Middle East and saying that the "use of force by the United States and Israel against Iran, and the subsequent retaliation by Iran across the region, undermine international peace and security."

"I call for an immediate cessation of hostilities and de-escalation. Failing to do so risks a wider regional conflict with grave consequences for civilians and regional stability. I strongly encourage all parties to return immediately to the negotiating table," Guterres said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:35:02 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/D65YRQ2TKVKZJLNZ7S4JKPPX3A.jpg?auth=85972956a6f40bae8e07846b92e3ba538cbe7a309bd9c8cd7affad3f1c3bc37f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iran war throws oil market into its biggest crisis in decades</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iran-war-throws-oil-market-into-biggest-crisis-decades-2026-02-28/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Global energy markets face one of their gravest shocks in decades as joint U.S. and Israeli strikes on Iran and Tehran’s retaliatory missile attacks across the Gulf disrupt oil exports from the world’s most important producing region.

The scale of the disruption will likely be determined by the duration of the conflict, but for now the threat and the uncertainty are already enough to severely impact flows from the region that accounts for 20% of global oil supplies.

Barring a swift resolution, oil prices will likely see steep increases when trading opens on Monday morning. Benchmark Brent crude oil prices rose in recent weeks to around $70 a barrel, their highest since August 2025 as investors braced for military confrontation in the Middle East.

The United States and Israel carried out military strikes on Iran on Saturday, targeting senior leaders and plunging the Middle East into a widening conflict. U.S. President Donald Trump said the attacks would eliminate a security threat to the United States and give Iranians an opportunity to topple their rulers.

For now, there is no confirmed damage to oil and gas infrastructure from retaliatory Iranian strikes.

Explosions were reported in the United Arab Emirates and Kuwait, two major oil exporters. Meanwhile, Qatar, the world’s second-largest exporter of liquefied natural gas, said it intercepted missiles aimed at the country.

Blasts were also heard in Bahrain and near Iran’s Kharg Island, the terminal through which about 90% of its crude exports normally flow, although shipping data suggests Tehran had transferred most of the oil stored there onto tankers in recent days.

Crucially, there have so far been no reports of disruptions to shipping through the Strait of Hormuz, the narrow waterway between Iran and Oman that handles nearly 20 million barrels per day of crude oil and refined products.

But the absence of physical damage may not matter much.

The risk that tankers could be stranded inside the Gulf, north of Hormuz, or that vessels could be targeted, is already enough to force producers, traders and shippers to rethink movements of oil and LNG. Reuters has reported that some oil majors and trading houses have suspended shipments through the strait for several days.

That caution is unlikely to ease until there is far greater confidence in the safety of the region’s sea lanes.

Tanker freight rates, which had already been climbing as tensions escalated, are set to rise further. Benchmark rates for very large crude carriers from the Middle East to China have more than tripled since the start of the year, reflecting both heightened risk and the shrinking pool of willing vessels.

The key questions now are whether energy infrastructure will be directly targeted and how quickly the U.S. military can secure shipping routes across the Gulf and the Strait of Hormuz.

It is worth noting that the Strait of Hormuz has never been fully blocked.

While Iran is unlikely to sustain a prolonged blockade, it has the capability to disrupt traffic temporarily. The U.S. Navy would almost certainly respond swiftly, but even short-lived attacks or mine-laying operations could have outsized effects on prices and supply.

Such tactics would not be unprecedented. During the 1980s Iran-Iraq war, Iran attacked commercial shipping and U.S. naval vessels, prompting President Ronald Reagan to deploy U.S. forces to escort tankers in Operation Earnest Will. More recently, in late 2007 and early 2008, there were repeated confrontations between Iranian and U.S. naval forces. And in April 2023, Iran's navy seized the Advantage Sweet crude tanker, chartered by Chevron, in the Gulf of Oman. The vessel was released more than a year later.

The global oil market is relatively well supplied today, after production from the United States, Brazil, Canada and other countries rose in recent years.

Saudi Arabia, the world’s top oil exporter, has also not sat idle in the face of the risk to supply. In recent days the kingdom increased crude shipments , which are set to exceed 7 million barrels per day in February, the highest since April 2023, according to shipping analytics firm Kpler.

OPEC+, which comprises the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries and allies like Russia, is expected to agree on an output increase during a meeting on Sunday.

Of course, disruptions to export routes from the Middle East could negate much of the production increases from regional producers, though Saudi and the UAE have some alternative export routes.

The scale of the U.S. and Israeli strikes, and Trump’s language, suggest Washington is bracing for a sustained military campaign aimed at severely weakening Iran’s leadership.

How threatened Iran's leadership feels may determine whether it escalates further by attacking a broader range of targets across the region, including oilfields, export terminals and processing facilities.

But even without that worst-case scenario, the conflict is already set to disrupt vital energy supplies from the Middle East in ways not seen for decades.

(The views expressed here are those of the author, a columnist for Reuters)</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:37:25 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/TMXV3DTJPZJSVBQJ4VIXCYJIXI.jpg?auth=aa50dd0a916a9b3337e10beec45e37a593e8a8788d1d6946dd8d781c1f024b9d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Trump’s new Iran attack opens up big global risks</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/commentary/breakingviews/trumps-new-iran-attack-opens-up-big-global-risks-2026-02-28/</link><description>LONDON, Feb 28 (Reuters Breakingviews) - Donald Trump has finally revealed his hand on Iran: a closed fist. After weeks of threats and escalating rhetoric, the U.S. president and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Saturday morning authorised major air strikes targeting the country’s leaders. For both the Gulf region and the global economy the latest attacks – and Tehran’s response – create a worryingly unstable and open-ended new reality.

Trump’s recent warnings had linked the possibility of an attack to ongoing negotiations aimed at restricting Iran’s nuclear capabilities. However, early on Saturday morning he laid out a wider justification for conflict based on the Islamic Republic’s 47 years of hostility towards the United States, as well as preventing it from possessing an atomic weapon. Most notably, the president called on the Iranian people to take over the government after American bombs have cleared the way. “The hour of your freedom is at hand,” he declared.

Iran’s government and armed forces have been weakened by losses sustained during last June’s 12-day war. Tehran also killed thousands of its own citizens last month following demonstrations. If the latest attacks succeed in removing Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei and other senior figures, it could lead to a change of leadership in Iran without embroiling American troops in another protracted conflict like the ones it fought in Afghanistan and Iraq.

Yet there is little historical precedent for air strikes by a foreign power triggering a popular uprising. It’s also far from clear that the powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) would accept a replacement leader, or that any new government would be less hostile to the United States. The shaky premise for the latest conflict is compounded by the fact Trump has not sought approval from Congress. Both he and Netanyahu claimed to have destroyed Iran’s nuclear programme last June, but have used the same threat as grounds to attack again.

Both sides could yet step back from a prolonged conflict, as they have in the past. However, the costs of Trump’s decision are clearer than the benefits. Iran has responded by firing missiles at Israel as well as U.S. allies in the Gulf like Bahrain, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates. Those countries’ economic plans to pivot away from fossil fuels hinge on attracting foreign direct investment and tourism. Both are bound to suffer when missile attacks force financial hubs like Abu Dhabi and Dubai to close their airspace.

The economic shocks could reverberate further if the conflict disrupts supplies of oil. Morgan Stanley reckons that if a large-scale U.S. attack is followed by significant Iranian counter-strikes, tanker disruptions in the Arabian Gulf could cut global supplies by up to 3 million barrels a day for several weeks. That would be sufficient to send crude prices soaring way above their already elevated level of $72 a barrel.

How much of this feeds through to wider global inflation, forcing central banks to keep interest rates higher for longer, depends on whether Saudi Arabia can deploy some of its 2 million daily barrels of spare oil capacity. It also hinges on how long the conflict drags on, given the risk of other disruptions like renewed attacks on Red Sea shipping by Iran-aligned Houthi forces. Whatever the outcome, Trump’s latest attacks have opened up big new risks.

Follow George Hay on Bluesky , opens new tab and LinkedIn , opens new tab .</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:38:07 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/F3RMO3NPSVOYFKIFRCMSNH4W7M.jpg?auth=acb7239537bb2a9e9d113e71c8b764c8f24498bed5673c2c6f7ec67c2ecd4740&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Italy's defence minister stuck in Dubai with family</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/italys-defence-minister-stuck-dubai-with-family-2026-02-28/</link><description>MILAN, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Italian Defence Minister Guido Crosetto was stuck in Dubai with his family on Saturday as flights were suspended after U.S and Israeli attacks on Iran, a source close to the ministry said on Saturday.

The minister left Rome on Friday evening aboard a civilian flight to join his family, already in Dubai on holiday. He was scheduled to return to Italy on Saturday afternoon.

The Italian carrier ITA Airways said it had suspended flights to and from Dubai until Sunday.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2ZTHAIME3JKWHPHPKG4BP5Y4YQ.jpg?auth=2874d8d5d38b09a73f37f656b3f606e28a5d5a2c47f85d26c2e94331249a94bd&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Israel's Netanyahu says there are signs that Iranian supreme leader Khamenei 'is no longer'</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-there-are-signs-that-iranian-supreme-leader-khamenei-is-2026-02-28/</link><description>JERUSALEM, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Saturday that there were many signs indicating Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei "is no longer", without explicitly confirming his death.

Netanyahu also said Khamenei's compound had been destroyed, and Revolutionary Guard commanders and senior nuclear officials had ben destroyed.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 19:26:06 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EWB6LYBEGFM63L2KX3YG2WXAZY.jpg?auth=8dcbc4b4c43790e5476012bbeadf4f24cf64098e21e081c8507ccd7fb423abcb&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Israeli opposition leader Lapid backs strikes on Iran, calls for regime change</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-opposition-leader-lapid-backs-strikes-iran-calls-regime-change-2026-02-28/</link><description>TEL AVIV, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Israeli opposition leader Yair Lapid said on Saturday that he backed Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's decision to strike Iran, describing the campaign as a "just war against evil"

The U.S. and Israel launched a series of strikes on Iran , targeting senior leaders and calling for the overthrow of its government, sparking a wave of Iranian missile barrages fired at Israel and Gulf countries including the United Arab Emirates and Qatar.

"We are going to stand united against this threat," Lapid told Reuters in Tel Aviv, shortly after emerging from a bomb shelter following sirens warning of an incoming Iranian attack.

Iran's ballistic and nuclear programs and, if possible, the country's leadership should be "obliterated", he said.

Netanyahu, and much of the country's political establishment have long warned Iran poses an existential threat to Israel.

Lapid, who was briefly prime minister in 2022 and is a fierce critic of Netanyahu, said that political differences with the prime minister would be put aside for the time-being.

The opposition leader also thanked President Donald Trump for what he described as the United States' leadership of the operation against Iran, saying Trump had shown courage.

Last June, Israel launched a surprise attack against Iran, sparking a war between the Middle East powers that ended after 12 days when the United States joined Israel in bombing Iran.

More than 30 people were killed in Israel in that war, as Iranian missiles struck the country, including densely populated Tel Aviv. Over 900 were killed in Israeli strikes on Iran.

Asked whether Israel could sustain a conflict with Iran lasting weeks or months, Lapid said the country was "way stronger" than many people assumed, and said that unlike Israel, he doubted Iran would be able to sustain a prolonged war.

Israel is due to hold a national election by October, in which polls show the coalition led by Netanyahu, Israel's longest serving prime minister, may not be able to form government.

The country's opposition is also splintered, although many seek to form a government without Netanyahu.

Israeli polls show Lapid's Yesh Atid could lose seats at the next election, although his party may still be key to forming the government.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 19:28:06 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/Q52BO2K25BKUHJYXZJ6PT573LY.jpg?auth=f3a4873fd83f5b50901f8a72a2b41ab88a51770c38258caf0cb2fe4635156181&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Mexican authorities return body of cartel boss 'El Mencho' to relatives</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexican-authorities-return-body-cartel-boss-el-mencho-relatives-2026-02-28/</link><description>MEXICO CITY, Feb 28 (Reuters) - The body of Mexican cartel boss Nemesio Oseguera, the country's most wanted man until his death a week ago, was returned to his family, the attorney general's office said on Saturday.

Osguera, known as "El Mencho", was killed in a military operation in Jalisco state on Sunday. That sparked a wave of retaliatory violence by the cartel across much of Mexico, killing dozens and temporarily stranding foreign tourists in their hotels.

The attorney general's office said they had performed genetic tests to match the remains to the relatives. The office did not say where the handover took place.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/SWJYRUSNTNOV3DJQMA4ELP5LWI.jpg?auth=d5636b98e2325006133ff130971a495ce7c91210eb0fe2e5221b02d121151a7b&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Iran missiles brings war to Gulf doorstep; hardens support for US–Israel campaign</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-missiles-brings-war-gulf-doorstep-hardens-support-usisrael-campaign-2026-02-28/</link><description>DUBAI, Feb 28 (Reuters) - Thunderous blasts and towering fireballs from Iranian missiles streaking across Gulf states vindicated their leaders' long-held fears that Tehran can bring war to their doorstep , likely to harden Arab rulers' support for U.S.–Israeli strikes .

Even in the Palm, Dubai's swankiest resort, explosions rattled buildings and hit a luxury hotel, sending panicked residents running for cover as missiles and interceptors tore across the sky. It was a stark sign that the conflict had spilled beyond Iran’s borders - just as Tehran had warned it would.

"What has now been proven is that we - not the United States - are in the line of fire," said Dr Ebtesam Al-Ketbi, President of the Emirates Policy Center. "When Iran struck, it struck the Gulf first under the pretext of targeting U.S. bases."

Analysts say Iran's strikes on Gulf countries are meant to demonstrate that no U.S. ally in the region is beyond reach, and to raise the cost of backing Washington’s campaign.

"The danger is that any miscalculation could push the region from an exchange of signals into an open war,” added al Ketbi.

Gulf sources say that by targeting oil-rich Gulf states, Tehran is “internationalising the battlefield” and threatening global oil flows, not just regional security.

For fast-growing economies such as Saudi Arabia, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates -- dependent on open airspace, secure shipping lanes and trade -- a broader conflict would be deeply disruptive.

In framing the war as a push for regime change in Iran, Trump has made it existential, raising the risk that Tehran lashes out, said Mohammed Baharoon, director-general of the Dubai Public Policy Research Center (B’huth).

"If Iran miscalculates and carries out an act of war against Gulf Cooperation Council countries, the conflict will change fundamentally. People can't stand by while lives are being lost and assets destroyed and do nothing."

Gulf analyst Abdelkhaleq Abdulla said Iran was making a strategic mistake by targeting its closest neighbours.

"It is foolish of Iran to alienate the people nearest to it," Abdulla said. "Tehran may believe it is targeting U.S. military bases, but Gulf states see this as a blatant act of aggression-- a violation of their sovereignty and an attack on their land."

In indirect U.S.–Iran talks in recent weeks aimed at averting war, Tehran agreed to discuss its nuclear programme but insisted its ballistic missiles and support for regional militias were off the table, sources close to the talks said.

Iran has indicated that any discussion about its missiles and its allied militias take place only in a regional framework, without Washington, the sources said.

But the Gulf Arab states - longtime U.S. partners which have previous experience of being targets of attacks by Iran and its proxies - argue that sidelining Washington would weaken, not stabilise the region’s security architecture.

From the Gulf perspective, Iran's missile arsenal and its proxies pose direct threats. Tehran floated a regional security forum without U.S. participation, but Gulf states saw little traction without external security guarantors.

"The implications are huge for Saudi Arabia and the Gulf," said one source close to government circles. "All U.S. allies in the region are now united against Iran."

Paul Salem of the Middle East Institute noted that Trump’s message has shifted sharply. While just days ago he framed potential U.S. strikes as leverage to push Iran toward a nuclear deal, his speech announcing them openly called for regime change.

In contrast to the massive 2003 U.S. ground invasion of Iraq, Trump appears to be betting on a short, decisive campaign that delivers visible results within days or weeks, limits U.S. casualties and contains domestic political risk.

The calculation is that a quick success would be politically advantageous, while a prolonged conflict -- especially one that disrupts oil markets or the wider economy -- could prove costly.

While the Bush administration spent months building a legal and political case and deployed some 300,000 troops in a ground invasion that led to years of occupation, Trump has opted for a limited campaign of air strikes.

But if the conflict spreads -- drawing in U.S. bases, embassies, energy infrastructure or the world's most vital oil shipping route through the Strait of Hormuz -- the economic and political risks would rise sharply for the United States, the Gulf and global markets.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 19:45:03 +0000</pubDate><enclosure url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RKCJAPJJNFN5ZGN62MQXA22QZE.jpg?auth=8dbd76d3d3fdefec520671d9e0cbcc5f2f6d47482e325144d477ccc6b883680d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" /></item></channel></rss>